<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><xbrl xmlns="http://www.xbrl.org/2003/instance" xmlns:f="http://xbrl.dcca.dk/sob" xmlns:b="http://xbrl.dcca.dk/entryBalanceSheetAccountFormIncomeStatementByNature" xmlns:h="http://xbrl.dcca.dk/mrv" xmlns:g="http://xbrl.dcca.dk/arr" xmlns:d="http://xbrl.dcca.dk/cmn" xmlns:e="http://xbrl.dcca.dk/fsa" xmlns:c="http://xbrl.dcca.dk/gsd" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xbrli="http://www.xbrl.org/2003/instance" xmlns:iso4217="http://www.xbrl.org/2003/iso4217" xmlns:xbrldi="http://xbrl.org/2006/xbrldi" xmlns:link="http://www.xbrl.org/2003/linkbase" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://xbrl.dcca.dk/entryBalanceSheetAccountFormIncomeStatementByNature http://archprod.service.eogs.dk/taxonomy/20171001/entryDanishGAAPBalanceSheetAccountFormIncomeStatementByNatureIncludingManagementsReviewStatisticsAndTax20171001.xsd"><link:schemaRef xlink:type="simple" xlink:href="http://archprod.service.eogs.dk/taxonomy/20171001/entryDanishGAAPBalanceSheetAccountFormIncomeStatementByNatureIncludingManagementsReviewStatisticsAndTax20171001.xsd"/><c:InformationOnTypeOfSubmittedReport contextRef="c11">Årsrapport</c:InformationOnTypeOfSubmittedReport><c:IdentificationNumberCvrOfSubmittingEnterprise contextRef="c11">24927016</c:IdentificationNumberCvrOfSubmittingEnterprise><c:NameOfSubmittingEnterprise contextRef="c11">Anpartsselskabet af 1. september 1984</c:NameOfSubmittingEnterprise><c:AddressOfSubmittingEnterpriseStreetAndNumber contextRef="c11">Hambros Allé 1</c:AddressOfSubmittingEnterpriseStreetAndNumber><c:AddressOfSubmittingEnterprisePostcodeAndTown contextRef="c11">2900 Hellerup</c:AddressOfSubmittingEnterprisePostcodeAndTown><c:ReportingPeriodStartDate contextRef="c11">2017-01-01</c:ReportingPeriodStartDate><c:ReportingPeriodEndDate contextRef="c11">2017-12-31</c:ReportingPeriodEndDate><c:PrecedingReportingPeriodStartDate contextRef="c11">2016-01-01</c:PrecedingReportingPeriodStartDate><c:PredingReportingPeriodEndDate contextRef="c11">2016-12-31</c:PredingReportingPeriodEndDate><c:DateOfApprovalOfReport contextRef="c11">2018-06-21</c:DateOfApprovalOfReport><c:IdentificationNumberCvrOfReportingEntity contextRef="c11">89422728</c:IdentificationNumberCvrOfReportingEntity><c:NameOfReportingEntity contextRef="c11">Adyn ApS</c:NameOfReportingEntity><c:AddressOfReportingEntityStreetName contextRef="c11">Hambros Allé</c:AddressOfReportingEntityStreetName><c:AddressOfReportingEntityStreetBuildingIdentifier contextRef="c11">1</c:AddressOfReportingEntityStreetBuildingIdentifier><c:AddressOfReportingEntityPostCodeIdentifier contextRef="c11">2900</c:AddressOfReportingEntityPostCodeIdentifier><c:AddressOfReportingEntityDistrictName contextRef="c11">Hellerup</c:AddressOfReportingEntityDistrictName><c:AddressOfReportingEntityCountryIdentificationCode contextRef="c11">DK</c:AddressOfReportingEntityCountryIdentificationCode><c:AddressOfReportingEntityCountry contextRef="c11">Danmark</c:AddressOfReportingEntityCountry><c:DateOfFoundationOfReportingEntity contextRef="c11">1979-12-28</c:DateOfFoundationOfReportingEntity><c:RegisteredOfficeOfReportingEntity contextRef="c11">Gentofte</c:RegisteredOfficeOfReportingEntity><d:NameOfAuditFirm contextRef="c12">PricewaterhouseCoopers</d:NameOfAuditFirm><d:IdentificationNumberCvrOfAuditFirm contextRef="c12">33771231</d:IdentificationNumberCvrOfAuditFirm><d:NameAndSurnameOfAuditor contextRef="c12">Jesper Wiinholt</d:NameAndSurnameOfAuditor><d:DescriptionOfAuditor contextRef="c12">Statsautoriseret revisor</d:DescriptionOfAuditor><c:AddressOfAuditorStreetName contextRef="c12">Strandvejen</c:AddressOfAuditorStreetName><c:AddressOfAuditorStreetBuildingIdentifier contextRef="c12">44</c:AddressOfAuditorStreetBuildingIdentifier><c:AddressOfAuditorPostCodeIdentifier contextRef="c12">2900</c:AddressOfAuditorPostCodeIdentifier><c:AddressOfAuditorDistrictName contextRef="c12">Hellerup</c:AddressOfAuditorDistrictName><c:AddressOfAuditorCountryIdentificationCode contextRef="c12">DK</c:AddressOfAuditorCountryIdentificationCode><c:AddressOfAuditorCountry contextRef="c11">Danmark</c:AddressOfAuditorCountry><c:DateOfGeneralMeeting contextRef="c11">2018-06-21</c:DateOfGeneralMeeting><c:NameAndSurnameOfChairmanOfGeneralMeeting contextRef="c11">Marcus Choleva</c:NameAndSurnameOfChairmanOfGeneralMeeting><e:ClassOfReportingEntity contextRef="c11">Regnskabsklasse C, mellemstor virksomhed</e:ClassOfReportingEntity><d:TypeOfAuditorAssistance contextRef="c11">Revisionspåtegning</d:TypeOfAuditorAssistance><c:ReportingPeriodNumber contextRef="c11" unitRef="u4" decimals="INF">38</c:ReportingPeriodNumber><c:ReportingPeriodNumber contextRef="c11" unitRef="u4" decimals="INF">38</c:ReportingPeriodNumber><f:IdentificationOfApprovedAnnualReport contextRef="c11" xml:lang="da">Direktionen har dags dato behandlet og godkendt årsrapporten for regnskabsåret 1. januar - 31. december 2017 for Adyn ApS.</f:IdentificationOfApprovedAnnualReport><f:IdentificationOfApprovedAnnualReport contextRef="c11" xml:lang="en">The executive board has today discussed and approved the annual report of Adyn ApS for the financial year 1 January - 31 December 2017.</f:IdentificationOfApprovedAnnualReport><f:ConfirmationThatAnnualReportIsPresentedInAccordanceWithRequirementsProvidedForByLegislationAnyStandardsAndRequirementsProvidedByArticlesOfAssociationOrByAgreement contextRef="c11" xml:lang="da">Årsrapporten aflægges i overensstemmelse med årsregnskabsloven.</f:ConfirmationThatAnnualReportIsPresentedInAccordanceWithRequirementsProvidedForByLegislationAnyStandardsAndRequirementsProvidedByArticlesOfAssociationOrByAgreement><f:ConfirmationThatAnnualReportIsPresentedInAccordanceWithRequirementsProvidedForByLegislationAnyStandardsAndRequirementsProvidedByArticlesOfAssociationOrByAgreement contextRef="c11" xml:lang="en">The annual report is prepared in accordance with the Danish Financial Statements Act.</f:ConfirmationThatAnnualReportIsPresentedInAccordanceWithRequirementsProvidedForByLegislationAnyStandardsAndRequirementsProvidedByArticlesOfAssociationOrByAgreement><f:ConfirmationThatFinancialStatementGivesTrueAndFairViewOfAssetsLiabilitiesEquityFinancialPositionAndResults contextRef="c11" xml:lang="da">Det er min opfattelse, at koncernregnskabet og årsregnskabet giver et retvisende billede af koncernens og selskabets  aktiver, passiver og finansielle stilling pr. 31. december 2017 og resultatet af koncernens og selskabets  aktiviteter samt af koncernens pengestrømme for regnskabsåret 1. januar - 31. december 2017.</f:ConfirmationThatFinancialStatementGivesTrueAndFairViewOfAssetsLiabilitiesEquityFinancialPositionAndResults><f:ConfirmationThatFinancialStatementGivesTrueAndFairViewOfAssetsLiabilitiesEquityFinancialPositionAndResults contextRef="c11" xml:lang="en">In my opinion, the consolidated financial statements and parent financial statements give a true and fair view of the company and the group financial position at 31 December 2017 and of the results of the group and the company operations and consolidated cash flows for the financial year 1 January - 31 December 2017.</f:ConfirmationThatFinancialStatementGivesTrueAndFairViewOfAssetsLiabilitiesEquityFinancialPositionAndResults><f:ManagementsStatementAboutManagementsReview contextRef="c11" xml:lang="da">Ledelsesberetningen indeholder efter min opfattelse en retvisende redegørelse for de forhold, beretningen omhandler.</f:ManagementsStatementAboutManagementsReview><f:ManagementsStatementAboutManagementsReview contextRef="c11" xml:lang="en">In my opinion, management's review includes a fair review of the matters dealt with in the management's review.</f:ManagementsStatementAboutManagementsReview><f:RecommendationForApprovalOfAnnualReportByGeneralMeeting contextRef="c11" xml:lang="da">Årsrapporten indstilles til generalforsamlingens godkendelse.</f:RecommendationForApprovalOfAnnualReportByGeneralMeeting><f:RecommendationForApprovalOfAnnualReportByGeneralMeeting contextRef="c11" xml:lang="en">Management recommends that the annual report should be approved at the annual general meeting.</f:RecommendationForApprovalOfAnnualReportByGeneralMeeting><d:NameAndSurnameOfMemberOfExecutiveBoard contextRef="c104">Marcus Choleva</d:NameAndSurnameOfMemberOfExecutiveBoard><g:AddresseeOfAuditorsReportOnAuditedFinancialStatements contextRef="c11" xml:lang="da">Til kapitalejeren i Adyn ApS</g:AddresseeOfAuditorsReportOnAuditedFinancialStatements><g:AddresseeOfAuditorsReportOnAuditedFinancialStatements contextRef="c11" xml:lang="en">To the shareholder of Adyn ApS</g:AddresseeOfAuditorsReportOnAuditedFinancialStatements><g:OpinionOnAuditedFinancialStatements contextRef="c11" xml:lang="da">Vi har revideret koncernregnskabet og årsregnskabet for Adyn ApS for regnskabsåret 1. januar - 31. december 2017, der omfatter anvendt regnskabspraksis, resultatopgørelse, balance, egenkapitalopgørelse og noter for såvel koncernen som selskabet samt pengestrømsopgørelse for koncernen. Koncernregnskabet og årsregnskabet udarbejdes efter årsregnskabsloven.
Det er vor opfattelse, at koncernregnskabet og årsregnskabet giver et retvisende billede af koncernens og selskabets aktiver, passiver og finansielle stilling pr. 31. december 2017 samt af resultatet af koncernens og selskabets aktiviteter og koncernens pengestrømme for regnskabsåret 1. januar - 31. december 2017 i overensstemmelse med årsregnskabsloven.</g:OpinionOnAuditedFinancialStatements><g:OpinionOnAuditedFinancialStatements contextRef="c11" xml:lang="en">We have audited the consolidated financial statements and the parent company financial statements of Adyn ApS for the financial year 1 January - 31 December 2017, which comprise  a summary of significant accounting policies, income statement, balance sheet, statement of changes in equity and notes, for both the group and the parent company as well as consolidated cash flow statement. The consolidated financial statements and the parent company financial statements are prepared under the Danish Financial Statements Act.
In our opinion, the consolidated financial statements and the parent company financial statements give a true and fair view of the group and the parent company's financial position at 31 December 2017 and of the results of the group and the parent company's operations and consolidated cash flows for the financial year 1 January - 31 December 2017 in accordance with the Danish Financial Statements Act.</g:OpinionOnAuditedFinancialStatements><g:DescriptionOfQualificationsOfAuditedFinancialStatements contextRef="c11" xml:lang="da">Vi har udført vor revision i overensstemmelse med internationale standarder om revision og de yderligere krav, der er gældende i Danmark. Vort ansvar ifølge disse standarder og krav er nærmere beskrevet i revisionspåtegningens afsnit “Revisors ansvar for revisionen af koncernregnskabet og årsregnskabet“. Vi er uafhængige af koncernen i overensstemmelse med internationale etiske regler for revisorer (IESBA’s Etiske regler) og de yderligere krav, der er gældende i Danmark, ligesom vi har opfyldt vore øvrige etiske forpligtelser i henhold til disse regler og krav. Det er vor opfattelse, at det opnåede revisionsbevis er tilstrækkeligt og egnet som grundlag for vor konklusion.</g:DescriptionOfQualificationsOfAuditedFinancialStatements><g:DescriptionOfQualificationsOfAuditedFinancialStatements contextRef="c11" xml:lang="en">We conducted our audit in accordance with International Standards on Auditing (ISAs) and the additional requirements applicable in Denmark. Our responsibilities under those standards and requirements are further described in the “Auditor's responsibilities for the audit of the consolidated financial statements and parent company financial statements” section of our report. We are independent of the group in accordance with the International Ethics Standards Board for Accountants' Code of Ethics for Professional Accountants (IESBA Code) and the additional requirements applicable in Denmark, and we have fulfilled our other ethical responsibilities in accordance with these requirements. We believe that the audit evidence we have obtained is sufficient and appropriate to provide a basis for our opinion.</g:DescriptionOfQualificationsOfAuditedFinancialStatements><g:StatementOfExecutiveAndSupervisoryBoardsResponsibilityForFinancialStatements contextRef="c11" xml:lang="da">Ledelsen har ansvaret for udarbejdelsen af et koncernregnskab og et årsregnskab, der giver et retvisende billede i overensstemmelse med årsregnskabsloven. Ledelsen har endvidere ansvaret for den interne kontrol, som ledelsen anser for nødvendig for at udarbejde et koncernregnskab og et årsregnskab uden væsentlig fejlinformation, uanset om denne skyldes besvigelser eller fejl.
Ved udarbejdelsen af koncernregnskabet og årsregnskabet er ledelsen ansvarlig for at vurdere koncernens og selskabets evne til at fortsætte driften, at oplyse om forhold vedrørende fortsat drift, hvor dette er relevant, samt at udarbejde koncernregnskabet og årsregnskabet på grundlag af regnskabsprincippet om fortsat drift, medmindre ledelsen enten har til hensigt at likvidere koncernen eller selskabet, indstille driften eller ikke har andet realistisk alternativ end at gøre dette.</g:StatementOfExecutiveAndSupervisoryBoardsResponsibilityForFinancialStatements><g:StatementOfExecutiveAndSupervisoryBoardsResponsibilityForFinancialStatements contextRef="c11" xml:lang="en">Management is responsible for the preparation of consolidated financial statements and parent company financial statements that give a true and fair view in accordance with the Danish Financial Statements Act, and for such internal control as management determines is necessary to enable the preparation of consolidated financial statements and parent company financial statements that are free from material misstatement, whether due to fraud or error.
In preparing the consolidated financial statements and parent company financial statements, management is responsible for assessing the group's and the parent company's ability to continue as a going concern, disclosing, as applicable, matters related to going concern and using the going concern basis of accounting in preparing the consolidated financial statements and parent company financial statements unless management either intends to liquidate the group or the company or to cease operations, or has no realistic alternative but to do so.</g:StatementOfExecutiveAndSupervisoryBoardsResponsibilityForFinancialStatements><g:StatementOfAuditorsResponsibilityForAuditAndAuditPerformed contextRef="c11" xml:lang="da">Vort mål er at opnå høj grad af sikkerhed for, om koncernregnskabet og årsregnskabet som helhed er uden væsentlig fejlinformation, uanset om denne skyldes besvigelser eller fejl, og at afgive en revisionspåtegning med en konklusion. Høj grad af sikkerhed er et højt niveau af sikkerhed, men er ikke en garanti for, at en revision, der udføres i overensstemmelse med internationale standarder om revision og de yderligere krav, der er gældende i Danmark, altid vil afdække væsentlig fejlinformation, når sådan findes. Fejlinformationer kan opstå som følge af besvigelser eller fejl og kan betragtes som væsentlige, hvis det med rimelighed kan forventes, at de enkeltvis eller samlet har indflydelse på de økonomiske beslutninger, som regnskabsbrugerne træffer på grundlag af koncernregnskabet og årsregnskabet.
Som led i en revision, der udføres i overensstemmelse med internationale standarder om revision og de yderligere krav, der er gældende i Danmark, foretager vi faglige vurderinger og opretholder professionel skepsis under revisionen. Herudover:
Identificerer og vurderer vi risikoen for væsentlig fejlinformation i koncernregnskabet og årsregnskabet, uanset om denne skyldes besvigelser eller fejl, udformer og udfører revisionshandlinger som reaktion på disse risici samt opnår revisionsbevis, der er tilstrækkeligt og egnet til at danne grundlag for vor konklusion. Risikoen for ikke at opdage væsentlig fejlinformation forårsaget af besvigelser er højere end ved væsentlig fejlinformation forårsaget af fejl, idet besvigelser kan omfatte sammensværgelser, dokumentfalsk, bevidste udeladelser, vildledning eller tilsidesættelse af intern kontrol.
Opnår vi forståelse af den interne kontrol med relevans for revisionen for at kunne udforme revisionshandlinger, der er passende efter omstændighederne, men ikke for at kunne udtrykke en konklusion om effektiviteten af koncernens og selskabets interne kontrol.
Tager vi stilling til, om den regnskabspraksis, som er anvendt af ledelsen, er passende, samt om de regnskabsmæssige skøn og tilknyttede oplysninger, som ledelsen har udarbejdet, er rimelige.
Konkluderer vi, om ledelsens udarbejdelse af koncernregnskabet og årsregnskabet på grundlag af regnskabsprincippet om fortsat drift er passende, samt om der på grundlag af det opnåede revisionsbevis er væsentlig usikkerhed forbundet med begivenheder eller forhold, der kan skabe betydelig tvivl om koncernens og selskabets evne til at fortsætte driften. Hvis vi konkluderer, at der er en væsentlig usikkerhed, skal vi i vor revisionspåtegning gøre opmærksom på oplysninger herom i koncernregnskabet og årsregnskabet eller, hvis sådanne oplysninger ikke er tilstrækkelige, modificere vor konklusion. Vor konklusioner er baseret på det revisionsbevis, der er opnået frem til datoen for vor revisionspåtegning. Fremtidige begivenheder eller forhold kan dog medføre, at koncernen og selskabet ikke længere kan fortsætte driften.
Tager vi stilling til den samlede præsentation, struktur og indhold af koncernregnskabet og årsregnskabet, herunder noteoplysningerne, samt om koncernregnskabet og årsregnskabet afspejler de underliggende transaktioner og begivenheder på en sådan måde, at der gives et retvisende billede heraf.
Opnår vi tilstrækkeligt og egnet revisionsbevis for de finansielle oplysninger for virksomhederne eller forretningsaktiviteterne i koncernen til brug for at udtrykke en konklusion om koncernregnskabet. Vi er ansvarlige for at lede, føre tilsyn med og udføre koncernrevisionen. Vi er eneansvarlige for vor revisionskonklusion.
Vi kommunikerer med den øverste ledelse om blandt andet det planlagte omfang og den tidsmæssige placering af revisionen samt betydelige revisionsmæssige observationer, herunder eventuelle betydelige mangler i intern kontrol, som vi identificerer under revisionen.</g:StatementOfAuditorsResponsibilityForAuditAndAuditPerformed><g:StatementOfAuditorsResponsibilityForAuditAndAuditPerformed contextRef="c11" xml:lang="en">Our objectives are to obtain reasonable assurance about whether the consolidated financial statements and parent company financial statements as a whole are free from material misstatement, whether due to fraud or error, and to issue an auditor's report that includes our opinion. Reasonable assurance is a high level of assurance, but is not a guarantee that an audit conducted in accordance with ISAs and the additional requirements applicable in Denmark will always detect a material misstatement when it exists. Misstatements can arise from fraud or error and are considered material if, individually or in the aggregate, they could reasonably be expected to influence the economic decisions of users taken on the basis of these consolidated financial statements and parent company financial statements
As part of an audit conducted in accordance with ISAs and the additional requirements applicable in Denmark, we exercise professional judgment and maintain professional skepticism throughout the audit. We also:
Identify and assess the risks of material misstatement of the consolidated financial statements and parent company financial statements, whether due to fraud or error, design and perform audit procedures responsive to those risks, and obtain audit evidence that is sufficient and appropriate to provide a basis for our opinion. The risk of not detecting a material misstatement resulting from fraud is higher than for one resulting from error as fraud may involve collusion, forgery, intentional omissions, misrepresentations, or the override of internal control.
Obtain an understanding of internal control relevant to the audit in order to design audit procedures that are appropriate in the circumstances, but not for the purpose of expressing an opinion on the effectiveness of the group's and the parent company's  internal control.
Evaluate the appropriateness of accounting policies used and the reasonableness of accounting estimates and related disclosures made by management.
Conclude on the appropriateness of management's use of the going concern basis of accounting in preparing the consolidated financial statements and parent company financial statements and, based on the audit evidence obtained, whether a material uncertainty exists related to events or conditions that may cast significant doubt on the group's and the parent company's  ability to continue as a going concern. If we conclude that a material uncertainty exists, we are required to draw attention in our auditor's report to the related disclosures in the consolidated financial statements and parent company financial statements or, if such disclosures are inadequate, to modify our opinion. Our conclusions are based on the audit evidence obtained up to the date of our auditor's report. However, future events or conditions may cause the group and the company to cease to continue as a going concern.
Evaluate the overall presentation, structure and contents of the consolidated financial statements and parent company financial statements, including the disclosures, and whether the consolidated financial statements and parent company financial statements represent the underlying transactions and events in a manner that gives a true and fair view.
Obtain sufficient and appropriate audit evidence regarding the financial information for the group's entities or business activities to express an opinion on the consolidated financial statements. We are responsible for directing, supervising and conducting the audit of the group. We alone are responsible for our audit opinion.
We communicate with those charged with governance regarding, among other matters, the planned scope and timing of the audit and significant audit findings, including any significant deficiencies in internal control that we identify during our audit.</g:StatementOfAuditorsResponsibilityForAuditAndAuditPerformed><g:StatementOnManagementsReviewAuditorsReportOnAuditedFinancialStatements contextRef="c11" xml:lang="da">Udtalelse om ledelsesberetningen
Ledelsen er ansvarlig for ledelsesberetningen.
Vor konklusion om koncernregnskabet og årsregnskabet omfatter ikke ledelsesberetningen, og vi udtrykker ingen form for konklusion med sikkerhed om ledelsesberetningen.
I tilknytning til vor revision af koncernregnskabet og årsregnskabet er det vort ansvar at læse ledelsesberetningen og i den forbindelse overveje, om ledelsesberetningen er væsentligt inkonsistent med koncernregnskabet eller årsregnskabet eller vor viden opnået ved revisionen eller på anden måde synes at indeholde væsentlig fejlinformation.
Vort ansvar er derudover at overveje, om ledelsesberetningen indeholder krævede oplysninger i henhold til årsregnskabsloven.
Baseret på det udførte arbejde er det vor opfattelse, at ledelsesberetningen er i overensstemmelse med koncernregnskabet og årsregnskabet og er udarbejdet i overensstemmelse med årsregnskabslovens krav. Vi har ikke fundet væsentlig fejlinformation i ledelsesberetningen.</g:StatementOnManagementsReviewAuditorsReportOnAuditedFinancialStatements><g:StatementOnManagementsReviewAuditorsReportOnAuditedFinancialStatements contextRef="c11" xml:lang="en">Statement on management's review
Management is responsible for management's review.
Our opinion on the consolidated financial statements and parent company financial statements does not cover management's review, and we do not express any form of assurance conclusion thereon.
In connection with our audit of the consolidated financial statements and parent company financial statements, our responsibility is to read management's review and, in doing so, consider whether management's review is materially inconsistent with the consolidated financial statements and parent company financial statements or our knowledge obtained during the audit, or otherwise appears to be materially misstated.
Moreover, it is our responsibility to consider whether management's review provides the information required under the Danish Financial Statements Act.
Based on the work we have performed, we conclude that management's review is in accordance with the consolidated financial statements and parent company financial statements and has been prepared in accordance with the requirements of the Danish Financial Statements Act. We did not identify any material misstatement of management's review.</g:StatementOnManagementsReviewAuditorsReportOnAuditedFinancialStatements><g:SignatureOfAuditorsPlace contextRef="c11">Hellerup</g:SignatureOfAuditorsPlace><g:SignatureOfAuditorsDate contextRef="c11">2018-06-21</g:SignatureOfAuditorsDate><d:NameOfAuditFirm contextRef="c12">PricewaterhouseCoopers</d:NameOfAuditFirm><d:NameAndSurnameOfAuditor contextRef="c12">Jesper Wiinholt</d:NameAndSurnameOfAuditor><d:DescriptionOfAuditor contextRef="c12">Statsautoriseret revisor</d:DescriptionOfAuditor><d:IdentificationNumberOfAuditor contextRef="c12">mne13914</d:IdentificationNumberOfAuditor><d:NameAndSurnameOfAuditor contextRef="c14">Lasse Hartlev</d:NameAndSurnameOfAuditor><d:DescriptionOfAuditor contextRef="c14">Statsautoriseret revisor</d:DescriptionOfAuditor><d:IdentificationNumberOfAuditor contextRef="c14">mne34350</d:IdentificationNumberOfAuditor><e:Revenue contextRef="c19" unitRef="u2" decimals="-3">27532000</e:Revenue><e:Revenue contextRef="c22" unitRef="u2" decimals="-3">23995000</e:Revenue><e:Revenue contextRef="c25" unitRef="u2" decimals="-3">24607000</e:Revenue><e:ResultsFromNetFinancials contextRef="c11" unitRef="u2" decimals="-3">72928000</e:ResultsFromNetFinancials><e:ResultsFromNetFinancials contextRef="c17" unitRef="u2" decimals="-3">34485000</e:ResultsFromNetFinancials><e:ResultsFromNetFinancials contextRef="c19" unitRef="u2" decimals="-3">37420000</e:ResultsFromNetFinancials><e:ResultsFromNetFinancials contextRef="c22" unitRef="u2" decimals="-3">19892000</e:ResultsFromNetFinancials><e:ResultsFromNetFinancials contextRef="c25" unitRef="u2" decimals="-3">60248000</e:ResultsFromNetFinancials><e:ProfitLoss contextRef="c19" unitRef="u2" decimals="-3">47708000</e:ProfitLoss><e:ProfitLoss contextRef="c22" unitRef="u2" decimals="-3">23403000</e:ProfitLoss><e:ProfitLoss contextRef="c25" unitRef="u2" decimals="-3">60896000</e:ProfitLoss><e:Assets contextRef="c21" unitRef="u2" decimals="-3">872580000</e:Assets><e:Assets contextRef="c24" unitRef="u2" decimals="-3">858674000</e:Assets><e:Assets contextRef="c27" unitRef="u2" decimals="-3">830593000</e:Assets><e:InvestmentInPropertyPlantAndEquipment contextRef="c11" unitRef="u2" decimals="-3">361463000</e:InvestmentInPropertyPlantAndEquipment><e:InvestmentInPropertyPlantAndEquipment contextRef="c17" unitRef="u2" decimals="-3">357031000</e:InvestmentInPropertyPlantAndEquipment><e:InvestmentInPropertyPlantAndEquipment contextRef="c19" unitRef="u2" decimals="-3">318428000</e:InvestmentInPropertyPlantAndEquipment><e:InvestmentInPropertyPlantAndEquipment contextRef="c22" unitRef="u2" decimals="-3">316015000</e:InvestmentInPropertyPlantAndEquipment><e:InvestmentInPropertyPlantAndEquipment contextRef="c25" unitRef="u2" decimals="-3">296683000</e:InvestmentInPropertyPlantAndEquipment><e:Equity contextRef="c21" unitRef="u2" decimals="-3">655111000</e:Equity><e:Equity contextRef="c24" unitRef="u2" decimals="-3">607406000</e:Equity><e:Equity contextRef="c27" unitRef="u2" decimals="-3">584003000</e:Equity><h:EquityRatio contextRef="c11" unitRef="u4" decimals="1">79.8</h:EquityRatio><h:EquityRatio contextRef="c17" unitRef="u4" decimals="1">75.1</h:EquityRatio><h:EquityRatio contextRef="c19" unitRef="u4" decimals="1">75.1</h:EquityRatio><h:EquityRatio contextRef="c22" unitRef="u4" decimals="1">70.7</h:EquityRatio><h:EquityRatio contextRef="c25" unitRef="u4" decimals="1">70.3</h:EquityRatio><h:ReturnOnEquity contextRef="c11" unitRef="u4" decimals="1">10.4</h:ReturnOnEquity><h:ReturnOnEquity contextRef="c17" unitRef="u4" decimals="1">10</h:ReturnOnEquity><h:ReturnOnEquity contextRef="c19" unitRef="u4" decimals="1">7.6</h:ReturnOnEquity><h:ReturnOnEquity contextRef="c22" unitRef="u4" decimals="1">3.9</h:ReturnOnEquity><h:ReturnOnEquity contextRef="c25" unitRef="u4" decimals="1">11</h:ReturnOnEquity><h:ManagementsReview contextRef="c11" xml:lang="da">Koncernens væsentligste aktiviteter
Selskabets og koncernens hovedaktivitet er udlejning af fast ejendom og investering i andre selskaber, herunder virksomheder der investerer i vedvarende energi.
Usikkerhed ved indregning og måling
Der er ikke forekommet væsentlig usikkerhed ved indregning og måling i årsrapporten.
Usædvanlige forhold
Koncernens aktiver, passiver og finansielle stilling pr. 31. december 2017 samt resultatet af koncernens aktiviteter og pengestrømme for regnskabsåret 2017 er ikke påvirket af usædvanlige forhold.
Udviklingen i aktiviteter og økonomiske forhold
Koncernens resultatopgørelse for 2017 udviser et overskud på kr. 79.724.516, og selskabets balance pr. 31. december 2017 udviser en egenkapital på kr. 803.651.168.
Selskabet er med regnskabsmæssig virkning pr. 1. januar 2017 fusioneret med sine 2 søsterselskaber Nyda-Finans ApS og ApS EGA-Administration, og med Adyn ApS som det fortsættende selskab.

Fusionen er regnskabsmæssigt behandlet efter sammenlægningsmetoden, og der er således foretaget tilpasning af sammenligningstal for 2016.
Virksomhedens forventede udvikling, herunder særlige forudsætninger og usikre faktorer
Koncernen forventer et resultat før finansielle poster på DKK 15-25 mio. for 2018. Koncernens resultat er væsentligt påvirket af kursudviklingen for børsnoterede aktier, der i væsentlig grad kan påvirke resultatet. Der forventes et resultat for 2018 på kr. 40 - 75 mio.
Året der gik og opfølgning på sidste års forventede udvikling
Der er ikke offentliggjort forventninger for 2017.
Betydningsfulde hændelser, som er indtruffet efter regnskabsårets afslutning
Der er efter regnskabsårets afslutning ikke indtruffet begivenheder, som væsentligt vil kunne påvirke selskabets finansielle stilling.</h:ManagementsReview><h:ManagementsReview contextRef="c11" xml:lang="en">Business activities
The Company's and the Group's main activity is rental of real estate and investment in other companies, including companies investing in renewable energy.
Recognition and measurement uncertainties
The recognition and measurement of items in the financial statements is not subject to any significant uncertainty.
Unusual matters
The Groups financial position at 31 December 2017 and the results of its operations and cash flows for the financial year ended 31 December 2017 are not affected by any unusual matters.
Business review 
The Group income statement for the year ended 31 December shows a profit of kr. 79.724.516, and the balance sheet at 31 December 2017 shows equity of kr. 803.651.168.
With financial effect as of 1 January 2017 the company has merged with its two sister companies Nyda-Finans ApS and ApS EGA-Administration, and with Adyn ApS as the continuing company.

 The merger is accounted for in accordance with the merging accounting method, and thus the comparative figures have been adjusted for 2016.
Financial review
The Group expect a profit before financial income and expenses of kr. 15-25 million for 2018. The Group's profits are significantly affected by the price development of listed shares, which can significantly affect the comany's profit. The expected profit for 2018 is kr. 40-75 million.
The year at a glance and follow-up on expectations expressed last year
There are no puclished expectations for 2017.
Significant events occurring after end of reporting period
No events have occurred after the balance sheet date which could significantly affect the company's  financial position.</h:ManagementsReview><e:Revenue contextRef="c11" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">29523481</e:Revenue><e:Revenue contextRef="c17" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">28207792</e:Revenue><e:OtherOperatingIncome contextRef="c11" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">19601</e:OtherOperatingIncome><e:OtherOperatingIncome contextRef="c17" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">1107435</e:OtherOperatingIncome><e:OtherExternalExpenses contextRef="c11" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">9741509</e:OtherExternalExpenses><e:OtherExternalExpenses contextRef="c17" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">13873367</e:OtherExternalExpenses><e:GrossResult contextRef="c11" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">19801573</e:GrossResult><e:GrossResult contextRef="c17" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">15441860</e:GrossResult><e:EmployeeBenefitsExpense contextRef="c11" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">3807171</e:EmployeeBenefitsExpense><e:EmployeeBenefitsExpense contextRef="c17" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">2710350</e:EmployeeBenefitsExpense><e:DepreciationAmortisationExpenseAndImpairmentLossesOfPropertyPlantAndEquipmentAndIntangibleAssetsRecognisedInProfitOrLoss contextRef="c11" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">1382649</e:DepreciationAmortisationExpenseAndImpairmentLossesOfPropertyPlantAndEquipmentAndIntangibleAssetsRecognisedInProfitOrLoss><e:DepreciationAmortisationExpenseAndImpairmentLossesOfPropertyPlantAndEquipmentAndIntangibleAssetsRecognisedInProfitOrLoss contextRef="c17" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">773552</e:DepreciationAmortisationExpenseAndImpairmentLossesOfPropertyPlantAndEquipmentAndIntangibleAssetsRecognisedInProfitOrLoss><e:ProfitLossFromOrdinaryOperatingActivitiesBeforeGainsLossesFromFairValueAdjustments contextRef="c11" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">14611753</e:ProfitLossFromOrdinaryOperatingActivitiesBeforeGainsLossesFromFairValueAdjustments><e:ProfitLossFromOrdinaryOperatingActivitiesBeforeGainsLossesFromFairValueAdjustments contextRef="c17" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">11957958</e:ProfitLossFromOrdinaryOperatingActivitiesBeforeGainsLossesFromFairValueAdjustments><e:ProfitLossFromOrdinaryOperatingActivities contextRef="c11" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">23017448</e:ProfitLossFromOrdinaryOperatingActivities><e:ProfitLossFromOrdinaryOperatingActivities contextRef="c17" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">48037901</e:ProfitLossFromOrdinaryOperatingActivities><e:IncomeFromInvestmentsInGroupEnterprises contextRef="c11" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">0</e:IncomeFromInvestmentsInGroupEnterprises><e:IncomeFromInvestmentsInGroupEnterprises contextRef="c17" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">0</e:IncomeFromInvestmentsInGroupEnterprises><e:IncomeFromInvestmentsInAssociates contextRef="c11" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">19645697</e:IncomeFromInvestmentsInAssociates><e:IncomeFromInvestmentsInAssociates contextRef="c17" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">644</e:IncomeFromInvestmentsInAssociates><e:OtherFinanceIncome contextRef="c11" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">58041711</e:OtherFinanceIncome><e:OtherFinanceIncome contextRef="c17" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">50186283</e:OtherFinanceIncome><e:OtherFinanceExpenses contextRef="c11" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">4759316</e:OtherFinanceExpenses><e:OtherFinanceExpenses contextRef="c17" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">15701928</e:OtherFinanceExpenses><e:ProfitLossFromOrdinaryActivitiesBeforeTax contextRef="c11" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">95945540</e:ProfitLossFromOrdinaryActivitiesBeforeTax><e:ProfitLossFromOrdinaryActivitiesBeforeTax contextRef="c17" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">82522900</e:ProfitLossFromOrdinaryActivitiesBeforeTax><e:TaxExpense contextRef="c11" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">16053262</e:TaxExpense><e:TaxExpense contextRef="c17" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">13151900</e:TaxExpense><e:ProfitLossAttributableToMinorityInterest contextRef="c11" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">167762</e:ProfitLossAttributableToMinorityInterest><e:ProfitLossAttributableToMinorityInterest contextRef="c17" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">445685</e:ProfitLossAttributableToMinorityInterest><e:ProfitLoss contextRef="c11" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">79724516</e:ProfitLoss><e:ProfitLoss contextRef="c17" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">68925315</e:ProfitLoss><e:InvestmentProperty contextRef="c75" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">355748331</e:InvestmentProperty><e:InvestmentProperty contextRef="c74" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">349935006</e:InvestmentProperty><e:LandAndBuildings contextRef="c75" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">3500000</e:LandAndBuildings><e:LandAndBuildings contextRef="c74" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">4037440</e:LandAndBuildings><e:FixturesFittingsToolsAndEquipment contextRef="c75" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">2214964</e:FixturesFittingsToolsAndEquipment><e:FixturesFittingsToolsAndEquipment contextRef="c74" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">3058742</e:FixturesFittingsToolsAndEquipment><e:PropertyPlantAndEquipment contextRef="c75" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">361463295</e:PropertyPlantAndEquipment><e:PropertyPlantAndEquipment contextRef="c74" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">357031188</e:PropertyPlantAndEquipment><e:LongtermInvestmentsInGroupEnterprises contextRef="c75" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">0</e:LongtermInvestmentsInGroupEnterprises><e:LongtermInvestmentsInGroupEnterprises contextRef="c74" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">0</e:LongtermInvestmentsInGroupEnterprises><e:LongtermInvestmentsInAssociates contextRef="c75" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">65516703</e:LongtermInvestmentsInAssociates><e:LongtermInvestmentsInAssociates contextRef="c74" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">57538976</e:LongtermInvestmentsInAssociates><e:LongtermReceivablesFromAssociates contextRef="c75" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">19652691</e:LongtermReceivablesFromAssociates><e:LongtermReceivablesFromAssociates contextRef="c74" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">20225718</e:LongtermReceivablesFromAssociates><e:OtherLongtermInvestments contextRef="c75" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">437947107</e:OtherLongtermInvestments><e:OtherLongtermInvestments contextRef="c74" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">396845368</e:OtherLongtermInvestments><e:LongtermInvestmentsAndReceivables contextRef="c75" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">523116501</e:LongtermInvestmentsAndReceivables><e:LongtermInvestmentsAndReceivables contextRef="c74" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">474610062</e:LongtermInvestmentsAndReceivables><e:NoncurrentAssets contextRef="c75" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">884579796</e:NoncurrentAssets><e:NoncurrentAssets contextRef="c74" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">831641250</e:NoncurrentAssets><e:ShorttermTradeReceivables contextRef="c75" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">70338</e:ShorttermTradeReceivables><e:ShorttermTradeReceivables contextRef="c74" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">282687</e:ShorttermTradeReceivables><e:ShorttermReceivablesFromGroupEnterprises contextRef="c75" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">0</e:ShorttermReceivablesFromGroupEnterprises><e:ShorttermReceivablesFromGroupEnterprises contextRef="c74" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">0</e:ShorttermReceivablesFromGroupEnterprises><e:ShorttermReceivablesFromAssociates contextRef="c75" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">5178285</e:ShorttermReceivablesFromAssociates><e:ShorttermReceivablesFromAssociates contextRef="c74" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">5732718</e:ShorttermReceivablesFromAssociates><e:OtherShorttermReceivables contextRef="c75" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">10471389</e:OtherShorttermReceivables><e:OtherShorttermReceivables contextRef="c74" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">7947771</e:OtherShorttermReceivables><e:ShorttermTaxReceivables contextRef="c75" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">0</e:ShorttermTaxReceivables><e:ShorttermTaxReceivables contextRef="c74" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">0</e:ShorttermTaxReceivables><e:DeferredIncomeAssets contextRef="c75" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">804798</e:DeferredIncomeAssets><e:DeferredIncomeAssets contextRef="c74" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">910989</e:DeferredIncomeAssets><e:ShorttermReceivables contextRef="c75" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">16524810</e:ShorttermReceivables><e:ShorttermReceivables contextRef="c74" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">14874165</e:ShorttermReceivables><e:OtherShorttermInvestments contextRef="c75" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">0</e:OtherShorttermInvestments><e:OtherShorttermInvestments contextRef="c74" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">110460954</e:OtherShorttermInvestments><e:ShorttermInvestments contextRef="c75" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">0</e:ShorttermInvestments><e:ShorttermInvestments contextRef="c74" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">110460954</e:ShorttermInvestments><e:CashAndCashEquivalents contextRef="c75" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">105748196</e:CashAndCashEquivalents><e:CashAndCashEquivalents contextRef="c74" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">7352867</e:CashAndCashEquivalents><e:CurrentAssets contextRef="c75" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">122273006</e:CurrentAssets><e:CurrentAssets contextRef="c74" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">132687986</e:CurrentAssets><e:Assets contextRef="c75" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">1006852802</e:Assets><e:Assets contextRef="c74" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">964329236</e:Assets><e:ContributedCapital contextRef="c75" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">385037</e:ContributedCapital><e:ContributedCapital contextRef="c74" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">385037</e:ContributedCapital><e:RetainedEarnings contextRef="c75" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">803266131</e:RetainedEarnings><e:RetainedEarnings contextRef="c74" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">723487052</e:RetainedEarnings><e:Equity contextRef="c75" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">803651168</e:Equity><e:Equity contextRef="c74" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">723872089</e:Equity><e:MinorityInterests contextRef="c75" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">2812843</e:MinorityInterests><e:MinorityInterests contextRef="c74" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">2645406</e:MinorityInterests><e:ProvisionsForDeferredTax contextRef="c75" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">34022815</e:ProvisionsForDeferredTax><e:ProvisionsForDeferredTax contextRef="c74" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">33089432</e:ProvisionsForDeferredTax><e:Provisions contextRef="c75" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">34022815</e:Provisions><e:Provisions contextRef="c74" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">33089432</e:Provisions><e:LongtermMortgageDebt contextRef="c75" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">122867610</e:LongtermMortgageDebt><e:LongtermMortgageDebt contextRef="c74" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">129328468</e:LongtermMortgageDebt><e:OtherLongtermPayables contextRef="c75" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">9770098</e:OtherLongtermPayables><e:OtherLongtermPayables contextRef="c74" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">9605968</e:OtherLongtermPayables><e:LongtermLiabilitiesOtherThanProvisions contextRef="c75" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">132637708</e:LongtermLiabilitiesOtherThanProvisions><e:LongtermLiabilitiesOtherThanProvisions contextRef="c74" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">138934436</e:LongtermLiabilitiesOtherThanProvisions><e:ShorttermPartOfLongtermLiabilitiesOtherThanProvisions contextRef="c75" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">6481157</e:ShorttermPartOfLongtermLiabilitiesOtherThanProvisions><e:ShorttermPartOfLongtermLiabilitiesOtherThanProvisions contextRef="c74" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">6360735</e:ShorttermPartOfLongtermLiabilitiesOtherThanProvisions><e:ShorttermDebtToBanks contextRef="c75" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">6156840</e:ShorttermDebtToBanks><e:ShorttermDebtToBanks contextRef="c74" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">39229096</e:ShorttermDebtToBanks><e:ShorttermPrepaymentsReceivedFromCustomers contextRef="c75" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">136861</e:ShorttermPrepaymentsReceivedFromCustomers><e:ShorttermPrepaymentsReceivedFromCustomers contextRef="c74" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">564012</e:ShorttermPrepaymentsReceivedFromCustomers><e:ShorttermTradePayables contextRef="c75" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">264033</e:ShorttermTradePayables><e:ShorttermTradePayables contextRef="c74" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">713278</e:ShorttermTradePayables><e:ShorttermPayablesToGroupEnterprises contextRef="c75" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">0</e:ShorttermPayablesToGroupEnterprises><e:ShorttermPayablesToGroupEnterprises contextRef="c74" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">0</e:ShorttermPayablesToGroupEnterprises><e:ShorttermPayablesToAssociates contextRef="c75" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">3092320</e:ShorttermPayablesToAssociates><e:ShorttermPayablesToAssociates contextRef="c74" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">406309</e:ShorttermPayablesToAssociates><e:ShorttermPayablesToShareholdersAndManagement contextRef="c75" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">299595</e:ShorttermPayablesToShareholdersAndManagement><e:ShorttermPayablesToShareholdersAndManagement contextRef="c74" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">11190801</e:ShorttermPayablesToShareholdersAndManagement><e:ShorttermTaxPayables contextRef="c75" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">10337799</e:ShorttermTaxPayables><e:ShorttermTaxPayables contextRef="c74" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">2398067</e:ShorttermTaxPayables><e:OtherShorttermPayables contextRef="c75" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">6959663</e:OtherShorttermPayables><e:OtherShorttermPayables contextRef="c74" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">4925575</e:OtherShorttermPayables><e:ShorttermLiabilitiesOtherThanProvisions contextRef="c75" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">33728268</e:ShorttermLiabilitiesOtherThanProvisions><e:ShorttermLiabilitiesOtherThanProvisions contextRef="c74" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">65787873</e:ShorttermLiabilitiesOtherThanProvisions><e:LiabilitiesOtherThanProvisions contextRef="c75" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">166365976</e:LiabilitiesOtherThanProvisions><e:LiabilitiesOtherThanProvisions contextRef="c74" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">204722309</e:LiabilitiesOtherThanProvisions><e:LiabilitiesAndEquity contextRef="c75" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">1006852802</e:LiabilitiesAndEquity><e:LiabilitiesAndEquity contextRef="c74" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">964329236</e:LiabilitiesAndEquity><e:Equity contextRef="c113" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">385037</e:Equity><e:Equity contextRef="c131" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">723487052</e:Equity><e:IncreaseDecreaseOfInvestmentsThroughNetExchangeDifferencesEquity contextRef="c114" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">0</e:IncreaseDecreaseOfInvestmentsThroughNetExchangeDifferencesEquity><e:IncreaseDecreaseOfInvestmentsThroughNetExchangeDifferencesEquity contextRef="c132" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">54563</e:IncreaseDecreaseOfInvestmentsThroughNetExchangeDifferencesEquity><e:ProfitLoss contextRef="c132" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">79724516</e:ProfitLoss><e:Equity contextRef="c115" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">385037</e:Equity><e:Equity contextRef="c133" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">803266131</e:Equity><e:Equity contextRef="c1284" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">338290</e:Equity><e:Equity contextRef="c1304" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">577734017</e:Equity><e:AdditionsToDisposalsOfEquityThroughMergersAndBusinessCombinations contextRef="c1285" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">46747</e:AdditionsToDisposalsOfEquityThroughMergersAndBusinessCombinations><e:AdditionsToDisposalsOfEquityThroughMergersAndBusinessCombinations contextRef="c1305" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">76991619</e:AdditionsToDisposalsOfEquityThroughMergersAndBusinessCombinations><e:IncreaseDecreaseOfInvestmentsThroughNetExchangeDifferencesEquity contextRef="c1285" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">0</e:IncreaseDecreaseOfInvestmentsThroughNetExchangeDifferencesEquity><e:IncreaseDecreaseOfInvestmentsThroughNetExchangeDifferencesEquity contextRef="c1305" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">-163899</e:IncreaseDecreaseOfInvestmentsThroughNetExchangeDifferencesEquity><e:ProfitLoss contextRef="c1305" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">68925315</e:ProfitLoss><e:Equity contextRef="c1286" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">385037</e:Equity><e:Equity contextRef="c1306" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">723487052</e:Equity><e:ProfitLoss contextRef="c11" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">79724516</e:ProfitLoss><e:ProfitLoss contextRef="c17" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">68925315</e:ProfitLoss><e:Adjustments contextRef="c11" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">-64103957</e:Adjustments><e:Adjustments contextRef="c17" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">-55564489</e:Adjustments><e:AdjustmentsForDecreaseIncreaseInWorkingCapital contextRef="c11" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">-8125121</e:AdjustmentsForDecreaseIncreaseInWorkingCapital><e:AdjustmentsForDecreaseIncreaseInWorkingCapital contextRef="c17" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">-16894955</e:AdjustmentsForDecreaseIncreaseInWorkingCapital><e:CashFlowFromOperatingActivitiesBeforeFinancialItems contextRef="c11" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">7495438</e:CashFlowFromOperatingActivitiesBeforeFinancialItems><e:CashFlowFromOperatingActivitiesBeforeFinancialItems contextRef="c17" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">-3534129</e:CashFlowFromOperatingActivitiesBeforeFinancialItems><e:InterestReceivedClassifiedAsOperatingActivities contextRef="c11" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">22553968</e:InterestReceivedClassifiedAsOperatingActivities><e:InterestReceivedClassifiedAsOperatingActivities contextRef="c17" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">50186283</e:InterestReceivedClassifiedAsOperatingActivities><e:InterestPaidClassifiedAsOperatingActivities contextRef="c11" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">-4569316</e:InterestPaidClassifiedAsOperatingActivities><e:InterestPaidClassifiedAsOperatingActivities contextRef="c17" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">-13688128</e:InterestPaidClassifiedAsOperatingActivities><e:CashFlowFromOrdinaryOperatingActivities contextRef="c11" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">25480090</e:CashFlowFromOrdinaryOperatingActivities><e:CashFlowFromOrdinaryOperatingActivities contextRef="c17" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">32964026</e:CashFlowFromOrdinaryOperatingActivities><e:IncomeTaxesPaidRefundClassifiedAsOperatingActivities contextRef="c11" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">-7186739</e:IncomeTaxesPaidRefundClassifiedAsOperatingActivities><e:IncomeTaxesPaidRefundClassifiedAsOperatingActivities contextRef="c17" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">-8014746</e:IncomeTaxesPaidRefundClassifiedAsOperatingActivities><e:CashFlowsFromUsedInOperatingActivities contextRef="c11" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">18293351</e:CashFlowsFromUsedInOperatingActivities><e:CashFlowsFromUsedInOperatingActivities contextRef="c17" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">24949280</e:CashFlowsFromUsedInOperatingActivities><e:PurchaseOfPropertyPlantAndEquipmentClassifiedAsInvestingActivities contextRef="c11" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">-4677690</e:PurchaseOfPropertyPlantAndEquipmentClassifiedAsInvestingActivities><e:PurchaseOfPropertyPlantAndEquipmentClassifiedAsInvestingActivities contextRef="c17" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">-3193567</e:PurchaseOfPropertyPlantAndEquipmentClassifiedAsInvestingActivities><e:PurchaseOfInvestments contextRef="c11" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">-21873287</e:PurchaseOfInvestments><e:PurchaseOfInvestments contextRef="c17" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">-240000</e:PurchaseOfInvestments><e:ProceedsFromSalesOfPropertyPlantAndEquipmentClassifiedAsInvestingActivities contextRef="c11" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">7913980</e:ProceedsFromSalesOfPropertyPlantAndEquipmentClassifiedAsInvestingActivities><e:ProceedsFromSalesOfPropertyPlantAndEquipmentClassifiedAsInvestingActivities contextRef="c17" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">202565</e:ProceedsFromSalesOfPropertyPlantAndEquipmentClassifiedAsInvestingActivities><e:SaleOfInvestments contextRef="c11" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">14958126</e:SaleOfInvestments><e:SaleOfInvestments contextRef="c17" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">17221314</e:SaleOfInvestments><e:Repayments contextRef="c11" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">110460954</e:Repayments><e:Repayments contextRef="c17" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">0</e:Repayments><e:ReceivedDividendsFromAssociates contextRef="c11" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">12470000</e:ReceivedDividendsFromAssociates><e:ReceivedDividendsFromAssociates contextRef="c17" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">0</e:ReceivedDividendsFromAssociates><e:OtherCashFlowsFromUsedInInvestingActivities contextRef="c11" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">99357</e:OtherCashFlowsFromUsedInInvestingActivities><e:OtherCashFlowsFromUsedInInvestingActivities contextRef="c17" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">5772057</e:OtherCashFlowsFromUsedInInvestingActivities><e:CashFlowsFromUsedInInvestingActivities contextRef="c11" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">119351440</e:CashFlowsFromUsedInInvestingActivities><e:CashFlowsFromUsedInInvestingActivities contextRef="c17" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">19762369</e:CashFlowsFromUsedInInvestingActivities><e:RepaymentsOfLongtermLiabilitiesClassifiedAsFinancingActivities contextRef="c11" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">-6340436</e:RepaymentsOfLongtermLiabilitiesClassifiedAsFinancingActivities><e:RepaymentsOfLongtermLiabilitiesClassifiedAsFinancingActivities contextRef="c17" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">-3897225</e:RepaymentsOfLongtermLiabilitiesClassifiedAsFinancingActivities><e:RepaymentOfDebtToCreditInstitutions contextRef="c11" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">-33073156</e:RepaymentOfDebtToCreditInstitutions><e:RepaymentOfDebtToCreditInstitutions contextRef="c17" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">-43633935</e:RepaymentOfDebtToCreditInstitutions><e:RaisingOfLongtermDebt contextRef="c11" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">164130</e:RaisingOfLongtermDebt><e:RaisingOfLongtermDebt contextRef="c17" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">316947</e:RaisingOfLongtermDebt><e:CashFlowsFromUsedInFinancingActivities contextRef="c11" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">-39249462</e:CashFlowsFromUsedInFinancingActivities><e:CashFlowsFromUsedInFinancingActivities contextRef="c17" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">-47214213</e:CashFlowsFromUsedInFinancingActivities><e:NetIncreaseDecreaseInCashAndCashEquivalents contextRef="c11" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">98395329</e:NetIncreaseDecreaseInCashAndCashEquivalents><e:NetIncreaseDecreaseInCashAndCashEquivalents contextRef="c17" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">-2502564</e:NetIncreaseDecreaseInCashAndCashEquivalents><e:CashAndCashEquivalentsConcerningCashflowStatement contextRef="c289" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">7352867</e:CashAndCashEquivalentsConcerningCashflowStatement><e:CashAndCashEquivalentsConcerningCashflowStatement contextRef="c290" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">9855431</e:CashAndCashEquivalentsConcerningCashflowStatement><e:CashAndCashEquivalentsConcerningCashflowStatement contextRef="c75" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">105748196</e:CashAndCashEquivalentsConcerningCashflowStatement><e:CashAndCashEquivalentsConcerningCashflowStatement contextRef="c74" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">7352867</e:CashAndCashEquivalentsConcerningCashflowStatement><e:CashAndCashEquivalents contextRef="c75" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">105748196</e:CashAndCashEquivalents><e:CashAndCashEquivalents contextRef="c74" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">7352867</e:CashAndCashEquivalents><e:DisclosureOfEmployeeBenefitsExpense contextRef="c11" xml:lang="da">
</e:DisclosureOfEmployeeBenefitsExpense><e:DisclosureOfEmployeeBenefitsExpense contextRef="c11" xml:lang="en">
</e:DisclosureOfEmployeeBenefitsExpense><e:WagesAndSalaries contextRef="c11" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">3688735</e:WagesAndSalaries><e:WagesAndSalaries contextRef="c17" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">2590858</e:WagesAndSalaries><e:PostemploymentBenefitExpense contextRef="c11" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">91306</e:PostemploymentBenefitExpense><e:PostemploymentBenefitExpense contextRef="c17" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">93310</e:PostemploymentBenefitExpense><e:SocialSecurityContributions contextRef="c11" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">27130</e:SocialSecurityContributions><e:SocialSecurityContributions contextRef="c17" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">26182</e:SocialSecurityContributions><e:EmployeeBenefitsExpense contextRef="c11" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">3807171</e:EmployeeBenefitsExpense><e:EmployeeBenefitsExpense contextRef="c17" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">2710350</e:EmployeeBenefitsExpense><e:AverageNumberOfEmployees contextRef="c11" unitRef="u4" decimals="INF">6</e:AverageNumberOfEmployees><e:AverageNumberOfEmployees contextRef="c17" unitRef="u4" decimals="INF">5</e:AverageNumberOfEmployees><e:InformationOnRemunerationOfManagementCategoriesAndSpecialIncentiveProgrammes contextRef="c11" xml:lang="da">Ifølge årsregnskabslovens § 98 B stk. 3 er vederlaget til direktionen udeladt.</e:InformationOnRemunerationOfManagementCategoriesAndSpecialIncentiveProgrammes><e:InformationOnRemunerationOfManagementCategoriesAndSpecialIncentiveProgrammes contextRef="c11" xml:lang="en">According to section 98 B(3) of the Danish Financial Statements Act, renumeration to the Executive Board has not been disclosed.</e:InformationOnRemunerationOfManagementCategoriesAndSpecialIncentiveProgrammes><e:DepreciationOfPropertyPlantAndEquipment contextRef="c11" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">839434</e:DepreciationOfPropertyPlantAndEquipment><e:DepreciationOfPropertyPlantAndEquipment contextRef="c17" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">773552</e:DepreciationOfPropertyPlantAndEquipment><e:ImpairmentLossesOfPropertyPlantAndEquipment contextRef="c11" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">537440</e:ImpairmentLossesOfPropertyPlantAndEquipment><e:ImpairmentLossesOfPropertyPlantAndEquipment contextRef="c17" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">0</e:ImpairmentLossesOfPropertyPlantAndEquipment><e:ProfitLossOnRealisations contextRef="c11" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">5775</e:ProfitLossOnRealisations><e:ProfitLossOnRealisations contextRef="c17" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">0</e:ProfitLossOnRealisations><e:DepreciationAmortisationExpenseAndImpairmentLossesOfPropertyPlantAndEquipmentAndIntangibleAssetsRecognisedInProfitOrLoss contextRef="c11" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">1382649</e:DepreciationAmortisationExpenseAndImpairmentLossesOfPropertyPlantAndEquipmentAndIntangibleAssetsRecognisedInProfitOrLoss><e:DepreciationAmortisationExpenseAndImpairmentLossesOfPropertyPlantAndEquipmentAndIntangibleAssetsRecognisedInProfitOrLoss contextRef="c17" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">773552</e:DepreciationAmortisationExpenseAndImpairmentLossesOfPropertyPlantAndEquipmentAndIntangibleAssetsRecognisedInProfitOrLoss><e:GainsLossesFromCurrentValueAdjustmentsOfInvestmentProperty contextRef="c11" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">8405695</e:GainsLossesFromCurrentValueAdjustmentsOfInvestmentProperty><e:GainsLossesFromCurrentValueAdjustmentsOfInvestmentProperty contextRef="c17" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">36079943</e:GainsLossesFromCurrentValueAdjustmentsOfInvestmentProperty><e:InterestIncomeFromGroupEnterprises contextRef="c11" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">0</e:InterestIncomeFromGroupEnterprises><e:InterestIncomeFromGroupEnterprises contextRef="c17" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">0</e:InterestIncomeFromGroupEnterprises><e:InterestIncomeFromAssociates contextRef="c11" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">0</e:InterestIncomeFromAssociates><e:InterestIncomeFromAssociates contextRef="c17" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">884060</e:InterestIncomeFromAssociates><e:OtherInterestIncome contextRef="c11" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">57804633</e:OtherInterestIncome><e:OtherInterestIncome contextRef="c17" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">49302223</e:OtherInterestIncome><e:ExchangeRateAdjustmentsOtherFinanceIncome contextRef="c11" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">232073</e:ExchangeRateAdjustmentsOtherFinanceIncome><e:ExchangeRateAdjustmentsOtherFinanceIncome contextRef="c17" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">0</e:ExchangeRateAdjustmentsOtherFinanceIncome><e:ExchangeRateProfit contextRef="c11" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">5005</e:ExchangeRateProfit><e:ExchangeRateProfit contextRef="c17" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">0</e:ExchangeRateProfit><e:OtherFinanceIncome contextRef="c11" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">58041711</e:OtherFinanceIncome><e:OtherFinanceIncome contextRef="c17" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">50186283</e:OtherFinanceIncome><e:ImpairmentOfFinancialAssets contextRef="c11" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">190000</e:ImpairmentOfFinancialAssets><e:ImpairmentOfFinancialAssets contextRef="c17" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">0</e:ImpairmentOfFinancialAssets><e:InterestExpenseAssignedToGroupEnterprises contextRef="c11" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">0</e:InterestExpenseAssignedToGroupEnterprises><e:InterestExpenseAssignedToGroupEnterprises contextRef="c17" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">0</e:InterestExpenseAssignedToGroupEnterprises><e:OtherInterestExpenses contextRef="c11" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">4569316</e:OtherInterestExpenses><e:OtherInterestExpenses contextRef="c17" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">15423557</e:OtherInterestExpenses><e:ExchangeRateLoss contextRef="c11" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">0</e:ExchangeRateLoss><e:ExchangeRateLoss contextRef="c17" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">278371</e:ExchangeRateLoss><e:OtherFinanceExpenses contextRef="c11" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">4759316</e:OtherFinanceExpenses><e:OtherFinanceExpenses contextRef="c17" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">15701928</e:OtherFinanceExpenses><e:CurrentTaxExpense contextRef="c11" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">15072517</e:CurrentTaxExpense><e:CurrentTaxExpense contextRef="c17" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">4496831</e:CurrentTaxExpense><e:AdjustmentsForDeferredTax contextRef="c11" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">926791</e:AdjustmentsForDeferredTax><e:AdjustmentsForDeferredTax contextRef="c17" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">9100827</e:AdjustmentsForDeferredTax><e:AdjustmentsForCurrentTaxOfPriorPeriod contextRef="c11" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">53954</e:AdjustmentsForCurrentTaxOfPriorPeriod><e:AdjustmentsForCurrentTaxOfPriorPeriod contextRef="c17" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">-445758</e:AdjustmentsForCurrentTaxOfPriorPeriod><e:ProfitLoss contextRef="c72" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">79724516</e:ProfitLoss><e:ProfitLoss contextRef="c73" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">68925315</e:ProfitLoss><e:PropertyPlantAndEquipmentGross contextRef="c369" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">239210460</e:PropertyPlantAndEquipmentGross><e:AdditionsToPropertyPlantAndEquipment contextRef="c370" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">4677690</e:AdditionsToPropertyPlantAndEquipment><e:DisposalsOfPropertyPlantAndEquipment contextRef="c370" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">-2223633</e:DisposalsOfPropertyPlantAndEquipment><e:PropertyPlantAndEquipmentGross contextRef="c371" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">241664517</e:PropertyPlantAndEquipmentGross><e:AccumulatedRevaluationOfPropertyPlantAndEquipment contextRef="c369" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">110724546</e:AccumulatedRevaluationOfPropertyPlantAndEquipment><e:RevaluationsOfPropertyPlantAndEquipment contextRef="c370" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">8405695</e:RevaluationsOfPropertyPlantAndEquipment><e:ReversalsOfRevaluationsOfPropertyPlantAndEquipmentFromPreviousPeriods contextRef="c370" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">-5046427</e:ReversalsOfRevaluationsOfPropertyPlantAndEquipmentFromPreviousPeriods><e:AccumulatedRevaluationOfPropertyPlantAndEquipment contextRef="c371" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">114083814</e:AccumulatedRevaluationOfPropertyPlantAndEquipment><e:PropertyPlantAndEquipment contextRef="c371" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">355748331</e:PropertyPlantAndEquipment><e:DisclosureOfAssumptionsOnCalculationMethodOfFairValueForAssetsAndLiabilities contextRef="c11" xml:lang="da">
Forudsætninger ved opgørelse af dagsværdi af investeringsejendommene    Tekster i afsnittet kan rettes via 'Rediger'   

Dagsværdien for investeringsejendomme er for hver enkel ejendom opgjort ved anvendelse af en afkastbaseret model, hvor der tages udgangspunkt i ejendommens driftsbudget og pengestrømme for det kommende år. Pengestrømmene fra den enkelte ejendom danner sammen med individuelt fastsatte afkastkrav basis for værdiansættelsen tillige med hensyntagen til tomgang og forventede investeringer mv. De anvendte afkastkrav er pr. 31. december 2017 fastsat til 2,0 % - 8,5 %. .

Følsomhed ved opgørelse af dagsværdi af investeringsejendommene    Tekster i afsnittet kan rettes via 'Rediger'   

Ved markedsværdi vurderingen pr. 31. december 2017er der anvendt et individuelt fastsat afkastkrav i intervallet 2,0 % - 8,5 %. Det kan opgøres til 7,1 %.

Ændringer i skøn over afkastkrav for investeringsejendomme vil påvirke den indregnede værdi af investeringsejendomme i balancen samt værdireguleringen i resultatopgørelsen.</e:DisclosureOfAssumptionsOnCalculationMethodOfFairValueForAssetsAndLiabilities><e:DisclosureOfAssumptionsOnCalculationMethodOfFairValueForAssetsAndLiabilities contextRef="c11" xml:lang="en">
Assumptions underlying the determination of fair value of investment properties

The present value of investment properties is calculated for each property using a return-based model, based on the property's operating budget and cash flow for the coming year. The cash flows from the individual property together with individually defined return requirements provide a basis for valuation, taking into account also idle and expected investments etc. The applied return requirements are per 31 December 2017 set at 2,0% - 8,5%.

Sensitivity in determination of fair value of investment properties

An  in the range of 2,0%-8,5% has been applied in the market value assessment at31 december 2017 The is determined at 7,1%.

Changes in estimated required rate of return for investment properties will affect the value of investment properties recognised in the balance sheet as well as value adjustments carried in the income statement.</e:DisclosureOfAssumptionsOnCalculationMethodOfFairValueForAssetsAndLiabilities><e:PropertyPlantAndEquipmentGross contextRef="c202" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">4037440</e:PropertyPlantAndEquipmentGross><e:PropertyPlantAndEquipmentGross contextRef="c211" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">5457034</e:PropertyPlantAndEquipmentGross><e:DisposalsOfPropertyPlantAndEquipment contextRef="c206" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">0</e:DisposalsOfPropertyPlantAndEquipment><e:DisposalsOfPropertyPlantAndEquipment contextRef="c212" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">-383650</e:DisposalsOfPropertyPlantAndEquipment><e:PropertyPlantAndEquipmentGross contextRef="c207" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">4037440</e:PropertyPlantAndEquipmentGross><e:PropertyPlantAndEquipmentGross contextRef="c213" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">5073384</e:PropertyPlantAndEquipmentGross><e:AccumulatedImpairmentLossesAndDepreciationOfPropertyPlantAndEquipment contextRef="c202" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">0</e:AccumulatedImpairmentLossesAndDepreciationOfPropertyPlantAndEquipment><e:AccumulatedImpairmentLossesAndDepreciationOfPropertyPlantAndEquipment contextRef="c211" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">2398291</e:AccumulatedImpairmentLossesAndDepreciationOfPropertyPlantAndEquipment><e:ImpairmentLossesOfPropertyPlantAndEquipment contextRef="c206" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">537440</e:ImpairmentLossesOfPropertyPlantAndEquipment><e:ImpairmentLossesOfPropertyPlantAndEquipment contextRef="c212" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">0</e:ImpairmentLossesOfPropertyPlantAndEquipment><e:DepreciationOfPropertyPlantAndEquipment contextRef="c206" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">0</e:DepreciationOfPropertyPlantAndEquipment><e:DepreciationOfPropertyPlantAndEquipment contextRef="c212" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">773004</e:DepreciationOfPropertyPlantAndEquipment><e:ReversalsOfImpairmentLossesAndDepreciationOfDisposedPropertyPlantAndEquipment contextRef="c206" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">0</e:ReversalsOfImpairmentLossesAndDepreciationOfDisposedPropertyPlantAndEquipment><e:ReversalsOfImpairmentLossesAndDepreciationOfDisposedPropertyPlantAndEquipment contextRef="c212" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">-312875</e:ReversalsOfImpairmentLossesAndDepreciationOfDisposedPropertyPlantAndEquipment><e:AccumulatedImpairmentLossesAndDepreciationOfPropertyPlantAndEquipment contextRef="c207" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">537440</e:AccumulatedImpairmentLossesAndDepreciationOfPropertyPlantAndEquipment><e:AccumulatedImpairmentLossesAndDepreciationOfPropertyPlantAndEquipment contextRef="c213" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">-2858420</e:AccumulatedImpairmentLossesAndDepreciationOfPropertyPlantAndEquipment><e:PropertyPlantAndEquipment contextRef="c207" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">3500000</e:PropertyPlantAndEquipment><e:PropertyPlantAndEquipment contextRef="c213" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">2214964</e:PropertyPlantAndEquipment><e:PropertyPlantAndEquipment contextRef="c1348" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">0</e:PropertyPlantAndEquipment><e:PropertyPlantAndEquipment contextRef="c1351" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">1504680</e:PropertyPlantAndEquipment><e:RelatedEntityName contextRef="c456">Anpartsselskabet af 1. september 1984</e:RelatedEntityName><e:RelatedEntityRegisteredOffice contextRef="c456">Gentofte</e:RelatedEntityRegisteredOffice><e:ShareHeldByEntityOrConsolidatedEnterprisesInRelatedEntity contextRef="c457" unitRef="u4" decimals="1">100</e:ShareHeldByEntityOrConsolidatedEnterprisesInRelatedEntity><e:Equity contextRef="c457" unitRef="u2" decimals="INF">159334788</e:Equity><e:ProfitLoss contextRef="c456" unitRef="u2" decimals="INF">6426470</e:ProfitLoss><e:RelatedEntityName contextRef="c737">ApS Nora Bio</e:RelatedEntityName><e:RelatedEntityRegisteredOffice contextRef="c737">Gentofte</e:RelatedEntityRegisteredOffice><e:ShareHeldByEntityOrConsolidatedEnterprisesInRelatedEntity contextRef="c756" unitRef="u4" decimals="1">100</e:ShareHeldByEntityOrConsolidatedEnterprisesInRelatedEntity><e:Equity contextRef="c756" unitRef="u2" decimals="INF">15691421</e:Equity><e:ProfitLoss contextRef="c737" unitRef="u2" decimals="INF">2517179</e:ProfitLoss><e:RelatedEntityName contextRef="c738">ApS Investeringsselskabet af 1.10.1979</e:RelatedEntityName><e:RelatedEntityRegisteredOffice contextRef="c738">Gentofte</e:RelatedEntityRegisteredOffice><e:ShareHeldByEntityOrConsolidatedEnterprisesInRelatedEntity contextRef="c757" unitRef="u4" decimals="1">100</e:ShareHeldByEntityOrConsolidatedEnterprisesInRelatedEntity><e:Equity contextRef="c757" unitRef="u2" decimals="INF">25101063</e:Equity><e:ProfitLoss contextRef="c738" unitRef="u2" decimals="INF">5650072</e:ProfitLoss><e:RelatedEntityName contextRef="c739">ApS Freden-Invest</e:RelatedEntityName><e:RelatedEntityRegisteredOffice contextRef="c739">Gentofte</e:RelatedEntityRegisteredOffice><e:ShareHeldByEntityOrConsolidatedEnterprisesInRelatedEntity contextRef="c758" unitRef="u4" decimals="1">100</e:ShareHeldByEntityOrConsolidatedEnterprisesInRelatedEntity><e:Equity contextRef="c758" unitRef="u2" decimals="INF">19113662</e:Equity><e:ProfitLoss contextRef="c739" unitRef="u2" decimals="INF">3424658</e:ProfitLoss><e:RelatedEntityName contextRef="c740">ApS Bregnerødvej</e:RelatedEntityName><e:RelatedEntityRegisteredOffice contextRef="c740">Gentofte</e:RelatedEntityRegisteredOffice><e:ShareHeldByEntityOrConsolidatedEnterprisesInRelatedEntity contextRef="c759" unitRef="u4" decimals="1">100</e:ShareHeldByEntityOrConsolidatedEnterprisesInRelatedEntity><e:Equity contextRef="c759" unitRef="u2" decimals="INF">1969848</e:Equity><e:ProfitLoss contextRef="c740" unitRef="u2" decimals="INF">-1858776</e:ProfitLoss><e:RelatedEntityName contextRef="c741">ApS Toftebakken 5 Birkerød</e:RelatedEntityName><e:RelatedEntityRegisteredOffice contextRef="c741">Gentofte</e:RelatedEntityRegisteredOffice><e:ShareHeldByEntityOrConsolidatedEnterprisesInRelatedEntity contextRef="c760" unitRef="u4" decimals="1">100</e:ShareHeldByEntityOrConsolidatedEnterprisesInRelatedEntity><e:Equity contextRef="c760" unitRef="u2" decimals="INF">3123769</e:Equity><e:ProfitLoss contextRef="c741" unitRef="u2" decimals="INF">84237</e:ProfitLoss><e:RelatedEntityName contextRef="c742">ApS af 12.3.1914</e:RelatedEntityName><e:RelatedEntityRegisteredOffice contextRef="c742">Gentofte</e:RelatedEntityRegisteredOffice><e:ShareHeldByEntityOrConsolidatedEnterprisesInRelatedEntity contextRef="c761" unitRef="u4" decimals="1">100</e:ShareHeldByEntityOrConsolidatedEnterprisesInRelatedEntity><e:Equity contextRef="c761" unitRef="u2" decimals="INF">34377113</e:Equity><e:ProfitLoss contextRef="c742" unitRef="u2" decimals="INF">2630016</e:ProfitLoss><e:RelatedEntityName contextRef="c743">ApS Bretagnevej 24 Hornbæk</e:RelatedEntityName><e:RelatedEntityRegisteredOffice contextRef="c743">Furesø</e:RelatedEntityRegisteredOffice><e:ShareHeldByEntityOrConsolidatedEnterprisesInRelatedEntity contextRef="c762" unitRef="u4" decimals="1">100</e:ShareHeldByEntityOrConsolidatedEnterprisesInRelatedEntity><e:Equity contextRef="c762" unitRef="u2" decimals="INF">59354</e:Equity><e:ProfitLoss contextRef="c743" unitRef="u2" decimals="INF">-559201</e:ProfitLoss><e:RelatedEntityName contextRef="c744">ApS Slesvig MC</e:RelatedEntityName><e:RelatedEntityRegisteredOffice contextRef="c744">Gentofte</e:RelatedEntityRegisteredOffice><e:ShareHeldByEntityOrConsolidatedEnterprisesInRelatedEntity contextRef="c763" unitRef="u4" decimals="1">100</e:ShareHeldByEntityOrConsolidatedEnterprisesInRelatedEntity><e:Equity contextRef="c763" unitRef="u2" decimals="INF">3678547</e:Equity><e:ProfitLoss contextRef="c744" unitRef="u2" decimals="INF">52401</e:ProfitLoss><e:RelatedEntityName contextRef="c745">ApS Kommandantens Gaard MC i likvidation</e:RelatedEntityName><e:RelatedEntityRegisteredOffice contextRef="c745">København</e:RelatedEntityRegisteredOffice><e:ShareHeldByEntityOrConsolidatedEnterprisesInRelatedEntity contextRef="c764" unitRef="u4" decimals="1">100</e:ShareHeldByEntityOrConsolidatedEnterprisesInRelatedEntity><e:Equity contextRef="c764" unitRef="u2" decimals="INF">556671</e:Equity><e:ProfitLoss contextRef="c745" unitRef="u2" decimals="INF">119775</e:ProfitLoss><e:RelatedEntityName contextRef="c746">Den jyske Cobrasamling ApS</e:RelatedEntityName><e:RelatedEntityRegisteredOffice contextRef="c746">Gentofte</e:RelatedEntityRegisteredOffice><e:ShareHeldByEntityOrConsolidatedEnterprisesInRelatedEntity contextRef="c765" unitRef="u4" decimals="1">100</e:ShareHeldByEntityOrConsolidatedEnterprisesInRelatedEntity><e:Equity contextRef="c765" unitRef="u2" decimals="INF">-7374</e:Equity><e:ProfitLoss contextRef="c746" unitRef="u2" decimals="INF">-7374</e:ProfitLoss><e:RelatedEntityName contextRef="c747">ApS MABA Invest</e:RelatedEntityName><e:RelatedEntityRegisteredOffice contextRef="c747">Gentofte</e:RelatedEntityRegisteredOffice><e:ShareHeldByEntityOrConsolidatedEnterprisesInRelatedEntity contextRef="c766" unitRef="u4" decimals="1">100</e:ShareHeldByEntityOrConsolidatedEnterprisesInRelatedEntity><e:Equity contextRef="c766" unitRef="u2" decimals="INF">123736</e:Equity><e:ProfitLoss contextRef="c747" unitRef="u2" decimals="INF">80442</e:ProfitLoss><e:RelatedEntityName contextRef="c748">I/S Nora Byggeselskab</e:RelatedEntityName><e:RelatedEntityRegisteredOffice contextRef="c748">Gentofte</e:RelatedEntityRegisteredOffice><e:ShareHeldByEntityOrConsolidatedEnterprisesInRelatedEntity contextRef="c767" unitRef="u4" decimals="1">100</e:ShareHeldByEntityOrConsolidatedEnterprisesInRelatedEntity><e:Equity contextRef="c767" unitRef="u2" decimals="INF">41852426</e:Equity><e:ProfitLoss contextRef="c748" unitRef="u2" decimals="INF">3264911</e:ProfitLoss><e:RelatedEntityName contextRef="c749">I/S Sct. Bendtsgade 8</e:RelatedEntityName><e:RelatedEntityRegisteredOffice contextRef="c749">Gentofte</e:RelatedEntityRegisteredOffice><e:ShareHeldByEntityOrConsolidatedEnterprisesInRelatedEntity contextRef="c768" unitRef="u4" decimals="1">50</e:ShareHeldByEntityOrConsolidatedEnterprisesInRelatedEntity><e:Equity contextRef="c768" unitRef="u2" decimals="INF">5215790</e:Equity><e:ProfitLoss contextRef="c749" unitRef="u2" decimals="INF">302875</e:ProfitLoss><e:InvestmentsGross contextRef="c82" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">66728457</e:InvestmentsGross><e:InvestmentsGross contextRef="c85" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">66703457</e:InvestmentsGross><e:InvestmentsGross contextRef="c82" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">79326815</e:InvestmentsGross><e:InvestmentsGross contextRef="c85" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">79326815</e:InvestmentsGross><e:AdditionsToInvestments contextRef="c83" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">1275000</e:AdditionsToInvestments><e:AdditionsToInvestments contextRef="c86" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">25000</e:AdditionsToInvestments><e:AdditionsToInvestments contextRef="c83" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">1275000</e:AdditionsToInvestments><e:AdditionsToInvestments contextRef="c86" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">0</e:AdditionsToInvestments><e:DisposalsOfInvestments contextRef="c83" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">-483750</e:DisposalsOfInvestments><e:DisposalsOfInvestments contextRef="c86" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">0</e:DisposalsOfInvestments><e:DisposalsOfInvestments contextRef="c83" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">-483750</e:DisposalsOfInvestments><e:DisposalsOfInvestments contextRef="c86" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">0</e:DisposalsOfInvestments><e:InvestmentsGross contextRef="c84" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">67519707</e:InvestmentsGross><e:InvestmentsGross contextRef="c87" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">66728457</e:InvestmentsGross><e:InvestmentsGross contextRef="c84" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">80118065</e:InvestmentsGross><e:InvestmentsGross contextRef="c87" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">79326815</e:InvestmentsGross><e:AccumulatedRevaluationsOfInvestments contextRef="c82" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">-9640408</e:AccumulatedRevaluationsOfInvestments><e:AccumulatedRevaluationsOfInvestments contextRef="c85" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">-8095927</e:AccumulatedRevaluationsOfInvestments><e:AccumulatedRevaluationsOfInvestments contextRef="c82" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">-3021112</e:AccumulatedRevaluationsOfInvestments><e:AccumulatedRevaluationsOfInvestments contextRef="c85" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">-5228775</e:AccumulatedRevaluationsOfInvestments><e:OtherAdjustmentsRelatedToInvestments contextRef="c83" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">0</e:OtherAdjustmentsRelatedToInvestments><e:OtherAdjustmentsRelatedToInvestments contextRef="c86" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">-930300</e:OtherAdjustmentsRelatedToInvestments><e:OtherAdjustmentsRelatedToInvestments contextRef="c83" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">0</e:OtherAdjustmentsRelatedToInvestments><e:OtherAdjustmentsRelatedToInvestments contextRef="c86" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">-930300</e:OtherAdjustmentsRelatedToInvestments><e:IncreaseDecreaseOfRevaluationsAndDevaluationsOfInvestmentsThroughNetExchangeDifferences contextRef="c83" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">87863</e:IncreaseDecreaseOfRevaluationsAndDevaluationsOfInvestmentsThroughNetExchangeDifferences><e:IncreaseDecreaseOfRevaluationsAndDevaluationsOfInvestmentsThroughNetExchangeDifferences contextRef="c86" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">-163898</e:IncreaseDecreaseOfRevaluationsAndDevaluationsOfInvestmentsThroughNetExchangeDifferences><e:IncreaseDecreaseOfRevaluationsAndDevaluationsOfInvestmentsThroughNetExchangeDifferences contextRef="c83" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">87863</e:IncreaseDecreaseOfRevaluationsAndDevaluationsOfInvestmentsThroughNetExchangeDifferences><e:IncreaseDecreaseOfRevaluationsAndDevaluationsOfInvestmentsThroughNetExchangeDifferences contextRef="c86" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">-163898</e:IncreaseDecreaseOfRevaluationsAndDevaluationsOfInvestmentsThroughNetExchangeDifferences><e:ProfitLossRelatedToInvestments contextRef="c83" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">20019541</e:ProfitLossRelatedToInvestments><e:ProfitLossRelatedToInvestments contextRef="c86" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">644</e:ProfitLossRelatedToInvestments><e:ProfitLossRelatedToInvestments contextRef="c83" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">21413859</e:ProfitLossRelatedToInvestments><e:ProfitLossRelatedToInvestments contextRef="c86" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">3301861</e:ProfitLossRelatedToInvestments><e:DividendIncomeRelatedToInvestments contextRef="c83" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">-12470000</e:DividendIncomeRelatedToInvestments><e:DividendIncomeRelatedToInvestments contextRef="c86" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">0</e:DividendIncomeRelatedToInvestments><e:DividendIncomeRelatedToInvestments contextRef="c83" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">-12470000</e:DividendIncomeRelatedToInvestments><e:DividendIncomeRelatedToInvestments contextRef="c86" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">0</e:DividendIncomeRelatedToInvestments><e:AccumulatedRevaluationsOfInvestments contextRef="c84" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">-2003004</e:AccumulatedRevaluationsOfInvestments><e:AccumulatedRevaluationsOfInvestments contextRef="c87" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">-9189481</e:AccumulatedRevaluationsOfInvestments><e:AccumulatedRevaluationsOfInvestments contextRef="c84" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">6010610</e:AccumulatedRevaluationsOfInvestments><e:AccumulatedRevaluationsOfInvestments contextRef="c87" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">-3021112</e:AccumulatedRevaluationsOfInvestments><e:LongtermInvestmentsAndReceivables contextRef="c84" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">65516703</e:LongtermInvestmentsAndReceivables><e:LongtermInvestmentsAndReceivables contextRef="c87" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">57538976</e:LongtermInvestmentsAndReceivables><e:LongtermInvestmentsAndReceivables contextRef="c84" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">86128675</e:LongtermInvestmentsAndReceivables><e:LongtermInvestmentsAndReceivables contextRef="c87" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">76305703</e:LongtermInvestmentsAndReceivables><e:RelatedEntityName contextRef="c675">ApS KG Bolig</e:RelatedEntityName><e:RelatedEntityRegisteredOffice contextRef="c675">Gentofte</e:RelatedEntityRegisteredOffice><e:ShareHeldByEntityOrConsolidatedEnterprisesInRelatedEntity contextRef="c676" unitRef="u4" decimals="1">50</e:ShareHeldByEntityOrConsolidatedEnterprisesInRelatedEntity><e:Equity contextRef="c676" unitRef="u2" decimals="INF">16451655</e:Equity><e:ProfitLoss contextRef="c675" unitRef="u2" decimals="INF">2102412</e:ProfitLoss><e:RelatedEntityName contextRef="c1548">EEA Renewables A/S</e:RelatedEntityName><e:RelatedEntityRegisteredOffice contextRef="c1548">Gladsaxe</e:RelatedEntityRegisteredOffice><e:ShareHeldByEntityOrConsolidatedEnterprisesInRelatedEntity contextRef="c1567" unitRef="u4" decimals="1">50</e:ShareHeldByEntityOrConsolidatedEnterprisesInRelatedEntity><e:Equity contextRef="c1567" unitRef="u2" decimals="INF">7996552</e:Equity><e:ProfitLoss contextRef="c1548" unitRef="u2" decimals="INF">8650050</e:ProfitLoss><e:RelatedEntityName contextRef="c1549">EEA Stormy ApS</e:RelatedEntityName><e:RelatedEntityRegisteredOffice contextRef="c1549">Gladsaxe</e:RelatedEntityRegisteredOffice><e:ShareHeldByEntityOrConsolidatedEnterprisesInRelatedEntity contextRef="c1568" unitRef="u4" decimals="1">50</e:ShareHeldByEntityOrConsolidatedEnterprisesInRelatedEntity><e:Equity contextRef="c1568" unitRef="u2" decimals="INF">51930508</e:Equity><e:ProfitLoss contextRef="c1549" unitRef="u2" decimals="INF">46440325</e:ProfitLoss><e:RelatedEntityName contextRef="c1550">EEA Swepol A/S</e:RelatedEntityName><e:RelatedEntityRegisteredOffice contextRef="c1550">Gladsaxe</e:RelatedEntityRegisteredOffice><e:ShareHeldByEntityOrConsolidatedEnterprisesInRelatedEntity contextRef="c1569" unitRef="u4" decimals="1">50</e:ShareHeldByEntityOrConsolidatedEnterprisesInRelatedEntity><e:Equity contextRef="c1569" unitRef="u2" decimals="INF">3440832</e:Equity><e:ProfitLoss contextRef="c1550" unitRef="u2" decimals="INF">-13394364</e:ProfitLoss><e:RelatedEntityName contextRef="c1551">Rosen Holbæk ApS</e:RelatedEntityName><e:RelatedEntityRegisteredOffice contextRef="c1551">Holbæk</e:RelatedEntityRegisteredOffice><e:ShareHeldByEntityOrConsolidatedEnterprisesInRelatedEntity contextRef="c1570" unitRef="u4" decimals="1">50</e:ShareHeldByEntityOrConsolidatedEnterprisesInRelatedEntity><e:Equity contextRef="c1570" unitRef="u2" decimals="INF">18259636</e:Equity><e:ProfitLoss contextRef="c1551" unitRef="u2" decimals="INF">-739698</e:ProfitLoss><e:RelatedEntityName contextRef="c1552">Ejendomsselskabet JAMA ApS</e:RelatedEntityName><e:RelatedEntityRegisteredOffice contextRef="c1552">Gentofte</e:RelatedEntityRegisteredOffice><e:ShareHeldByEntityOrConsolidatedEnterprisesInRelatedEntity contextRef="c1571" unitRef="u4" decimals="1">0</e:ShareHeldByEntityOrConsolidatedEnterprisesInRelatedEntity><e:Equity contextRef="c1571" unitRef="u2" decimals="INF">186862</e:Equity><e:ProfitLoss contextRef="c1552" unitRef="u2" decimals="INF">136862</e:ProfitLoss><e:RelatedEntityName contextRef="c1553">EEA Verwaltung GmbH</e:RelatedEntityName><e:RelatedEntityRegisteredOffice contextRef="c1553">Breklund, Tyskland</e:RelatedEntityRegisteredOffice><e:ShareHeldByEntityOrConsolidatedEnterprisesInRelatedEntity contextRef="c1572" unitRef="u4" decimals="1">50</e:ShareHeldByEntityOrConsolidatedEnterprisesInRelatedEntity><e:Equity contextRef="c1572" unitRef="u2" decimals="INF">275217</e:Equity><e:ProfitLoss contextRef="c1553" unitRef="u2" decimals="INF">0</e:ProfitLoss><e:RelatedEntityName contextRef="c1554">Komplementar Mexico Ventures ApS</e:RelatedEntityName><e:RelatedEntityRegisteredOffice contextRef="c1554">Gladsaxe</e:RelatedEntityRegisteredOffice><e:ShareHeldByEntityOrConsolidatedEnterprisesInRelatedEntity contextRef="c1573" unitRef="u4" decimals="1">50</e:ShareHeldByEntityOrConsolidatedEnterprisesInRelatedEntity><e:Equity contextRef="c1573" unitRef="u2" decimals="INF">50000</e:Equity><e:ProfitLoss contextRef="c1554" unitRef="u2" decimals="INF">0</e:ProfitLoss><e:RelatedEntityName contextRef="c1555">Mexico Partnership P/S</e:RelatedEntityName><e:RelatedEntityRegisteredOffice contextRef="c1555">Gladsaxe</e:RelatedEntityRegisteredOffice><e:ShareHeldByEntityOrConsolidatedEnterprisesInRelatedEntity contextRef="c1574" unitRef="u4" decimals="1">50</e:ShareHeldByEntityOrConsolidatedEnterprisesInRelatedEntity><e:Equity contextRef="c1574" unitRef="u2" decimals="INF">500000</e:Equity><e:ProfitLoss contextRef="c1555" unitRef="u2" decimals="INF">0</e:ProfitLoss><e:RelatedEntityName contextRef="c1556">O+C Holding IVS</e:RelatedEntityName><e:RelatedEntityRegisteredOffice contextRef="c1556">København</e:RelatedEntityRegisteredOffice><e:ShareHeldByEntityOrConsolidatedEnterprisesInRelatedEntity contextRef="c1575" unitRef="u4" decimals="1">32</e:ShareHeldByEntityOrConsolidatedEnterprisesInRelatedEntity><e:Equity contextRef="c1575" unitRef="u2" decimals="INF">855474</e:Equity><e:ProfitLoss contextRef="c1556" unitRef="u2" decimals="INF">-79536</e:ProfitLoss><e:RelatedEntityName contextRef="c1557">EWF Eins Sieben GmbH &amp; Co. KG</e:RelatedEntityName><e:RelatedEntityRegisteredOffice contextRef="c1557">Breklum, Tyskland</e:RelatedEntityRegisteredOffice><e:ShareHeldByEntityOrConsolidatedEnterprisesInRelatedEntity contextRef="c1576" unitRef="u4" decimals="1">50</e:ShareHeldByEntityOrConsolidatedEnterprisesInRelatedEntity><e:Equity contextRef="c1576" unitRef="u2" decimals="INF">0</e:Equity><e:ProfitLoss contextRef="c1557" unitRef="u2" decimals="INF">0</e:ProfitLoss><e:RelatedEntityName contextRef="c1558">EWF Eins Acht GmbH &amp; Co. KG</e:RelatedEntityName><e:RelatedEntityRegisteredOffice contextRef="c1558">Breklum, Tyskland</e:RelatedEntityRegisteredOffice><e:ShareHeldByEntityOrConsolidatedEnterprisesInRelatedEntity contextRef="c1577" unitRef="u4" decimals="1">50</e:ShareHeldByEntityOrConsolidatedEnterprisesInRelatedEntity><e:Equity contextRef="c1577" unitRef="u2" decimals="INF">0</e:Equity><e:ProfitLoss contextRef="c1558" unitRef="u2" decimals="INF">0</e:ProfitLoss><e:RelatedEntityName contextRef="c1559">EWF Zwei Null GmbH &amp; Co. KG</e:RelatedEntityName><e:RelatedEntityRegisteredOffice contextRef="c1559">Breklum, Tyskland</e:RelatedEntityRegisteredOffice><e:ShareHeldByEntityOrConsolidatedEnterprisesInRelatedEntity contextRef="c1578" unitRef="u4" decimals="1">50</e:ShareHeldByEntityOrConsolidatedEnterprisesInRelatedEntity><e:Equity contextRef="c1578" unitRef="u2" decimals="INF">0</e:Equity><e:ProfitLoss contextRef="c1559" unitRef="u2" decimals="INF">0</e:ProfitLoss><e:RelatedEntityName contextRef="c1560">EWF Fünf Vier GmbH &amp; Co. KG</e:RelatedEntityName><e:RelatedEntityRegisteredOffice contextRef="c1560">Breklum Tyskland</e:RelatedEntityRegisteredOffice><e:ShareHeldByEntityOrConsolidatedEnterprisesInRelatedEntity contextRef="c1579" unitRef="u4" decimals="1">50</e:ShareHeldByEntityOrConsolidatedEnterprisesInRelatedEntity><e:Equity contextRef="c1579" unitRef="u2" decimals="INF">0</e:Equity><e:ProfitLoss contextRef="c1560" unitRef="u2" decimals="INF">0</e:ProfitLoss><e:RelatedEntityName contextRef="c1561">EWF Fünf Eins GmbH &amp; Co. KG</e:RelatedEntityName><e:RelatedEntityRegisteredOffice contextRef="c1561">Breklum, Tyskland</e:RelatedEntityRegisteredOffice><e:ShareHeldByEntityOrConsolidatedEnterprisesInRelatedEntity contextRef="c1580" unitRef="u4" decimals="1">25</e:ShareHeldByEntityOrConsolidatedEnterprisesInRelatedEntity><e:Equity contextRef="c1580" unitRef="u2" decimals="INF">0</e:Equity><e:ProfitLoss contextRef="c1561" unitRef="u2" decimals="INF">0</e:ProfitLoss><e:RelatedEntityName contextRef="c1562">WP Hellberge GmbH &amp; Co. KG</e:RelatedEntityName><e:RelatedEntityRegisteredOffice contextRef="c1562">Breklum, Tyskland</e:RelatedEntityRegisteredOffice><e:ShareHeldByEntityOrConsolidatedEnterprisesInRelatedEntity contextRef="c1581" unitRef="u4" decimals="1">50</e:ShareHeldByEntityOrConsolidatedEnterprisesInRelatedEntity><e:Equity contextRef="c1581" unitRef="u2" decimals="INF">0</e:Equity><e:ProfitLoss contextRef="c1562" unitRef="u2" decimals="INF">0</e:ProfitLoss><e:RelatedEntityName contextRef="c1563">EE Sieben Zwei GmbH &amp; Co. KG</e:RelatedEntityName><e:RelatedEntityRegisteredOffice contextRef="c1563">Breklum, Tyskland</e:RelatedEntityRegisteredOffice><e:ShareHeldByEntityOrConsolidatedEnterprisesInRelatedEntity contextRef="c1582" unitRef="u4" decimals="1">50</e:ShareHeldByEntityOrConsolidatedEnterprisesInRelatedEntity><e:Equity contextRef="c1582" unitRef="u2" decimals="INF">0</e:Equity><e:ProfitLoss contextRef="c1563" unitRef="u2" decimals="INF">0</e:ProfitLoss><e:RelatedEntityName contextRef="c1564">EE Sieben Drei GmbH &amp; Co. KG</e:RelatedEntityName><e:RelatedEntityRegisteredOffice contextRef="c1564">Breklum, Tyskland</e:RelatedEntityRegisteredOffice><e:ShareHeldByEntityOrConsolidatedEnterprisesInRelatedEntity contextRef="c1583" unitRef="u4" decimals="1">50</e:ShareHeldByEntityOrConsolidatedEnterprisesInRelatedEntity><e:Equity contextRef="c1583" unitRef="u2" decimals="INF">0</e:Equity><e:ProfitLoss contextRef="c1564" unitRef="u2" decimals="INF">0</e:ProfitLoss><e:InvestmentsGross contextRef="c357" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">22484060</e:InvestmentsGross><e:InvestmentsGross contextRef="c360" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">363239235</e:InvestmentsGross><e:DisposalsOfInvestmentsByDivisionAndSaleOfOtherCompany contextRef="c358" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">0</e:DisposalsOfInvestmentsByDivisionAndSaleOfOtherCompany><e:DisposalsOfInvestmentsByDivisionAndSaleOfOtherCompany contextRef="c361" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">4162068</e:DisposalsOfInvestmentsByDivisionAndSaleOfOtherCompany><e:AdditionsToInvestments contextRef="c358" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">0</e:AdditionsToInvestments><e:AdditionsToInvestments contextRef="c361" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">20598287</e:AdditionsToInvestments><e:DisposalsOfInvestments contextRef="c358" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">-2831369</e:DisposalsOfInvestments><e:DisposalsOfInvestments contextRef="c361" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">-15756855</e:DisposalsOfInvestments><e:InvestmentsGross contextRef="c359" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">19652691</e:InvestmentsGross><e:InvestmentsGross contextRef="c362" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">372242735</e:InvestmentsGross><e:AccumulatedRevaluationsOfInvestments contextRef="c357" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">0</e:AccumulatedRevaluationsOfInvestments><e:AccumulatedRevaluationsOfInvestments contextRef="c360" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">29444067</e:AccumulatedRevaluationsOfInvestments><e:RevaluationsOfInvestmentsOfTheYear contextRef="c358" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">0</e:RevaluationsOfInvestmentsOfTheYear><e:RevaluationsOfInvestmentsOfTheYear contextRef="c361" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">35461576</e:RevaluationsOfInvestmentsOfTheYear><e:ReversalsOfInvestmentsOfPriorYearsRevaluations contextRef="c358" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">0</e:ReversalsOfInvestmentsOfPriorYearsRevaluations><e:ReversalsOfInvestmentsOfPriorYearsRevaluations contextRef="c361" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">798729</e:ReversalsOfInvestmentsOfPriorYearsRevaluations><e:AccumulatedRevaluationsOfInvestments contextRef="c359" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">0</e:AccumulatedRevaluationsOfInvestments><e:AccumulatedRevaluationsOfInvestments contextRef="c362" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">65704372</e:AccumulatedRevaluationsOfInvestments><e:LongtermInvestmentsAndReceivables contextRef="c359" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">19652691</e:LongtermInvestmentsAndReceivables><e:LongtermInvestmentsAndReceivables contextRef="c362" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">437947107</e:LongtermInvestmentsAndReceivables><e:ExplanationOfPrepayments contextRef="c11" xml:lang="da">Periodeafgrænsningsposter udgøres af forudbetalte omkostninger vedrørende husleje, forsikringspræmier, abonnementer og renter samt reguleringer til dagsværdi for afledte finansielle instrumenter med positiv dagsværdi.</e:ExplanationOfPrepayments><e:ExplanationOfPrepayments contextRef="c11" xml:lang="en">Prepayments comprise prepaid expenses regarding rent, insurance premiums, subscriptions and interest as well as fair value adjustments of derivative financial instruments with a positive fair value.</e:ExplanationOfPrepayments><e:NumberOfIssuedShares contextRef="c226" unitRef="u1" decimals="INF">96257</e:NumberOfIssuedShares><e:DescriptionOfClassOfIssuedShares contextRef="c226">A</e:DescriptionOfClassOfIssuedShares><e:NominalValueOfIssuedShares contextRef="c226" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">96257</e:NominalValueOfIssuedShares><e:NumberOfIssuedShares contextRef="c227" unitRef="u1" decimals="INF">288780</e:NumberOfIssuedShares><e:DescriptionOfClassOfIssuedShares contextRef="c227">B</e:DescriptionOfClassOfIssuedShares><e:NominalValueOfIssuedShares contextRef="c227" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">288780</e:NominalValueOfIssuedShares><e:InformationOnChangesAsResultOfApplicationOfUnitingOfInterestsMethod contextRef="c11" xml:lang="da">Selskabet er med regnskabsmæssig virkning fra 1. januar 2017 fusioneret med sine 2 søsterselskaber Nyda-Finans ApS og ApS EGA-Administration. Der er foretaget tilpasning af sammenligningstal for 2016</e:InformationOnChangesAsResultOfApplicationOfUnitingOfInterestsMethod><e:InformationOnChangesAsResultOfApplicationOfUnitingOfInterestsMethod contextRef="c11" xml:lang="en">With financial effect from 1 January 2017 the company has merged with its two sister companies Nyda-Finans ApS and ApS EGA-Administration. Adjustment of comparative figures for 2016 has been made.</e:InformationOnChangesAsResultOfApplicationOfUnitingOfInterestsMethod><e:Equity contextRef="c277" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">338200</e:Equity><e:Equity contextRef="c280" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">338200</e:Equity><e:Equity contextRef="c283" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">338290</e:Equity><e:Equity contextRef="c286" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">338290</e:Equity><e:IncreaseOfCapital contextRef="c278" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">46837</e:IncreaseOfCapital><e:IncreaseOfCapital contextRef="c281" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">0</e:IncreaseOfCapital><e:IncreaseOfCapital contextRef="c284" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">0</e:IncreaseOfCapital><e:IncreaseOfCapital contextRef="c287" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">0</e:IncreaseOfCapital><e:Equity contextRef="c279" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">385037</e:Equity><e:Equity contextRef="c282" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">338200</e:Equity><e:Equity contextRef="c285" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">338290</e:Equity><e:Equity contextRef="c288" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">338290</e:Equity><e:DisclosureOfDeferredTaxAssetsAndLiabilities contextRef="c11" xml:lang="da">Hensættelse til udskudt skat 1. januar 2017 
33.096.024
23.870.827
832.090
326.260
Provision for deferred tax at 1 January 2017 




Hensat i året 
926.791
9.225.197
104.147
505.830
Provision in year 




Hensættelse til udskudt skat 31. december 2017 
34.022.815
33.096.024
936.237
832.090
Provision for deferred tax at 31 December 2017 









Hensættelse til udskudt skat vedrører:
Provisions for deffered tax on:
Materielle anlægsaktiver 
32.141.074
31.159.915
0
0
Property, plant and equipment 




Finansielle anlægsaktiver 
2.297.892
2.337.116
936.237
832.090
Fixed asset investments 




Tilgodehavender fra salg og tjenesteydelse 
-11.000
0
0
0
Trade receivables 




Låneomkostninger 
89
-607
0
0
Amortization




Andre midlertidige forskelle 
-405.240
-400.400
0
0
Other taxable temporary differences




 
34.022.815
33.089.432
936.237
832.090





</e:DisclosureOfDeferredTaxAssetsAndLiabilities><e:ProvisionsForDeferredTax contextRef="c289" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">33096024</e:ProvisionsForDeferredTax><e:ProvisionsForDeferredTax contextRef="c290" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">23870827</e:ProvisionsForDeferredTax><e:ProvisionsForDeferredTax contextRef="c289" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">832090</e:ProvisionsForDeferredTax><e:ProvisionsForDeferredTax contextRef="c290" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">326260</e:ProvisionsForDeferredTax><e:ProvisionsForDeferredTax contextRef="c75" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">34022815</e:ProvisionsForDeferredTax><e:ProvisionsForDeferredTax contextRef="c74" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">33096024</e:ProvisionsForDeferredTax><e:ProvisionsForDeferredTax contextRef="c75" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">936237</e:ProvisionsForDeferredTax><e:ProvisionsForDeferredTax contextRef="c74" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">832090</e:ProvisionsForDeferredTax><e:DeferredTaxLiability contextRef="c425" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">32141074</e:DeferredTaxLiability><e:DeferredTaxLiability contextRef="c426" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">31159915</e:DeferredTaxLiability><e:DeferredTaxLiability contextRef="c427" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">2297892</e:DeferredTaxLiability><e:DeferredTaxLiability contextRef="c428" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">2337116</e:DeferredTaxLiability><e:DeferredTaxLiability contextRef="c431" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">-11000</e:DeferredTaxLiability><e:DeferredTaxLiability contextRef="c432" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">0</e:DeferredTaxLiability><e:DeferredTaxLiability contextRef="c714" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">89</e:DeferredTaxLiability><e:DeferredTaxLiability contextRef="c715" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">-607</e:DeferredTaxLiability><e:DeferredTaxLiability contextRef="c718" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">-405240</e:DeferredTaxLiability><e:DeferredTaxLiability contextRef="c719" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">-400400</e:DeferredTaxLiability><e:LongtermLiabilitiesOtherThanProvisions contextRef="c236" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">135689203</e:LongtermLiabilitiesOtherThanProvisions><e:LongtermLiabilitiesOtherThanProvisions contextRef="c234" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">129348767</e:LongtermLiabilitiesOtherThanProvisions><e:LongtermLiabilitiesOtherThanProvisionsDueInOneYear contextRef="c234" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">6481157</e:LongtermLiabilitiesOtherThanProvisionsDueInOneYear><e:LongtermLiabilitiesOtherThanProvisionsDueAfterFiveYearsAndMore contextRef="c234" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">95904039</e:LongtermLiabilitiesOtherThanProvisionsDueAfterFiveYearsAndMore><e:LongtermLiabilitiesOtherThanProvisions contextRef="c268" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">9605968</e:LongtermLiabilitiesOtherThanProvisions><e:LongtermLiabilitiesOtherThanProvisions contextRef="c267" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">9770098</e:LongtermLiabilitiesOtherThanProvisions><e:LongtermLiabilitiesOtherThanProvisionsDueInOneYear contextRef="c267" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">0</e:LongtermLiabilitiesOtherThanProvisionsDueInOneYear><e:LongtermLiabilitiesOtherThanProvisionsDueAfterFiveYearsAndMore contextRef="c267" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">5430075</e:LongtermLiabilitiesOtherThanProvisionsDueAfterFiveYearsAndMore><e:DisclosureOfDeferredIncome contextRef="c11" xml:lang="da">Periodeafgrænsningsposter udgøres af modtagne forudbetalinger vedrørende indtægter i de efterfølgende år samt reguleringer til dagsværdi for afledte finansielle instrumenter med negativ dagsværdi.</e:DisclosureOfDeferredIncome><e:DisclosureOfDeferredIncome contextRef="c11" xml:lang="en">Deferred income consists of payments received in respect of income in subsequent years as well as fair value adjustments of derivative financial instruments with a negative fair value.</e:DisclosureOfDeferredIncome><e:DisclosureOfContingentLiabilities contextRef="c11" xml:lang="da">I forbindelse med en associeret virksomheds salg af en vindmøllepark har Adyn ApS afgivet pro rata kaution for sælgers sædvanlige garantier i salgsaftalen. Garantierne omhandler rettigheder, selskabets status og skatteposition mm.
I en associeret virksomhed er der etableret bankgaranti over for tredjepart på EUR 1,4 mio.
Kautions- og garantiforpligtelser
Selskabet er som administrationsselskab sambeskattet med øvrige danske tilknyttede virksomheder, og hæfter solidarisk med øvrige sambeskattede selskaber for betaling af selskabsskat for indkomståret 2013 og frem samt for kildeskat på udbytter, renter og royalties, som forfalder til betaling 1. juli 2012 eller senere.
Selskabet har sammen med en anden selskabsdeltager afgivet pro rata selvskyldnerkaution for 2 tyske associerede selskabers bankkreditter.</e:DisclosureOfContingentLiabilities><e:DisclosureOfContingentLiabilities contextRef="c11" xml:lang="en">In connection with an affiliate's sale of a wind farm, Adyn ApS has provided a pro rata guarantee for the seller's usual guarantees in the sales agreement. The guarantees concern rights, company status and tax position etc.
An associated company has established a bank guarantee against a third party of EUR 1.4 million.
Recourse and non-recourse guarantee commitments
In its capacity as management company, the company is jointly taxed with its Danish group entities and is jointly and severally liable with the other jointly taxed entities for the payment of income taxes for income years 2013 onwards and withholding taxes on dividends, interest and royalties falling due for payment on or after 1 July 2012.
The company together with another shareholder made pro rata guarantee for 2 German affiliates' bank credits.</e:DisclosureOfContingentLiabilities><e:DisclosureOfMortgagesAndCollaterals contextRef="c11" xml:lang="da">Til sikkerhed for gæld til realkreditinstitutter, t.kr. 129.046, er der givet pant i grunde og bygninger, hvis regnskabsmæssige værdi pr. 31/12 2017  udgør t.kr. 311.548.
Der er udstedt ejerpantebreve for i alt kr. 25.000 i ovenstående grunde og bygninger. Ejerpantebrevene er i koncernens egen besiddelse.
Til sikkerhed for 2 tyske associerede virksomheders bankkreditter er der meddelt sikkerhed i kapitalandelene for disse virksomheder. Den bogførte værdi af kapitalandelene andrager pr. 31/12 2017 t.kr. 693.
</e:DisclosureOfMortgagesAndCollaterals><e:DisclosureOfMortgagesAndCollaterals contextRef="c11" xml:lang="en">As security for mortgage debt totalling DKK 129.046 thousand, the Company has granted charges on land and buildings carried at DKK 311.348 thousand at 31 December 2017.
The Group has issued mortgages registered to the owners totalling DKK 25.000 on the above land and buildings, which are in the Group's own possession.
As security for bank credits in two German associates are granted security in the shares for these companies. As of 31 december 2017 the book value of the investment amounts to KDKK 693.
</e:DisclosureOfMortgagesAndCollaterals><e:InformationOnRelatedEntities contextRef="c11" xml:lang="da">Marcus Choleva, Stavnsholt Gydevej 38, DK-3460 Birkerød</e:InformationOnRelatedEntities><e:InformationOnTransactionsWithRelatedPartiesConcludedUnderNormalMarketConditions contextRef="c11" xml:lang="da">Transaktioner med nærtstående parter er sket på markedsvilkår.</e:InformationOnTransactionsWithRelatedPartiesConcludedUnderNormalMarketConditions><e:InformationOnTransactionsWithRelatedPartiesConcludedUnderNormalMarketConditions contextRef="c11" xml:lang="en">Transactions with related parties has been effected at arm's length.</e:InformationOnTransactionsWithRelatedPartiesConcludedUnderNormalMarketConditions><e:AdjustmentsOfInterestAndSimilarIncomes contextRef="c11" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">-58041711</e:AdjustmentsOfInterestAndSimilarIncomes><e:AdjustmentsOfInterestAndSimilarIncomes contextRef="c17" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">-50186283</e:AdjustmentsOfInterestAndSimilarIncomes><e:AdjustmentsfInterestAndSimilarExpenses contextRef="c11" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">4759316</e:AdjustmentsfInterestAndSimilarExpenses><e:AdjustmentsfInterestAndSimilarExpenses contextRef="c17" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">15701928</e:AdjustmentsfInterestAndSimilarExpenses><e:DepreciationAmortisationExpenseAndImpairmentLossesOfPropertyPlantAndEquipmentAndIntangibleAssets contextRef="c11" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">1382649</e:DepreciationAmortisationExpenseAndImpairmentLossesOfPropertyPlantAndEquipmentAndIntangibleAssets><e:DepreciationAmortisationExpenseAndImpairmentLossesOfPropertyPlantAndEquipmentAndIntangibleAssets contextRef="c17" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">773552</e:DepreciationAmortisationExpenseAndImpairmentLossesOfPropertyPlantAndEquipmentAndIntangibleAssets><e:AdjustmentsOfShareBasedPayment contextRef="c11" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">-8405695</e:AdjustmentsOfShareBasedPayment><e:AdjustmentsOfShareBasedPayment contextRef="c17" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">-36079943</e:AdjustmentsOfShareBasedPayment><e:AdjustmentsOfProfitFromAssociatesAfterTax contextRef="c11" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">-20019540</e:AdjustmentsOfProfitFromAssociatesAfterTax><e:AdjustmentsOfProfitFromAssociatesAfterTax contextRef="c17" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">-644</e:AdjustmentsOfProfitFromAssociatesAfterTax><e:AdjustmentsOfTaxExpense contextRef="c11" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">16053262</e:AdjustmentsOfTaxExpense><e:AdjustmentsOfTaxExpense contextRef="c17" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">13151900</e:AdjustmentsOfTaxExpense><e:OtherAdjustments contextRef="c11" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">0</e:OtherAdjustments><e:OtherAdjustments contextRef="c17" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">629316</e:OtherAdjustments><e:DecreaseIncreaseInReceivables contextRef="c11" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">-1077618</e:DecreaseIncreaseInReceivables><e:DecreaseIncreaseInReceivables contextRef="c17" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">-20572577</e:DecreaseIncreaseInReceivables><e:DecreaseIncreaseInTradePayables contextRef="c11" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">-7047503</e:DecreaseIncreaseInTradePayables><e:DecreaseIncreaseInTradePayables contextRef="c17" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">3677622</e:DecreaseIncreaseInTradePayables><e:AdjustmentsForDecreaseIncreaseInWorkingCapital contextRef="c11" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">-8125121</e:AdjustmentsForDecreaseIncreaseInWorkingCapital><e:AdjustmentsForDecreaseIncreaseInWorkingCapital contextRef="c17" unitRef="u2" decimals="0">-16894955</e:AdjustmentsForDecreaseIncreaseInWorkingCapital><e:InformationOnReportingClassOfEntity contextRef="c11" xml:lang="da">Årsrapporten for Adyn ApS for 2017 er aflagt i overensstemmelse med årsregnskabslovens bestemmelser  for mellemstore virksomheder i regnskabsklasse C.
Den anvendte regnskabspraksis er ens for såvel moderselskabsregnskabet som koncernregnskabet.
Den anvendte regnskabspraksis er uændret i forhold til sidste år.
Årsrapporten for 2017 er aflagt i kr.</e:InformationOnReportingClassOfEntity><e:InformationOnReportingClassOfEntity contextRef="c11" xml:lang="en">The annual report of Adyn ApS for 2017 has been prepared in accordance with the provisions of the Danish Financial Statements Act applying to medium-sized enterprises of reporting class C.
The accounting policies are identical for both the parent company financial statements and the consolidated financial statements.
The accounting policies applied are consistent with those of last year.
The annual report for 2017 is presented in kr.</e:InformationOnReportingClassOfEntity><e:DescriptionOfGeneralMattersRelatedToRecognitionMeasurementAndChangesInAccountingPolicies contextRef="c11" xml:lang="da">I resultatopgørelsen indregnes indtægter i takt med, at de indtjenes. Herudover indregnes værdireguleringer af finansielle aktiver og forpligtelser. I resultatopgørelsen indregnes ligeledes alle omkostninger, herunder afskrivninger og nedskrivninger. 
Aktiver indregnes i balancen, når det er sandsynligt, at fremtidige økonomiske fordele vil tilflyde koncernen og moderselskabet og aktivets værdi kan måles pålideligt.
Forpligtelser indregnes i balancen, når det er sandsynligt, at fremtidige økonomiske fordele vil fragå koncernen og moderselskabet, og forpligtelsens værdi kan måles pålideligt.
Ved første indregning måles aktiver og forpligtelser til kostpris. Efterfølgende måles aktiver og forpligtelser som beskrevet for hver enkelt regnskabspost nedenfor.
Visse finansielle aktiver og forpligtelser måles til amortiseret kostpris, hvorved der indregnes en konstant effektiv rente over løbetiden. Amortiseret kostpris opgøres som oprindelig kostpris med fradrag af eventuelle afdrag samt tillæg/fradrag af den akkumulerede amortisering af forskellen mellem kostpris og nominelt beløb. 
Ved indregning og måling tages hensyn til forudsigelige tab og risici, der fremkommer, inden årsrapporten aflægges, og som be- eller afkræfter forhold, der eksisterede på balancedagen.</e:DescriptionOfGeneralMattersRelatedToRecognitionMeasurementAndChangesInAccountingPolicies><e:DescriptionOfGeneralMattersRelatedToRecognitionMeasurementAndChangesInAccountingPolicies contextRef="c11" xml:lang="en">Income is recognised in the income statement as earned, including value adjustments of financial assets and liabilities. All expenses, including amortisation, depreciation and impairment losses, are also recognised in the income statement.
Assets are recognised in the balance sheet when it is probable that future economic benefits will flow to the group's and the parent company's and the value of the asset can be measured reliably.
Liabilities are recognised in the balance sheet when it is probable that future economic benefits will flow from the group's and the parent company's and the value of the liability can be measured reliably.
On initial recognition, assets and liabilities are measured at cost. On subsequent recognition, assets and liabilities are measured as described below for each individual accounting item.
Certain financial assets and liabilities are measured at amortised cost using the effective interest method. Amortised cost is calculated as the historic cost less any instalments and plus/less the accumulated amortisation of the difference between the cost and the nominal amount. 
On recognition and measurement, allowance is made for predictable losses and risks which occur before the annual report is presented and which confirm or invalidate matters existing at the balance sheet date.</e:DescriptionOfGeneralMattersRelatedToRecognitionMeasurementAndChangesInAccountingPolicies><e:InformationOnConsolidations contextRef="c11" xml:lang="da">Koncernregnskabet omfatter modervirksomheden Adyn Aps og dattervirksomheder, hvori Adyn Aps direkte eller indirekte besidder mere end 50% af stemmerettighederne eller på anden måde har bestemmende indflydelse. Virksomheder, hvori koncernen besidder mellem 20% og 50% af stemmerettighederne og udøver betydelig, men ikke bestemmende indflydelse, betragtes som associerede virksomheder, jf. koncernoversigten.
Ved konsolideringen foretages eliminering af koncerninterne indtægter og omkostninger, aktiebesidelser, interne mellemværender og udbytter samt realiserede og urealiserede fortjenester og tab ved transaktioner mellem konsoliderede virksomheder.
Kapitalandele i dattervirksomheder udlignes med den forholdsmæssige andel af dattervirksomheders dagsværdi af nettoaktiver og forpligtelser på anskaffelsestidspunktet.
Nyerhvervede eller nystiftede virksomheder indregnes i koncernregnskabet fra anskaffelsestidspunktet. Solgte eller afviklede virksomheder, indregnes i den konsoliderede resultatopgørelse frem til afståelsestidspunktet. Sammenligningstal korrigeres ikke for nyerhvervede, solgte eller afviklede virksomheder.</e:InformationOnConsolidations><e:InformationOnConsolidations contextRef="c11" xml:lang="en">The consolidated financial statements comprise the parent company Adyn Aps and subsidiaries in which the parent company, directly or indirectly, holds more than 50% of the voting rights or otherwise has a controlling interest. Entities in which the Group holds between 20% and 50% of the voting rights and over which it exercises significant influence, but which it does not control, are considered associates, cf. the group chart.
On consolidation, intra-group income and expenses, holdings of shares, intra-group balances and dividends as well as realised and unrealised gains and losses on intra-group transactions are eliminated.
Investments in subsidiaries are set off against the proportionate share of the subsidiaries' fair value of net assets and liabilities at the acquisition date.
Entities acquired or formed during the year are recognised in the consolidated financial statements from the date of acquisition. Entities disposed of are recognised in the consolidated income statement until the date of disposal. Comparative figures are not restated for acquisitions or disposals.</e:InformationOnConsolidations><e:DescriptionOfMethodsOfRecognitionAndMeasurementBasisOfOtherOperatingIncome contextRef="c11" xml:lang="da">Andre driftsindtægter indeholder regnskabsposter af sekundær karakter i forhold til virksomhedernes aktiviteter, herunder fortjeneste ved salg af materielle anlægsaktiver.</e:DescriptionOfMethodsOfRecognitionAndMeasurementBasisOfOtherOperatingIncome><e:DescriptionOfMethodsOfRecognitionAndMeasurementBasisOfOtherOperatingIncome contextRef="c11" xml:lang="en">Other operating income comprises items of a secondary nature relative to the company's activities, including gains on the sale of property, plant and equipment.</e:DescriptionOfMethodsOfRecognitionAndMeasurementBasisOfOtherOperatingIncome><e:DescriptionOfMethodsOfRecognitionAndMeasurementBasisOfExternalExpenses contextRef="c11" xml:lang="da">Andre eksterne omkostninger omfatter omkostninger til ejendommenes drift, reklame, administration, lokaler, tab på debitorer mv.</e:DescriptionOfMethodsOfRecognitionAndMeasurementBasisOfExternalExpenses><e:DescriptionOfMethodsOfRecognitionAndMeasurementBasisOfExternalExpenses contextRef="c11" xml:lang="en">Other external expenses include expenses related to the operation of the properties, advertising, administration, premises, bad debts etc.</e:DescriptionOfMethodsOfRecognitionAndMeasurementBasisOfExternalExpenses><e:DescriptionOfMethodsOfRecognitionAndMeasurementBasisOfEmployeeBenefitExpense contextRef="c11" xml:lang="da">Personaleomkostninger omfatter løn og gager, inklusive feriepenge og pensioner samt andre omkostninger til social sikring m.v. til selskabets medarbejdere. I personaleomkostninger er fratrukket modtagne godtgørelser fra offentlige myndigheder.</e:DescriptionOfMethodsOfRecognitionAndMeasurementBasisOfEmployeeBenefitExpense><e:DescriptionOfMethodsOfRecognitionAndMeasurementBasisOfEmployeeBenefitExpense contextRef="c11" xml:lang="en">Staff costs include wages and salaries, including compensated absence and pensions, as well as other social security contributions, etc. made to the entity's employees. The item is net of refunds made by public authorities.</e:DescriptionOfMethodsOfRecognitionAndMeasurementBasisOfEmployeeBenefitExpense><e:DescriptionOfMethodsOfImpairmentLossesAndDepreciation contextRef="c11" xml:lang="da">Af- og nedskrivninger indeholder årets af- og nedskrivninger af immaterielle og materielle anlægsaktiver.</e:DescriptionOfMethodsOfImpairmentLossesAndDepreciation><e:DescriptionOfMethodsOfImpairmentLossesAndDepreciation contextRef="c11" xml:lang="en">Amortisation, depreciation and impairment losses comprise the year's amortisation, depreciation and impairment of intangible assets and property, plant and equipment.</e:DescriptionOfMethodsOfImpairmentLossesAndDepreciation><e:DescriptionOfMethodsOfRecognitionAndMeasurementBasisOfGainsLossesFromCurrentValueAdjustmentsOfInvestmentProperty contextRef="c11" xml:lang="da">Værdiregulering af investeringsejendomme indeholder årets ændring i dagsværdien af  investeringsejendomme og tilhørende gæld.</e:DescriptionOfMethodsOfRecognitionAndMeasurementBasisOfGainsLossesFromCurrentValueAdjustmentsOfInvestmentProperty><e:DescriptionOfMethodsOfRecognitionAndMeasurementBasisOfGainsLossesFromCurrentValueAdjustmentsOfInvestmentProperty contextRef="c11" xml:lang="en">Value adjustments of investment property comprise the year's changes in the fair value of investment property and relating payables.</e:DescriptionOfMethodsOfRecognitionAndMeasurementBasisOfGainsLossesFromCurrentValueAdjustmentsOfInvestmentProperty><e:DescriptionOfMethodsOfRecognitionAndMeasurementBasisOfFinanceIncomeAndExpenses contextRef="c11" xml:lang="da">Finansielle indtægter og omkostninger indregnes i resultatopgørelsen med de beløb, der vedrører regnskabsåret. Finansielle poster omfatter renteindtægter og -omkostninger, realiserede og urealiserede kursgevinster og -tab vedrørende værdipapirer, gæld og transaktioner i fremmed valuta, amortisering af realkreditlån samt tillæg og godtgørelse under acontoskatteordningen mv.</e:DescriptionOfMethodsOfRecognitionAndMeasurementBasisOfFinanceIncomeAndExpenses><e:DescriptionOfMethodsOfRecognitionAndMeasurementBasisOfFinanceIncomeAndExpenses contextRef="c11" xml:lang="en">Financial income and expenses are recognised in the income statement at the amounts relating to the financial year. Net financials include interest income and expenses, realised and unrealised capital/exchange gains and losses on securities and foreign currency transactions, amortisation of mortgage loans and surcharges and allowances under the advance-payment-of-tax scheme, etc.</e:DescriptionOfMethodsOfRecognitionAndMeasurementBasisOfFinanceIncomeAndExpenses><e:DescriptionOfMethodsOfRecognitionAndMeasurementBasisOfIncomeAndExpensesFromInvestmentsInGroupEnterprisesAndAssociates contextRef="c11" xml:lang="da">I modervirksomhedens resultatopgørelse indregnes den forholdsmæssige andel af de enkelte dattervirksomheders resultat efter skat efter fuld eliminering af intern avance/tab.
I både koncernens og modervirksomhedens resultatopgørelser  indregnes den forholdsmæssige andel af de associerede virksomheders resultat efter skat efter eliminering af forholdsmæssig andel af intern avance/tab.</e:DescriptionOfMethodsOfRecognitionAndMeasurementBasisOfIncomeAndExpensesFromInvestmentsInGroupEnterprisesAndAssociates><e:DescriptionOfMethodsOfRecognitionAndMeasurementBasisOfIncomeAndExpensesFromInvestmentsInGroupEnterprisesAndAssociates contextRef="c11" xml:lang="en">The proportionate share of the results after tax of the individual subsidiaries is recognised in the income statement of the parent companyafter full elimination of intra-group profits/losses.
The proportionate share of the results after tax of the associates is recognised in both the consolidated and the parent company income statement after elimination of the proportionate share of intra-group profits/gains.</e:DescriptionOfMethodsOfRecognitionAndMeasurementBasisOfIncomeAndExpensesFromInvestmentsInGroupEnterprisesAndAssociates><e:DescriptionOfMethodsOfRecognitionAndMeasurementBasisOfTaxExpenses contextRef="c11" xml:lang="da">Modervirksomheden er omfattet af de danske regler om tvungen sambeskatning af koncernens danske dattervirksomheder. Dattervirksomheder indgår i sambeskatningen fra det tidspunkt, hvor de indgår i konsolideringen i koncernregnskabet og frem til det tidspunkt, hvor de udgår fra konsolideringen.
Modervirksomheden er administrationsselskab for sambeskatningen og afregner som følge heraf alle betalinger af selskabsskat med skattemyndighederne.
Den aktuelle danske selskabsskat fordeles ved afregning af sambeskatningsbidrag mellem de sambeskattede virksomheder i forhold til disses skattepligtige indkomster. I tilknytning hertil modtager virksomheder med skattemæssigt underskud sambeskatningsbidrag fra virksomheder, der har kunnet anvende dette underskud til nedsættelse af eget skattemæssigt overskud.
Årets skat, som består af årets aktuelle selskabsskat og ændring i udskudt skat, indregnes i resultatopgørelsen med den del, der kan henføres til årets resultat, og direkte i egenkapitalen med den del, der kan henføres til posteringer direkte i egenkapitalen.</e:DescriptionOfMethodsOfRecognitionAndMeasurementBasisOfTaxExpenses><e:DescriptionOfMethodsOfRecognitionAndMeasurementBasisOfTaxExpenses contextRef="c11" xml:lang="en">The parent company is subject to the Danish rules on compulsory joint taxation of the Group's Danish subsidiaries. Subsidiaries participate in the joint taxation arrangement from the time when they are included in the consolidated financial statements and until the time when they withdraw from the consolidation.
The parent company acts as management company for all jointly taxed entities and, in its capacity as such, pays all income taxes to the Danish tax authorities.
On payment of joint taxation contributions, the current Danish income tax is allocated between the jointly taxed entities in proportion to their taxable income. Entities with tax losses receive joint taxation contributions from entities that have been able to use tax losses to reduce their own taxable profits.
Tax for the year, which comprises the current tax charge for the year and changes in the deferred tax charge, including changes arising from changes in tax rates, is recognised in the income statement as regards the portion that relates to entries directly in equity.</e:DescriptionOfMethodsOfRecognitionAndMeasurementBasisOfTaxExpenses><e:DescriptionOfMethodsOfRecognitionAndMeasurementBasisOfPropertyPlantAndEquipment contextRef="c11" xml:lang="da">Grunde og bygninger, driftsmateriel og inventar måles til kostpris med fradrag af akkumulerede af- og nedskrivninger.
Afskrivningsgrundlaget er kostpris med fradrag af forventet restværdi efter afsluttet brugstid. Der afskrives ikke på grunde.
Kostpris omfatter anskaffelsesprisen og omkostninger direkte tilknyttet anskaffelsen indtil det tidspunkt, hvor aktivet er klar til brug. For egne fremstillede aktiver omfatter kostprisen direkte og indirekte omkostninger til materialer, komponenter, underleverandører og løn.
Der foretages lineære afskrivninger baseret på følgende vurdering af aktivernes forventede brugstider og restværdier:
Brugstid 
Useful life  
Andre anlæg, driftsmateriel og inventar  3-10  år  
Other fixtures and fittings, tools and equipment  3-10  years  

Aktiver med en kostpris på under kr. 13.200 omkostningsføres i anskaffelsesåret.
Fortjeneste eller tab ved salg af materielle anlægsaktiver indregnes i resultatopgørelsen under andre driftsindtægter henholdsvis andre driftsomkostninger.</e:DescriptionOfMethodsOfRecognitionAndMeasurementBasisOfPropertyPlantAndEquipment><e:DescriptionOfMethodsOfRecognitionAndMeasurementBasisOfPropertyPlantAndEquipment contextRef="c11" xml:lang="en">Items of land and buildings, tools and equipment are measured at cost less accumulated depreciation and impairment losses.
The depreciable amount is cost less the expected residual value at the end of the useful life. Land is not depreciated.
Cost comprises the purchase price and any costs directly attributable to the acquisition until the date when the asset is available for use. The cost of self-constructed assets comprises direct and indirect costs of materials, components, sub-suppliers and wages.
Straight-line depreciation is provided on the basis of the following estimated useful lives of the assets:
Assets costing less than kr. 13.200 are expensed in the year of acquisition.
Gains or losses from the disposal of property, plant and equipment are recognised in the income statement as other operating income or other operating expenses.</e:DescriptionOfMethodsOfRecognitionAndMeasurementBasisOfPropertyPlantAndEquipment><e:DescriptionOfMethodsOfRecognitionAndMeasurementBasisOfInvestmentProperty contextRef="c11" xml:lang="da">Investeringsejendomme
Investeringsejendomme udgør investeringer i grunde og bygninger med det formål at opnå afkast af den investerede kapital i form af løbende driftsafkast og/eller kapitalgevinst ved videresalg.
Vis opsætning af investeringsaktiverInvesteringsejendomme måles ved anskaffelse til kostpris omfattende anskaffelsespris inkl. købsomkostninger. 
Efter første indregning måles investeringsejendomme til dagsværdi. Værdireguleringer af investeringsejendomme indregnes i resultatopgørelsen. 
Dagsværdien er udtryk for den pris ejendommen kan handles til mellem velinformerede og villige parter på arms længde vilkår på balancedagen. Fastlæggelse af dagsværdi medfører væsentlige regnskabsmæssige skøn.
Det er ledelsens vurdering, at det for indeværende år ikke har været muligt at finde dagsværdien ved hjælp af markedsinformationer, hvorfor værdiansættelsen er sket på baggrund af diskonteringsmodeller.
Dagsværdien for investeringsejendomme er pr. 31. december 2017 fastsat ved anvendelse af en afkastbaseret værdiansættelsesmodel. Beregningerne tager udgangspunkt i budget for det kommende år, korrigeret for udsving, der karakteriseres ved at være enkeltstående begivenheder. Denne normalindtjening kapitaliseres med en individuelt fastsat afkastprocent. Den herved beregnede værdi korrigeres for eventuelle driftsfremmede aktiver, såsom likvider, deposita mv., såfremt disse ikke indgår særskilt andet sted i balancen, hvorved dagsværdien fremkommer.
De anvendte skøn er baseret på oplysninger samt forudsætninger, som ledelsen vurderer forsvarlige, men som i sagens natur er usikre og uforudsigelige. De faktiske begivenheder eller omstændigheder vil sandsynligvis afvige fra de i beregningerne forudsatte, idet forudsatte begivenheder ofte ikke indtræder som forventet. Disse afvigelser kan være væsentlige.</e:DescriptionOfMethodsOfRecognitionAndMeasurementBasisOfInvestmentProperty><e:DescriptionOfMethodsOfRecognitionAndMeasurementBasisOfInvestmentProperty contextRef="c11" xml:lang="en">Investment properties
Investment properties comprises investments in land and buildings for purposes of gaining a return on the invested capital in the form of regular operating income and/or capital gains on resale.
On acquisition, investment properties is measured at cost, comprising the purchase price, including purchase costs.
On subsequent recognition, investment property is measured at cost less the year's depreciation and impairment charges. investment properties are measured at fair value. Value adjustments of investment properties on subsequent recognition, investment property is measured at cost less the year's depreciation and impairment charges.
The fair value reflects the price for which the property should exchange on the balance sheet date between well-informed and willing parties in an arm's length transaction. The determination of fair value involves significant accounting estimates.
In management's assessment, the fair value for the current year could not be determined based on market information. Accordingly, values have been determined based on discount models.
The fair value of each individual investment properties at 31 december 2017 has been determined using a return-based valuation model. Calculations are based on the budget for the coming year, adjusted for any fluctuations characterised as non-recurring events. These normal earnings are capitalised based on an individually determined return rate. The resulting value is adjusted for any non-operating assets, such as cash and cash equivalents, deposits, etc., provided these are not separately disclosed elsewhere in the balance sheet, to arrive at the fair value. 
The estimates used are based on information and assumptions which management considers reasonable, but which are, inherently, uncertain and unpredictable. Actual events and circumstances are likely to be different from those assumed in the calculations, since anticipated events frequently do not occur as expected. These variations may be material.</e:DescriptionOfMethodsOfRecognitionAndMeasurementBasisOfInvestmentProperty><e:DescriptionOfMethodsOfRecognitionAndMeasurementBasisForInvestmentsInSubsidiariesAndAssociates contextRef="c11" xml:lang="da">Kapitalandele i dattervirksomheder og associerede virksomheder måles til den forholdsmæssige andel af virksomhedernes indre værdi opgjort efter koncernens regnskabspraksis med fradrag eller tillæg af urealiserede koncerninterne avancer og tab og med tillæg eller fradrag af resterende værdi af positiv eller negativ goodwill opgjort efter overtagelsesmetoden.
Kapitalandele i dattervirksomheder og associerede virksomheder med regnskabsmæssig negativ indre værdi måles til kr. 0, og et eventuelt tilgodehavende hos disse virksomheder nedskrives, i det omfang tilgodehavendet er uerholdeligt. I det omfang modervirksomheden har en retlig eller faktisk forpligtelse til at dække en underbalance, der overstiger tilgodehavendet, indregnes det resterende beløb under hensatte forpligtelser.
Nettoopskrivning af kapitalandele i dattervirksomheder og associerede virksomheder bindes som reserve for nettoopskrivning efter den indre værdis metode under egenkapitalen, i det omfang den regnskabsmæssige værdi overstiger kostprisen. Udbytter fra dattervirksomheder, der forventes vedtaget inden godkendelsen af årsrapporten for Adyn ApS, bindes ikke på opskrivningsreserven.
Ved køb af virksomheder anvendes overtagelsesmetoden, jf. beskrivelse ovenfor under opgørelse af goodwill. </e:DescriptionOfMethodsOfRecognitionAndMeasurementBasisForInvestmentsInSubsidiariesAndAssociates><e:DescriptionOfMethodsOfRecognitionAndMeasurementBasisForInvestmentsInSubsidiariesAndAssociates contextRef="c11" xml:lang="en">Investments in subsidiaries and associates are measured at the proportionate share of the net asset value of the entities, calculated on the basis of the group's accounting policies, less or plus unrealised intra-group gains or losses and plus or less any remaining value of positive or negative goodwill made up according to the purchase method.
Investments in subsidiaries and associates with a negative net asset value are measured at DKK 0, and the carrying amount of any receivables from these entities is reduced to the extent that they are considered irrecoverable. If the parent company has a legal or constructive obligation to cover a deficit that exceeds the receivable, the balance is recognised under provisions.
Net revaluations of investments in subsidiaries and associates are taken to the net revaluation reserve according to the equity method to the extent that the carrying amount exceeds the cost. Dividends from subsidiaries which are expected to be declared before the annual report of  Adyn ApS is adopted are not taken to the net revaluation reserve.
Acquisitions are accounted for using the purchase method, cf. the description of the statement of goodwill above.</e:DescriptionOfMethodsOfRecognitionAndMeasurementBasisForInvestmentsInSubsidiariesAndAssociates><e:DescriptionOfMethodsOfInvestments contextRef="c11" xml:lang="da">Kapitalandele måles til dagsværdi.
Beholdning af gældsbreve, der af ledelsen forventes beholdt til udløb, måles til amortiseret kostpris. Ved amortiseret kostpris for disse gældsbreve forstås gældsbrevenes resttilgodehavende optaget til en kurs, der beregnes som kursværdien (dagsprisen) ved anskaffelsen med et tidsmæssigt beregnet tillæg/fradrag af forskellen mellem denne kurs og indfrielseskurs.</e:DescriptionOfMethodsOfInvestments><e:DescriptionOfMethodsOfInvestments contextRef="c11" xml:lang="en">Investments are measured at fair value.
Holding of debt securities which management expects will be kept to maturity is measured at amortised cost. By amortised cost for these securities is meant the outstanding receivable recognised at a price calculated as the market value (fair value) on acquisition with a surcharge/allowance of the difference between this value and the redemption price.</e:DescriptionOfMethodsOfInvestments><e:DescriptionOfMethodsOfAmortisationOfNoncurrentAssets contextRef="c11" xml:lang="da">Den regnskabsmæssige værdi af immaterielle og materielle anlægsaktiver samt kapitalandele i dattervirksomheder og associerede virksomheder vurderes årligt for indikationer på værdiforringelse, ud over det som udtrykkes ved afskrivning.
Foreligger der indikationer på værdiforringelse, foretages nedskrivningstest af hvert enkelt aktiv henholdsvis gruppe af aktiver. Der foretages nedskrivning til genindvindingsværdien, hvis denne er lavere end den regnskabsmæssige værdi.</e:DescriptionOfMethodsOfAmortisationOfNoncurrentAssets><e:DescriptionOfMethodsOfAmortisationOfNoncurrentAssets contextRef="c11" xml:lang="en">The carrying amount of intangible assets, property, plant and equipment and investments in subsidiaries and associates is reviewed for impairment, other than what is reflected through normal amortisation and depreciation, on an annual basis.
Where there are indications of impairment, an impairment test is performed for each individual asset or group of assets, respectively. The carrying amount of impaired assets is reduced to the higher of the net selling price and the value in use (recoverable amount).</e:DescriptionOfMethodsOfAmortisationOfNoncurrentAssets><e:DescriptionOfMethodsOfRecognitionAndMeasurementBasisOfReceivables contextRef="c11" xml:lang="da">Tilgodehavender måles til amortiseret kostpris.</e:DescriptionOfMethodsOfRecognitionAndMeasurementBasisOfReceivables><e:DescriptionOfMethodsOfRecognitionAndMeasurementBasisOfReceivables contextRef="c11" xml:lang="en">Receivables are measured at amortised cost.</e:DescriptionOfMethodsOfRecognitionAndMeasurementBasisOfReceivables><e:DescriptionOfMethodsOfRecognitionAndMeasurementBasisOfDeferredIncomeAssets contextRef="c11" xml:lang="da">Periodeafgrænsningsposter, indregnet under omsætningsaktiver, omfatter afholdte omkostninger vedrørende efterfølgende regnskabsår.</e:DescriptionOfMethodsOfRecognitionAndMeasurementBasisOfDeferredIncomeAssets><e:DescriptionOfMethodsOfRecognitionAndMeasurementBasisOfDeferredIncomeAssets contextRef="c11" xml:lang="en">Prepayments comprise costs incurred concerning subsequent financial years.</e:DescriptionOfMethodsOfRecognitionAndMeasurementBasisOfDeferredIncomeAssets><e:DescriptionOfMethodsOfDividends contextRef="c11" xml:lang="da">Reserve for nettoopskrivning efter den indre værdis metode
Reserve for nettoopskrivning efter indre værdis metode i moderselskabets årsregnskab omfatter nettoopskrivning af kapitalandele i dattervirksomheder og associerede virksomheder i forhold til kostpris.</e:DescriptionOfMethodsOfDividends><e:DescriptionOfMethodsOfDividends contextRef="c11" xml:lang="en">Reserve for net revaluation according to the equity method
The reserve for net revaluation according to the equity method comprises net revaluation of investments in subsidiaries and associates relative to the cost.</e:DescriptionOfMethodsOfDividends><e:DescriptionOfMethodsOfRecognitionAndMeasurementBasisOfTaxPayablesAndDeferredTax contextRef="c11" xml:lang="da">Adyn ApS hæfter som administrationsselskab for dattervirksomhedernes selskabsskatter over for skattemyndighederne.
Aktuelle skatteforpligtelser og tilgodehavende aktuel skat indregnes i balancen som beregnet skat af årets skattepligtige indkomst, reguleret for skat af tidligere års skattepligtige indkomster samt for betalte acontoskatter.
Skyldige og tilgodehavende sambeskatningsbidrag indregnes i balancen som 'Tilgodehavende sambeskatningsbidrag' eller 'Skyldige sambeskatningsbidrag'.
Udskudt skat måles efter den balanceorienterede gældsmetode af midlertidige forskelle mellem regnskabsmæssig og skattemæssig værdi af aktiver og forpligtelser opgjort på grundlag af den planlagte anvendelse af aktivet henholdsvis afvikling af forpligtelsen.
Udskudte skatteaktiver, herunder skatteværdien af fremførselsberettiget skattemæssigt underskud, måles til den værdi, hvortil aktivet forventes at kunne realiseres, enten ved udligning i skat af fremtidig indtjening eller ved modregning i udskudte skatteforpligtelser inden for samme juridiske skatteenhed. Eventuelle udskudte nettoskatteaktiver måles til nettorealisationsværdi.</e:DescriptionOfMethodsOfRecognitionAndMeasurementBasisOfTaxPayablesAndDeferredTax><e:DescriptionOfMethodsOfRecognitionAndMeasurementBasisOfTaxPayablesAndDeferredTax contextRef="c11" xml:lang="en">As management company, Adyn ApS is liable for payment of the subsidiaries' corporate income taxes to the tax authorities.
Current tax liabilities and current tax receivables are recognised in the balance sheet as the estimated tax on the taxable income for the year, adjusted for tax on the taxable income for previous years and tax paid on account.
Joint taxation contributions payable and receivable are recognised in the balance sheet as 'Joint taxation contributions receivable' or 'Joint taxation contributions payable'.
Deferred tax is measured according to the liability method in respect of temporary differences between the carrying amount of assets and liabilities and their tax base, calculated on the basis of the planned use of the asset and settlement of the liability, respectively.
Deferred tax assets, including the tax base of tax loss allowed for carry forward are measured at the value to which the asset is expected to be realised, either by elimination in tax on future income or by offsetting against deferred tax liabilities within the same legal tax entity. Any deferred net tax assets are measured at net realisable value.</e:DescriptionOfMethodsOfRecognitionAndMeasurementBasisOfTaxPayablesAndDeferredTax><e:DescriptionOfMethodsOfRecognitionAndMeasurementBasisOfLiabilitiesOtherThanProvisions contextRef="c11" xml:lang="da">Finansielle forpligtelser indregnes ved lånoptagelse til det modtagne provenu efter fradrag af afholdte transaktionsomkostninger. I efterfølgende perioder måles de finansielle forpligtelser til amortiseret kostpris svarende til den kapitaliserede værdi ved anvendelse af den effektive rente, så forskellen mellem provenuet og den nominelle værdi indregnes i resultatopgørelsen over låneperioden.
Prioritetsgæld er således målt til amortiseret kostpris, der for kontantlån svarer til lånets restgæld. For obligationslån svarer amortiseret kostpris til en restgæld beregnet som lånets underliggende kontantværdi på lånoptagelsestidspunktet reguleret med en over afdragstiden foretaget amortisering af lånets kursregulering på optagelsestidspunktet.
Øvrige gældsforpligtelser, som omfatter gæld til leverandører, tilknyttede virksomheder samt anden gæld, måles til amortiseret kostpris, hvilket sædvanligvis svarer til nominel værdi.</e:DescriptionOfMethodsOfRecognitionAndMeasurementBasisOfLiabilitiesOtherThanProvisions><e:DescriptionOfMethodsOfRecognitionAndMeasurementBasisOfLiabilitiesOtherThanProvisions contextRef="c11" xml:lang="en">Financial liabilities are recognised on the raising of the loan at the proceeds received net of transaction costs incurred. On subsequent recognition, the financial liabilities are measured at amortised cost, corresponding to the capitalised value, using the effective interest method. Accordingly, the difference between the proceeds and the nominal value is recognised in the income statement over the term of the loan.
Mortgage debt is thus measured at amortised cost, which for cash loans corresponds to the outstanding debt. For bond loans, amortised cost corresponds to an outstanding debt calculated as the underlying cash value of the loan at the time of borrowing, adjusted by amortisation of the value adjustment of the loan at the time of borrowing.
Other liabilities, which include trade receivables, payables to group entities and other payables, are measured at amortised cost, which is usually equivalent to nominal value.</e:DescriptionOfMethodsOfRecognitionAndMeasurementBasisOfLiabilitiesOtherThanProvisions><e:DescriptionOfMethodsOfRecognitionAndMeasurementBasisOfDeferredIncomeLiabilities contextRef="c11" xml:lang="da">Periodeafgrænsningsposter omfatter modtagne betalinger vedrørende indtægter i de efterfølgende år.</e:DescriptionOfMethodsOfRecognitionAndMeasurementBasisOfDeferredIncomeLiabilities><e:DescriptionOfMethodsOfRecognitionAndMeasurementBasisOfDeferredIncomeLiabilities contextRef="c11" xml:lang="en">Deferred income comprises payments received concerning income in subsequent reporting years.</e:DescriptionOfMethodsOfRecognitionAndMeasurementBasisOfDeferredIncomeLiabilities><e:DescriptionMethodsOfRecognitionAndMeasurementBasisForCashFlowsStatement contextRef="c11" xml:lang="da">Pengestrømsopgørelsen viser koncernens pengestrømme fordelt på drifts-, investerings- og finansieringsaktivitet for året, årets forskydning i likvider og koncernens likvider ved årets begyndelse og slutning.
Likviditetsvirkningen af køb og salg af virksomheder vises separat under pengestrømme fra investeringsaktivitet. I pengestrømsopgørelsen indregnes pengestrømme vedrørende købte virksomheder fra anskaffelsestidspunktet, og pengestrømme vedrørende solgte virksomheder indregnes frem til salgstidspunktet.
Pengestrøm fra driftsaktivitet
Pengestrømme fra driftsaktivitet opgøres som koncernens andel af resultatet reguleret for ikke-kontante driftsposter, ændring i driftskapital og betalt selskabsskat.
Pengestrøm fra investeringsaktivitet
Pengestrømme fra investeringsaktivitet omfatter betaling i forbindelse med køb og salg af virksomheder og aktiviteter samt køb og salg af immaterielle, materielle og finansielle anlægsaktiver.
Pengestrøm fra finansieringsaktivitet
Pengestrømme fra finansieringsaktivitet omfatter ændringer i størrelse eller sammensætning af koncernens aktiekapital og omkostninger forbundet hermed samt optagelse af lån, afdrag på rentebærende gæld og betaling af udbytte til selskabsdeltagere.
Likvider
Likvider omfatter likvide beholdninger og kortfristede værdipapirer med en løbetid under 3 måneder, og som uden hindring kan omsættes til likvide beholdninger, og hvorpå der kun er ubetydelige risici for værdiændringer.</e:DescriptionMethodsOfRecognitionAndMeasurementBasisForCashFlowsStatement><e:DescriptionMethodsOfRecognitionAndMeasurementBasisForCashFlowsStatement contextRef="c11" xml:lang="en">The cash flow statement shows the group's cash flows for the year, broken down under cash flows from operating, investing and financing activities, the year's changes in cash and cash equivalents and the  group's cash and cash equivalents at the beginning and at the end of the year.
The cash flow effect of additions and disposals of entities is shown separately under cash flows from investing activities. The cash flow statement includes cash flows from acquired entities from the time of acquisition, and cash flows from sold entities are included until the date of sale.
Cash flows from operating activities
Cash flows from operating activities are stated as the profit or loss for the year, adjusted for non-cash operating items, changes in working capital and paid income taxes.
Cash flows from investing activities
Cash flows from investing activities comprise payments related to the acquisition and sale of entities and activities, intangible assets, property, plant and equipment and investments.
Cash flows from financing activities
Cash flows from financing activities comprise changes in the size or composition of the share capital and related costs, as well as the raising of loans, repayment of interest-bearing debt and payment of dividends to shareholders.
Cash and cash equivalents
Cash and cash equivalents comprise cash and short-term securities whose remaining life is less than three months and which are readily convertible into cash and which are subject only to insignificant risks of changes in value.</e:DescriptionMethodsOfRecognitionAndMeasurementBasisForCashFlowsStatement><h:DescriptionOfKeyFiguresAndFinancialRatios contextRef="c11">Forklaring af nøgletal.
Definitions of financial ratios.
Soliditetsgrad
Egenkapital ultimo x 100Samlede aktiver ultimo
Solvency ratio

Equity at year end x 100Total assets

Forrentning af egenkapital
Ordinært resultat efter skat x 100Gennemsnitlig egenkapital
Return on equity

Net profit for the year x 100Average equity
</h:DescriptionOfKeyFiguresAndFinancialRatios><!--Aktuelle periode enkelt selskab--><context id="c11"><entity><identifier scheme="http://www.dcca.dk/cvr">89422728</identifier></entity><period><startDate>2017-01-01</startDate><endDate>2017-12-31</endDate></period></context><!--REVISOR1--><context id="c12"><entity><identifier scheme="http://www.dcca.dk/cvr">89422728</identifier></entity><period><startDate>2017-01-01</startDate><endDate>2017-12-31</endDate></period><scenario><xbrldi:typedMember dimension="d:IdentificationOfAuditorDimension"><d:auditorIdentifier>1</d:auditorIdentifier></xbrldi:typedMember></scenario></context><!--REVISOR2--><context id="c14"><entity><identifier scheme="http://www.dcca.dk/cvr">89422728</identifier></entity><period><startDate>2017-01-01</startDate><endDate>2017-12-31</endDate></period><scenario><xbrldi:typedMember dimension="d:IdentificationOfAuditorDimension"><d:auditorIdentifier>2</d:auditorIdentifier></xbrldi:typedMember></scenario></context><!--HTAL aar2--><context id="c17"><entity><identifier scheme="http://www.dcca.dk/cvr">89422728</identifier></entity><period><startDate>2016-01-01</startDate><endDate>2016-12-31</endDate></period></context><!--HTAL aar3--><context id="c19"><entity><identifier scheme="http://www.dcca.dk/cvr">89422728</identifier></entity><period><startDate>2017-01-01</startDate><endDate>2017-12-31</endDate></period><scenario><xbrldi:explicitMember dimension="d:RetrospectiveInformationDimension">d:TwoYearsAgoMember</xbrldi:explicitMember></scenario></context><!--HTAL ultimo aar3--><context id="c21"><entity><identifier scheme="http://www.dcca.dk/cvr">89422728</identifier></entity><period><instant>2017-12-31</instant></period><scenario><xbrldi:explicitMember dimension="d:RetrospectiveInformationDimension">d:TwoYearsAgoMember</xbrldi:explicitMember></scenario></context><!--HTAL aar4--><context id="c22"><entity><identifier scheme="http://www.dcca.dk/cvr">89422728</identifier></entity><period><startDate>2017-01-01</startDate><endDate>2017-12-31</endDate></period><scenario><xbrldi:explicitMember dimension="d:RetrospectiveInformationDimension">d:ThreeYearsAgoMember</xbrldi:explicitMember></scenario></context><!--HTAL ultimo aar4--><context id="c24"><entity><identifier scheme="http://www.dcca.dk/cvr">89422728</identifier></entity><period><instant>2017-12-31</instant></period><scenario><xbrldi:explicitMember dimension="d:RetrospectiveInformationDimension">d:ThreeYearsAgoMember</xbrldi:explicitMember></scenario></context><!--HTAL aar5--><context id="c25"><entity><identifier scheme="http://www.dcca.dk/cvr">89422728</identifier></entity><period><startDate>2017-01-01</startDate><endDate>2017-12-31</endDate></period><scenario><xbrldi:explicitMember dimension="d:RetrospectiveInformationDimension">d:FourYearsAgoMember</xbrldi:explicitMember></scenario></context><!--HTAL ultimo aar5--><context id="c27"><entity><identifier scheme="http://www.dcca.dk/cvr">89422728</identifier></entity><period><instant>2017-12-31</instant></period><scenario><xbrldi:explicitMember dimension="d:RetrospectiveInformationDimension">d:FourYearsAgoMember</xbrldi:explicitMember></scenario></context><!--Overfoert resultat aktuel i aaret--><context id="c72"><entity><identifier scheme="http://www.dcca.dk/cvr">89422728</identifier></entity><period><startDate>2017-01-01</startDate><endDate>2017-12-31</endDate></period><scenario><xbrldi:explicitMember dimension="e:ResultDistributionDimension">e:RetainedEarningsMember</xbrldi:explicitMember></scenario></context><!--Overfoert resultat forrige i aaret--><context id="c73"><entity><identifier scheme="http://www.dcca.dk/cvr">89422728</identifier></entity><period><startDate>2016-01-01</startDate><endDate>2016-12-31</endDate></period><scenario><xbrldi:explicitMember dimension="e:ResultDistributionDimension">e:RetainedEarningsMember</xbrldi:explicitMember></scenario></context><!--Slutdato forrige periode enkelt selskab--><context id="c74"><entity><identifier scheme="http://www.dcca.dk/cvr">89422728</identifier></entity><period><instant>2016-12-31</instant></period></context><!--Slutdato aktuelle periode enkelt selskab--><context id="c75"><entity><identifier scheme="http://www.dcca.dk/cvr">89422728</identifier></entity><period><instant>2017-12-31</instant></period></context><!--Kapitalandel associerede aktuel primo--><context id="c82"><entity><identifier scheme="http://www.dcca.dk/cvr">89422728</identifier></entity><period><instant>2017-01-01</instant></period><scenario><xbrldi:explicitMember dimension="e:ClassesOfInvestmentsDimension">e:InvestmentsInAssociatesMember</xbrldi:explicitMember></scenario></context><!--Kapitalandel associerede aktuel i aaret--><context id="c83"><entity><identifier scheme="http://www.dcca.dk/cvr">89422728</identifier></entity><period><startDate>2017-01-01</startDate><endDate>2017-12-31</endDate></period><scenario><xbrldi:explicitMember dimension="e:ClassesOfInvestmentsDimension">e:InvestmentsInAssociatesMember</xbrldi:explicitMember></scenario></context><!--Kapitalandel associerede aktuel ultimo--><context id="c84"><entity><identifier scheme="http://www.dcca.dk/cvr">89422728</identifier></entity><period><instant>2017-12-31</instant></period><scenario><xbrldi:explicitMember dimension="e:ClassesOfInvestmentsDimension">e:InvestmentsInAssociatesMember</xbrldi:explicitMember></scenario></context><!--Kapitalandel associerede forrige primo--><context id="c85"><entity><identifier scheme="http://www.dcca.dk/cvr">89422728</identifier></entity><period><instant>2016-01-01</instant></period><scenario><xbrldi:explicitMember dimension="e:ClassesOfInvestmentsDimension">e:InvestmentsInAssociatesMember</xbrldi:explicitMember></scenario></context><!--Kapitalandel associerede forrige i aaret--><context id="c86"><entity><identifier scheme="http://www.dcca.dk/cvr">89422728</identifier></entity><period><startDate>2016-01-01</startDate><endDate>2016-12-31</endDate></period><scenario><xbrldi:explicitMember dimension="e:ClassesOfInvestmentsDimension">e:InvestmentsInAssociatesMember</xbrldi:explicitMember></scenario></context><!--Kapitalandel associerede forrige ultimo--><context id="c87"><entity><identifier scheme="http://www.dcca.dk/cvr">89422728</identifier></entity><period><instant>2016-12-31</instant></period><scenario><xbrldi:explicitMember dimension="e:ClassesOfInvestmentsDimension">e:InvestmentsInAssociatesMember</xbrldi:explicitMember></scenario></context><!--CEO1--><context id="c104"><entity><identifier scheme="http://www.dcca.dk/cvr">89422728</identifier></entity><period><startDate>2017-01-01</startDate><endDate>2017-12-31</endDate></period><scenario><xbrldi:typedMember dimension="d:IdentificationOfMemberOfExecutiveBoardDimension"><d:memberOfBoardIdentifier>1</d:memberOfBoardIdentifier></xbrldi:typedMember></scenario></context><!--Virksomhedskapital aktuel primo--><context id="c113"><entity><identifier scheme="http://www.dcca.dk/cvr">89422728</identifier></entity><period><instant>2017-01-01</instant></period><scenario><xbrldi:explicitMember dimension="e:ClassesOfEquityDimension">e:ContributedCapitalMember</xbrldi:explicitMember></scenario></context><!--Virksomhedskapital aktuel i aaret--><context id="c114"><entity><identifier scheme="http://www.dcca.dk/cvr">89422728</identifier></entity><period><startDate>2017-01-01</startDate><endDate>2017-12-31</endDate></period><scenario><xbrldi:explicitMember dimension="e:ClassesOfEquityDimension">e:ContributedCapitalMember</xbrldi:explicitMember></scenario></context><!--Virksomhedskapital aktuel ultimo--><context id="c115"><entity><identifier scheme="http://www.dcca.dk/cvr">89422728</identifier></entity><period><instant>2017-12-31</instant></period><scenario><xbrldi:explicitMember dimension="e:ClassesOfEquityDimension">e:ContributedCapitalMember</xbrldi:explicitMember></scenario></context><!--Overfort res aktuel primo--><context id="c131"><entity><identifier scheme="http://www.dcca.dk/cvr">89422728</identifier></entity><period><instant>2017-01-01</instant></period><scenario><xbrldi:explicitMember dimension="e:ClassesOfEquityDimension">e:RetainedEarningsMember</xbrldi:explicitMember></scenario></context><!--Overfort res aktuel i aaret--><context id="c132"><entity><identifier scheme="http://www.dcca.dk/cvr">89422728</identifier></entity><period><startDate>2017-01-01</startDate><endDate>2017-12-31</endDate></period><scenario><xbrldi:explicitMember dimension="e:ClassesOfEquityDimension">e:RetainedEarningsMember</xbrldi:explicitMember></scenario></context><!--Overfort res aktuel ultimo--><context id="c133"><entity><identifier scheme="http://www.dcca.dk/cvr">89422728</identifier></entity><period><instant>2017-12-31</instant></period><scenario><xbrldi:explicitMember dimension="e:ClassesOfEquityDimension">e:RetainedEarningsMember</xbrldi:explicitMember></scenario></context><!--Grunde og bygninger aktuel primo--><context id="c202"><entity><identifier scheme="http://www.dcca.dk/cvr">89422728</identifier></entity><period><instant>2017-01-01</instant></period><scenario><xbrldi:explicitMember dimension="e:ClassesOfPropertyPlantAndEquipmentDimension">e:LandAndBuildingsMember</xbrldi:explicitMember></scenario></context><!--Grunde og bygninger aktuel i aaret--><context id="c206"><entity><identifier scheme="http://www.dcca.dk/cvr">89422728</identifier></entity><period><startDate>2017-01-01</startDate><endDate>2017-12-31</endDate></period><scenario><xbrldi:explicitMember dimension="e:ClassesOfPropertyPlantAndEquipmentDimension">e:LandAndBuildingsMember</xbrldi:explicitMember></scenario></context><!--Grunde og bygninger aktuel ultimo--><context id="c207"><entity><identifier scheme="http://www.dcca.dk/cvr">89422728</identifier></entity><period><instant>2017-12-31</instant></period><scenario><xbrldi:explicitMember dimension="e:ClassesOfPropertyPlantAndEquipmentDimension">e:LandAndBuildingsMember</xbrldi:explicitMember></scenario></context><!--Andre anlag aktuel primo--><context id="c211"><entity><identifier scheme="http://www.dcca.dk/cvr">89422728</identifier></entity><period><instant>2017-01-01</instant></period><scenario><xbrldi:explicitMember dimension="e:ClassesOfPropertyPlantAndEquipmentDimension">e:FixturesFittingsToolsAndEquipmentMember</xbrldi:explicitMember></scenario></context><!--Andre anlag aktuel i aaret--><context id="c212"><entity><identifier scheme="http://www.dcca.dk/cvr">89422728</identifier></entity><period><startDate>2017-01-01</startDate><endDate>2017-12-31</endDate></period><scenario><xbrldi:explicitMember dimension="e:ClassesOfPropertyPlantAndEquipmentDimension">e:FixturesFittingsToolsAndEquipmentMember</xbrldi:explicitMember></scenario></context><!--Andre anlag aktuel ultimo--><context id="c213"><entity><identifier scheme="http://www.dcca.dk/cvr">89422728</identifier></entity><period><instant>2017-12-31</instant></period><scenario><xbrldi:explicitMember dimension="e:ClassesOfPropertyPlantAndEquipmentDimension">e:FixturesFittingsToolsAndEquipmentMember</xbrldi:explicitMember></scenario></context><!--Aktiespec1--><context id="c226"><entity><identifier scheme="http://www.dcca.dk/cvr">89422728</identifier></entity><period><instant>2017-12-31</instant></period><scenario><xbrldi:typedMember dimension="e:IdentificationOfClassOfSharesDimension"><e:classOfSharesIdentifier>1</e:classOfSharesIdentifier></xbrldi:typedMember></scenario></context><!--Aktiespec2--><context id="c227"><entity><identifier scheme="http://www.dcca.dk/cvr">89422728</identifier></entity><period><instant>2017-12-31</instant></period><scenario><xbrldi:typedMember dimension="e:IdentificationOfClassOfSharesDimension"><e:classOfSharesIdentifier>2</e:classOfSharesIdentifier></xbrldi:typedMember></scenario></context><!--Gald realkredit aktuel ultimo--><context id="c234"><entity><identifier scheme="http://www.dcca.dk/cvr">89422728</identifier></entity><period><instant>2017-12-31</instant></period><scenario><xbrldi:explicitMember dimension="e:ClassesOfLongTermLiabilitiesDimension">e:LongtermMortgageLoansMember</xbrldi:explicitMember></scenario></context><!--Gald realkredit aktuel primo--><context id="c236"><entity><identifier scheme="http://www.dcca.dk/cvr">89422728</identifier></entity><period><instant>2017-01-01</instant></period><scenario><xbrldi:explicitMember dimension="e:ClassesOfLongTermLiabilitiesDimension">e:LongtermMortgageLoansMember</xbrldi:explicitMember></scenario></context><!--Anden gald aktuel ultimo--><context id="c267"><entity><identifier scheme="http://www.dcca.dk/cvr">89422728</identifier></entity><period><instant>2017-12-31</instant></period><scenario><xbrldi:explicitMember dimension="e:ClassesOfLongTermLiabilitiesDimension">e:OtherLongtermPayablesMember</xbrldi:explicitMember></scenario></context><!--Anden gald aktuel primo--><context id="c268"><entity><identifier scheme="http://www.dcca.dk/cvr">89422728</identifier></entity><period><instant>2017-01-01</instant></period><scenario><xbrldi:explicitMember dimension="e:ClassesOfLongTermLiabilitiesDimension">e:OtherLongtermPayablesMember</xbrldi:explicitMember></scenario></context><!--Kapital aktuel primo forrige aar--><context id="c277"><entity><identifier scheme="http://www.dcca.dk/cvr">89422728</identifier></entity><period><instant>2017-01-01</instant></period><scenario><xbrldi:explicitMember dimension="d:RetrospectiveInformationDimension">d:PreviousYearMember</xbrldi:explicitMember><xbrldi:explicitMember dimension="e:ClassesOfEquityDimension">e:ContributedCapitalMember</xbrldi:explicitMember></scenario></context><!--Kapital aktuel i aaret forrige aar--><context id="c278"><entity><identifier scheme="http://www.dcca.dk/cvr">89422728</identifier></entity><period><startDate>2017-01-01</startDate><endDate>2017-12-31</endDate></period><scenario><xbrldi:explicitMember dimension="d:RetrospectiveInformationDimension">d:PreviousYearMember</xbrldi:explicitMember><xbrldi:explicitMember dimension="e:ClassesOfEquityDimension">e:ContributedCapitalMember</xbrldi:explicitMember></scenario></context><!--Kapital aktuel ultimo forrige aar--><context id="c279"><entity><identifier scheme="http://www.dcca.dk/cvr">89422728</identifier></entity><period><instant>2017-12-31</instant></period><scenario><xbrldi:explicitMember dimension="d:RetrospectiveInformationDimension">d:PreviousYearMember</xbrldi:explicitMember><xbrldi:explicitMember dimension="e:ClassesOfEquityDimension">e:ContributedCapitalMember</xbrldi:explicitMember></scenario></context><!--Kapital aktuel primo forrige aar 2--><context id="c280"><entity><identifier scheme="http://www.dcca.dk/cvr">89422728</identifier></entity><period><instant>2017-01-01</instant></period><scenario><xbrldi:explicitMember dimension="d:RetrospectiveInformationDimension">d:TwoYearsAgoMember</xbrldi:explicitMember><xbrldi:explicitMember dimension="e:ClassesOfEquityDimension">e:ContributedCapitalMember</xbrldi:explicitMember></scenario></context><!--Kapital aktuel i aaret forrige aar 2--><context id="c281"><entity><identifier scheme="http://www.dcca.dk/cvr">89422728</identifier></entity><period><startDate>2017-01-01</startDate><endDate>2017-12-31</endDate></period><scenario><xbrldi:explicitMember dimension="d:RetrospectiveInformationDimension">d:TwoYearsAgoMember</xbrldi:explicitMember><xbrldi:explicitMember dimension="e:ClassesOfEquityDimension">e:ContributedCapitalMember</xbrldi:explicitMember></scenario></context><!--Kapital aktuel ultimo forrige aar 2--><context id="c282"><entity><identifier scheme="http://www.dcca.dk/cvr">89422728</identifier></entity><period><instant>2017-12-31</instant></period><scenario><xbrldi:explicitMember dimension="d:RetrospectiveInformationDimension">d:TwoYearsAgoMember</xbrldi:explicitMember><xbrldi:explicitMember dimension="e:ClassesOfEquityDimension">e:ContributedCapitalMember</xbrldi:explicitMember></scenario></context><!--Kapital aktuel primo forrige aar 3--><context id="c283"><entity><identifier scheme="http://www.dcca.dk/cvr">89422728</identifier></entity><period><instant>2017-01-01</instant></period><scenario><xbrldi:explicitMember dimension="d:RetrospectiveInformationDimension">d:ThreeYearsAgoMember</xbrldi:explicitMember><xbrldi:explicitMember dimension="e:ClassesOfEquityDimension">e:ContributedCapitalMember</xbrldi:explicitMember></scenario></context><!--Kapital aktuel i aaret forrige aar 3--><context id="c284"><entity><identifier scheme="http://www.dcca.dk/cvr">89422728</identifier></entity><period><startDate>2017-01-01</startDate><endDate>2017-12-31</endDate></period><scenario><xbrldi:explicitMember dimension="d:RetrospectiveInformationDimension">d:ThreeYearsAgoMember</xbrldi:explicitMember><xbrldi:explicitMember dimension="e:ClassesOfEquityDimension">e:ContributedCapitalMember</xbrldi:explicitMember></scenario></context><!--Kapital aktuel ultimo forrige aar 3--><context id="c285"><entity><identifier scheme="http://www.dcca.dk/cvr">89422728</identifier></entity><period><instant>2017-12-31</instant></period><scenario><xbrldi:explicitMember dimension="d:RetrospectiveInformationDimension">d:ThreeYearsAgoMember</xbrldi:explicitMember><xbrldi:explicitMember dimension="e:ClassesOfEquityDimension">e:ContributedCapitalMember</xbrldi:explicitMember></scenario></context><!--Kapital aktuel primo forrige aar 4--><context id="c286"><entity><identifier scheme="http://www.dcca.dk/cvr">89422728</identifier></entity><period><instant>2017-01-01</instant></period><scenario><xbrldi:explicitMember dimension="d:RetrospectiveInformationDimension">d:FourYearsAgoMember</xbrldi:explicitMember><xbrldi:explicitMember dimension="e:ClassesOfEquityDimension">e:ContributedCapitalMember</xbrldi:explicitMember></scenario></context><!--Kapital aktuel i aaret forrige aar 4--><context id="c287"><entity><identifier scheme="http://www.dcca.dk/cvr">89422728</identifier></entity><period><startDate>2017-01-01</startDate><endDate>2017-12-31</endDate></period><scenario><xbrldi:explicitMember dimension="d:RetrospectiveInformationDimension">d:FourYearsAgoMember</xbrldi:explicitMember><xbrldi:explicitMember dimension="e:ClassesOfEquityDimension">e:ContributedCapitalMember</xbrldi:explicitMember></scenario></context><!--Kapital aktuel ultimo forrige aar 4--><context id="c288"><entity><identifier scheme="http://www.dcca.dk/cvr">89422728</identifier></entity><period><instant>2017-12-31</instant></period><scenario><xbrldi:explicitMember dimension="d:RetrospectiveInformationDimension">d:FourYearsAgoMember</xbrldi:explicitMember><xbrldi:explicitMember dimension="e:ClassesOfEquityDimension">e:ContributedCapitalMember</xbrldi:explicitMember></scenario></context><!--Startdato aktuelle periode enkelt selskab--><context id="c289"><entity><identifier scheme="http://www.dcca.dk/cvr">89422728</identifier></entity><period><instant>2017-01-01</instant></period></context><!--Startdato forrige periode enkelt selskab--><context id="c290"><entity><identifier scheme="http://www.dcca.dk/cvr">89422728</identifier></entity><period><instant>2016-01-01</instant></period></context><!--Tilgodehavender associerede aktuel primo--><context id="c357"><entity><identifier scheme="http://www.dcca.dk/cvr">89422728</identifier></entity><period><instant>2017-01-01</instant></period><scenario><xbrldi:explicitMember dimension="e:ClassesOfInvestmentsDimension">e:ReceivablesFromAssociatesMember</xbrldi:explicitMember></scenario></context><!--Tilgodehavender associerede aktuel i aaret--><context id="c358"><entity><identifier scheme="http://www.dcca.dk/cvr">89422728</identifier></entity><period><startDate>2017-01-01</startDate><endDate>2017-12-31</endDate></period><scenario><xbrldi:explicitMember dimension="e:ClassesOfInvestmentsDimension">e:ReceivablesFromAssociatesMember</xbrldi:explicitMember></scenario></context><!--Tilgodehavender associerede aktuel ultimo--><context id="c359"><entity><identifier scheme="http://www.dcca.dk/cvr">89422728</identifier></entity><period><instant>2017-12-31</instant></period><scenario><xbrldi:explicitMember dimension="e:ClassesOfInvestmentsDimension">e:ReceivablesFromAssociatesMember</xbrldi:explicitMember></scenario></context><!--Andre vardipapirer og kapitalandele aktuel primo--><context id="c360"><entity><identifier scheme="http://www.dcca.dk/cvr">89422728</identifier></entity><period><instant>2017-01-01</instant></period><scenario><xbrldi:explicitMember dimension="e:ClassesOfInvestmentsDimension">e:OtherInvestmentsMember</xbrldi:explicitMember></scenario></context><!--Andre vardipapirer og kapitalandele aktuel i aaret--><context id="c361"><entity><identifier scheme="http://www.dcca.dk/cvr">89422728</identifier></entity><period><startDate>2017-01-01</startDate><endDate>2017-12-31</endDate></period><scenario><xbrldi:explicitMember dimension="e:ClassesOfInvestmentsDimension">e:OtherInvestmentsMember</xbrldi:explicitMember></scenario></context><!--Andre vardipapirer og kapitalandele aktuel ultimo--><context id="c362"><entity><identifier scheme="http://www.dcca.dk/cvr">89422728</identifier></entity><period><instant>2017-12-31</instant></period><scenario><xbrldi:explicitMember dimension="e:ClassesOfInvestmentsDimension">e:OtherInvestmentsMember</xbrldi:explicitMember></scenario></context><!--Investeringsejendomme aktuel primo--><context id="c369"><entity><identifier scheme="http://www.dcca.dk/cvr">89422728</identifier></entity><period><instant>2017-01-01</instant></period><scenario><xbrldi:explicitMember dimension="e:ClassesOfPropertyPlantAndEquipmentDimension">e:InvestmentPropertyMember</xbrldi:explicitMember></scenario></context><!--Investeringsejendomme aktuel i aaret--><context id="c370"><entity><identifier scheme="http://www.dcca.dk/cvr">89422728</identifier></entity><period><startDate>2017-01-01</startDate><endDate>2017-12-31</endDate></period><scenario><xbrldi:explicitMember dimension="e:ClassesOfPropertyPlantAndEquipmentDimension">e:InvestmentPropertyMember</xbrldi:explicitMember></scenario></context><!--Investeringsejendomme aktuel ultimo--><context id="c371"><entity><identifier scheme="http://www.dcca.dk/cvr">89422728</identifier></entity><period><instant>2017-12-31</instant></period><scenario><xbrldi:explicitMember dimension="e:ClassesOfPropertyPlantAndEquipmentDimension">e:InvestmentPropertyMember</xbrldi:explicitMember></scenario></context><!--Udskudt skat Mat aktuel ultimo--><context id="c425"><entity><identifier scheme="http://www.dcca.dk/cvr">89422728</identifier></entity><period><instant>2017-12-31</instant></period><scenario><xbrldi:explicitMember dimension="e:DeferredTaxItemsDimension">e:PropertyPlantAndEquipmentMember</xbrldi:explicitMember></scenario></context><!--Udskudt skat Mat forrige ultimo--><context id="c426"><entity><identifier scheme="http://www.dcca.dk/cvr">89422728</identifier></entity><period><instant>2016-12-31</instant></period><scenario><xbrldi:explicitMember dimension="e:DeferredTaxItemsDimension">e:PropertyPlantAndEquipmentMember</xbrldi:explicitMember></scenario></context><!--Udskudt skat Fin aktuel ultimo--><context id="c427"><entity><identifier scheme="http://www.dcca.dk/cvr">89422728</identifier></entity><period><instant>2017-12-31</instant></period><scenario><xbrldi:explicitMember dimension="e:DeferredTaxItemsDimension">e:LongtermInvestmentsAndReceivablesMember</xbrldi:explicitMember></scenario></context><!--Udskudt skat Fin forrige ultimo--><context id="c428"><entity><identifier scheme="http://www.dcca.dk/cvr">89422728</identifier></entity><period><instant>2016-12-31</instant></period><scenario><xbrldi:explicitMember dimension="e:DeferredTaxItemsDimension">e:LongtermInvestmentsAndReceivablesMember</xbrldi:explicitMember></scenario></context><!--Udskudt skat tilgodeh aktuel ultimo--><context id="c431"><entity><identifier scheme="http://www.dcca.dk/cvr">89422728</identifier></entity><period><instant>2017-12-31</instant></period><scenario><xbrldi:explicitMember dimension="e:DeferredTaxItemsDimension">e:ReceivablesMember</xbrldi:explicitMember></scenario></context><!--Udskudt skat tilgodeh forrige ultimo--><context id="c432"><entity><identifier scheme="http://www.dcca.dk/cvr">89422728</identifier></entity><period><instant>2016-12-31</instant></period><scenario><xbrldi:explicitMember dimension="e:DeferredTaxItemsDimension">e:ReceivablesMember</xbrldi:explicitMember></scenario></context><!--Datterselskab1--><context id="c456"><entity><identifier scheme="http://www.dcca.dk/cvr">89422728</identifier></entity><period><startDate>2017-01-01</startDate><endDate>2017-12-31</endDate></period><scenario><xbrldi:explicitMember dimension="e:TypeOfRelatedEntityDimension">e:SubsidiaryMember</xbrldi:explicitMember><xbrldi:typedMember dimension="e:IdentificationOfRelatedEntityDimension"><e:relatedEntityIdentifier>1</e:relatedEntityIdentifier></xbrldi:typedMember></scenario></context><!--Datterselskab ultimo1--><context id="c457"><entity><identifier scheme="http://www.dcca.dk/cvr">89422728</identifier></entity><period><instant>2017-12-31</instant></period><scenario><xbrldi:explicitMember dimension="e:TypeOfRelatedEntityDimension">e:SubsidiaryMember</xbrldi:explicitMember><xbrldi:typedMember dimension="e:IdentificationOfRelatedEntityDimension"><e:relatedEntityIdentifier>1</e:relatedEntityIdentifier></xbrldi:typedMember></scenario></context><!--Associeret1--><context id="c675"><entity><identifier scheme="http://www.dcca.dk/cvr">89422728</identifier></entity><period><startDate>2017-01-01</startDate><endDate>2017-12-31</endDate></period><scenario><xbrldi:explicitMember dimension="e:TypeOfRelatedEntityDimension">e:AssociateMember</xbrldi:explicitMember><xbrldi:typedMember dimension="e:IdentificationOfRelatedEntityDimension"><e:relatedEntityIdentifier>1</e:relatedEntityIdentifier></xbrldi:typedMember></scenario></context><!--Associeret ultimo1--><context id="c676"><entity><identifier scheme="http://www.dcca.dk/cvr">89422728</identifier></entity><period><instant>2017-12-31</instant></period><scenario><xbrldi:explicitMember dimension="e:TypeOfRelatedEntityDimension">e:AssociateMember</xbrldi:explicitMember><xbrldi:typedMember dimension="e:IdentificationOfRelatedEntityDimension"><e:relatedEntityIdentifier>1</e:relatedEntityIdentifier></xbrldi:typedMember></scenario></context><!--Udskudt skat gald aktuel ultimo--><context id="c714"><entity><identifier scheme="http://www.dcca.dk/cvr">89422728</identifier></entity><period><instant>2017-12-31</instant></period><scenario><xbrldi:explicitMember dimension="e:DeferredTaxItemsDimension">e:LiabilitiesOtherThanProvisionsMember</xbrldi:explicitMember></scenario></context><!--Udskudt skat gald forrige ultimo--><context id="c715"><entity><identifier scheme="http://www.dcca.dk/cvr">89422728</identifier></entity><period><instant>2016-12-31</instant></period><scenario><xbrldi:explicitMember dimension="e:DeferredTaxItemsDimension">e:LiabilitiesOtherThanProvisionsMember</xbrldi:explicitMember></scenario></context><!--Udskudt skat skimidl forskelle aktuel ultimo--><context id="c718"><entity><identifier scheme="http://www.dcca.dk/cvr">89422728</identifier></entity><period><instant>2017-12-31</instant></period><scenario><xbrldi:explicitMember dimension="e:DeferredTaxItemsDimension">e:OtherTaxableTemporaryDifferencesMember</xbrldi:explicitMember></scenario></context><!--Udskudt skat skimidl forskelle forrige ultimo--><context id="c719"><entity><identifier scheme="http://www.dcca.dk/cvr">89422728</identifier></entity><period><instant>2016-12-31</instant></period><scenario><xbrldi:explicitMember dimension="e:DeferredTaxItemsDimension">e:OtherTaxableTemporaryDifferencesMember</xbrldi:explicitMember></scenario></context><!--Datterselskab2--><context id="c737"><entity><identifier scheme="http://www.dcca.dk/cvr">89422728</identifier></entity><period><startDate>2017-01-01</startDate><endDate>2017-12-31</endDate></period><scenario><xbrldi:explicitMember dimension="e:TypeOfRelatedEntityDimension">e:SubsidiaryMember</xbrldi:explicitMember><xbrldi:typedMember dimension="e:IdentificationOfRelatedEntityDimension"><e:relatedEntityIdentifier>2</e:relatedEntityIdentifier></xbrldi:typedMember></scenario></context><!--Datterselskab3--><context id="c738"><entity><identifier scheme="http://www.dcca.dk/cvr">89422728</identifier></entity><period><startDate>2017-01-01</startDate><endDate>2017-12-31</endDate></period><scenario><xbrldi:explicitMember dimension="e:TypeOfRelatedEntityDimension">e:SubsidiaryMember</xbrldi:explicitMember><xbrldi:typedMember dimension="e:IdentificationOfRelatedEntityDimension"><e:relatedEntityIdentifier>3</e:relatedEntityIdentifier></xbrldi:typedMember></scenario></context><!--Datterselskab4--><context id="c739"><entity><identifier scheme="http://www.dcca.dk/cvr">89422728</identifier></entity><period><startDate>2017-01-01</startDate><endDate>2017-12-31</endDate></period><scenario><xbrldi:explicitMember dimension="e:TypeOfRelatedEntityDimension">e:SubsidiaryMember</xbrldi:explicitMember><xbrldi:typedMember dimension="e:IdentificationOfRelatedEntityDimension"><e:relatedEntityIdentifier>4</e:relatedEntityIdentifier></xbrldi:typedMember></scenario></context><!--Datterselskab5--><context id="c740"><entity><identifier scheme="http://www.dcca.dk/cvr">89422728</identifier></entity><period><startDate>2017-01-01</startDate><endDate>2017-12-31</endDate></period><scenario><xbrldi:explicitMember dimension="e:TypeOfRelatedEntityDimension">e:SubsidiaryMember</xbrldi:explicitMember><xbrldi:typedMember dimension="e:IdentificationOfRelatedEntityDimension"><e:relatedEntityIdentifier>5</e:relatedEntityIdentifier></xbrldi:typedMember></scenario></context><!--Datterselskab6--><context id="c741"><entity><identifier scheme="http://www.dcca.dk/cvr">89422728</identifier></entity><period><startDate>2017-01-01</startDate><endDate>2017-12-31</endDate></period><scenario><xbrldi:explicitMember dimension="e:TypeOfRelatedEntityDimension">e:SubsidiaryMember</xbrldi:explicitMember><xbrldi:typedMember dimension="e:IdentificationOfRelatedEntityDimension"><e:relatedEntityIdentifier>6</e:relatedEntityIdentifier></xbrldi:typedMember></scenario></context><!--Datterselskab7--><context id="c742"><entity><identifier scheme="http://www.dcca.dk/cvr">89422728</identifier></entity><period><startDate>2017-01-01</startDate><endDate>2017-12-31</endDate></period><scenario><xbrldi:explicitMember dimension="e:TypeOfRelatedEntityDimension">e:SubsidiaryMember</xbrldi:explicitMember><xbrldi:typedMember dimension="e:IdentificationOfRelatedEntityDimension"><e:relatedEntityIdentifier>7</e:relatedEntityIdentifier></xbrldi:typedMember></scenario></context><!--Datterselskab8--><context id="c743"><entity><identifier scheme="http://www.dcca.dk/cvr">89422728</identifier></entity><period><startDate>2017-01-01</startDate><endDate>2017-12-31</endDate></period><scenario><xbrldi:explicitMember dimension="e:TypeOfRelatedEntityDimension">e:SubsidiaryMember</xbrldi:explicitMember><xbrldi:typedMember dimension="e:IdentificationOfRelatedEntityDimension"><e:relatedEntityIdentifier>8</e:relatedEntityIdentifier></xbrldi:typedMember></scenario></context><!--Datterselskab9--><context id="c744"><entity><identifier scheme="http://www.dcca.dk/cvr">89422728</identifier></entity><period><startDate>2017-01-01</startDate><endDate>2017-12-31</endDate></period><scenario><xbrldi:explicitMember dimension="e:TypeOfRelatedEntityDimension">e:SubsidiaryMember</xbrldi:explicitMember><xbrldi:typedMember dimension="e:IdentificationOfRelatedEntityDimension"><e:relatedEntityIdentifier>9</e:relatedEntityIdentifier></xbrldi:typedMember></scenario></context><!--Datterselskab10--><context id="c745"><entity><identifier scheme="http://www.dcca.dk/cvr">89422728</identifier></entity><period><startDate>2017-01-01</startDate><endDate>2017-12-31</endDate></period><scenario><xbrldi:explicitMember dimension="e:TypeOfRelatedEntityDimension">e:SubsidiaryMember</xbrldi:explicitMember><xbrldi:typedMember dimension="e:IdentificationOfRelatedEntityDimension"><e:relatedEntityIdentifier>10</e:relatedEntityIdentifier></xbrldi:typedMember></scenario></context><!--Datterselskab11--><context id="c746"><entity><identifier scheme="http://www.dcca.dk/cvr">89422728</identifier></entity><period><startDate>2017-01-01</startDate><endDate>2017-12-31</endDate></period><scenario><xbrldi:explicitMember dimension="e:TypeOfRelatedEntityDimension">e:SubsidiaryMember</xbrldi:explicitMember><xbrldi:typedMember dimension="e:IdentificationOfRelatedEntityDimension"><e:relatedEntityIdentifier>11</e:relatedEntityIdentifier></xbrldi:typedMember></scenario></context><!--Datterselskab12--><context id="c747"><entity><identifier scheme="http://www.dcca.dk/cvr">89422728</identifier></entity><period><startDate>2017-01-01</startDate><endDate>2017-12-31</endDate></period><scenario><xbrldi:explicitMember dimension="e:TypeOfRelatedEntityDimension">e:SubsidiaryMember</xbrldi:explicitMember><xbrldi:typedMember dimension="e:IdentificationOfRelatedEntityDimension"><e:relatedEntityIdentifier>12</e:relatedEntityIdentifier></xbrldi:typedMember></scenario></context><!--Datterselskab13--><context id="c748"><entity><identifier scheme="http://www.dcca.dk/cvr">89422728</identifier></entity><period><startDate>2017-01-01</startDate><endDate>2017-12-31</endDate></period><scenario><xbrldi:explicitMember dimension="e:TypeOfRelatedEntityDimension">e:SubsidiaryMember</xbrldi:explicitMember><xbrldi:typedMember dimension="e:IdentificationOfRelatedEntityDimension"><e:relatedEntityIdentifier>13</e:relatedEntityIdentifier></xbrldi:typedMember></scenario></context><!--Datterselskab14--><context id="c749"><entity><identifier scheme="http://www.dcca.dk/cvr">89422728</identifier></entity><period><startDate>2017-01-01</startDate><endDate>2017-12-31</endDate></period><scenario><xbrldi:explicitMember dimension="e:TypeOfRelatedEntityDimension">e:SubsidiaryMember</xbrldi:explicitMember><xbrldi:typedMember dimension="e:IdentificationOfRelatedEntityDimension"><e:relatedEntityIdentifier>14</e:relatedEntityIdentifier></xbrldi:typedMember></scenario></context><!--Datterselskab ultimo2--><context id="c756"><entity><identifier scheme="http://www.dcca.dk/cvr">89422728</identifier></entity><period><instant>2017-12-31</instant></period><scenario><xbrldi:explicitMember dimension="e:TypeOfRelatedEntityDimension">e:SubsidiaryMember</xbrldi:explicitMember><xbrldi:typedMember dimension="e:IdentificationOfRelatedEntityDimension"><e:relatedEntityIdentifier>2</e:relatedEntityIdentifier></xbrldi:typedMember></scenario></context><!--Datterselskab ultimo3--><context id="c757"><entity><identifier scheme="http://www.dcca.dk/cvr">89422728</identifier></entity><period><instant>2017-12-31</instant></period><scenario><xbrldi:explicitMember dimension="e:TypeOfRelatedEntityDimension">e:SubsidiaryMember</xbrldi:explicitMember><xbrldi:typedMember dimension="e:IdentificationOfRelatedEntityDimension"><e:relatedEntityIdentifier>3</e:relatedEntityIdentifier></xbrldi:typedMember></scenario></context><!--Datterselskab ultimo4--><context id="c758"><entity><identifier scheme="http://www.dcca.dk/cvr">89422728</identifier></entity><period><instant>2017-12-31</instant></period><scenario><xbrldi:explicitMember dimension="e:TypeOfRelatedEntityDimension">e:SubsidiaryMember</xbrldi:explicitMember><xbrldi:typedMember dimension="e:IdentificationOfRelatedEntityDimension"><e:relatedEntityIdentifier>4</e:relatedEntityIdentifier></xbrldi:typedMember></scenario></context><!--Datterselskab ultimo5--><context id="c759"><entity><identifier scheme="http://www.dcca.dk/cvr">89422728</identifier></entity><period><instant>2017-12-31</instant></period><scenario><xbrldi:explicitMember dimension="e:TypeOfRelatedEntityDimension">e:SubsidiaryMember</xbrldi:explicitMember><xbrldi:typedMember dimension="e:IdentificationOfRelatedEntityDimension"><e:relatedEntityIdentifier>5</e:relatedEntityIdentifier></xbrldi:typedMember></scenario></context><!--Datterselskab ultimo6--><context id="c760"><entity><identifier scheme="http://www.dcca.dk/cvr">89422728</identifier></entity><period><instant>2017-12-31</instant></period><scenario><xbrldi:explicitMember dimension="e:TypeOfRelatedEntityDimension">e:SubsidiaryMember</xbrldi:explicitMember><xbrldi:typedMember dimension="e:IdentificationOfRelatedEntityDimension"><e:relatedEntityIdentifier>6</e:relatedEntityIdentifier></xbrldi:typedMember></scenario></context><!--Datterselskab ultimo7--><context id="c761"><entity><identifier scheme="http://www.dcca.dk/cvr">89422728</identifier></entity><period><instant>2017-12-31</instant></period><scenario><xbrldi:explicitMember dimension="e:TypeOfRelatedEntityDimension">e:SubsidiaryMember</xbrldi:explicitMember><xbrldi:typedMember dimension="e:IdentificationOfRelatedEntityDimension"><e:relatedEntityIdentifier>7</e:relatedEntityIdentifier></xbrldi:typedMember></scenario></context><!--Datterselskab ultimo8--><context id="c762"><entity><identifier scheme="http://www.dcca.dk/cvr">89422728</identifier></entity><period><instant>2017-12-31</instant></period><scenario><xbrldi:explicitMember dimension="e:TypeOfRelatedEntityDimension">e:SubsidiaryMember</xbrldi:explicitMember><xbrldi:typedMember dimension="e:IdentificationOfRelatedEntityDimension"><e:relatedEntityIdentifier>8</e:relatedEntityIdentifier></xbrldi:typedMember></scenario></context><!--Datterselskab ultimo9--><context id="c763"><entity><identifier scheme="http://www.dcca.dk/cvr">89422728</identifier></entity><period><instant>2017-12-31</instant></period><scenario><xbrldi:explicitMember dimension="e:TypeOfRelatedEntityDimension">e:SubsidiaryMember</xbrldi:explicitMember><xbrldi:typedMember dimension="e:IdentificationOfRelatedEntityDimension"><e:relatedEntityIdentifier>9</e:relatedEntityIdentifier></xbrldi:typedMember></scenario></context><!--Datterselskab ultimo10--><context id="c764"><entity><identifier scheme="http://www.dcca.dk/cvr">89422728</identifier></entity><period><instant>2017-12-31</instant></period><scenario><xbrldi:explicitMember dimension="e:TypeOfRelatedEntityDimension">e:SubsidiaryMember</xbrldi:explicitMember><xbrldi:typedMember dimension="e:IdentificationOfRelatedEntityDimension"><e:relatedEntityIdentifier>10</e:relatedEntityIdentifier></xbrldi:typedMember></scenario></context><!--Datterselskab ultimo11--><context id="c765"><entity><identifier scheme="http://www.dcca.dk/cvr">89422728</identifier></entity><period><instant>2017-12-31</instant></period><scenario><xbrldi:explicitMember dimension="e:TypeOfRelatedEntityDimension">e:SubsidiaryMember</xbrldi:explicitMember><xbrldi:typedMember dimension="e:IdentificationOfRelatedEntityDimension"><e:relatedEntityIdentifier>11</e:relatedEntityIdentifier></xbrldi:typedMember></scenario></context><!--Datterselskab ultimo12--><context id="c766"><entity><identifier scheme="http://www.dcca.dk/cvr">89422728</identifier></entity><period><instant>2017-12-31</instant></period><scenario><xbrldi:explicitMember dimension="e:TypeOfRelatedEntityDimension">e:SubsidiaryMember</xbrldi:explicitMember><xbrldi:typedMember dimension="e:IdentificationOfRelatedEntityDimension"><e:relatedEntityIdentifier>12</e:relatedEntityIdentifier></xbrldi:typedMember></scenario></context><!--Datterselskab ultimo13--><context id="c767"><entity><identifier scheme="http://www.dcca.dk/cvr">89422728</identifier></entity><period><instant>2017-12-31</instant></period><scenario><xbrldi:explicitMember dimension="e:TypeOfRelatedEntityDimension">e:SubsidiaryMember</xbrldi:explicitMember><xbrldi:typedMember dimension="e:IdentificationOfRelatedEntityDimension"><e:relatedEntityIdentifier>13</e:relatedEntityIdentifier></xbrldi:typedMember></scenario></context><!--Datterselskab ultimo14--><context id="c768"><entity><identifier scheme="http://www.dcca.dk/cvr">89422728</identifier></entity><period><instant>2017-12-31</instant></period><scenario><xbrldi:explicitMember dimension="e:TypeOfRelatedEntityDimension">e:SubsidiaryMember</xbrldi:explicitMember><xbrldi:typedMember dimension="e:IdentificationOfRelatedEntityDimension"><e:relatedEntityIdentifier>14</e:relatedEntityIdentifier></xbrldi:typedMember></scenario></context><!--Virksomhedskapital forrige EKprimo--><context id="c1284"><entity><identifier scheme="http://www.dcca.dk/cvr">89422728</identifier></entity><period><instant>2016-01-01</instant></period><scenario><xbrldi:explicitMember dimension="e:ClassesOfEquityDimension">e:ContributedCapitalMember</xbrldi:explicitMember></scenario></context><!--Virksomhedskapital forrige EKi aaret--><context id="c1285"><entity><identifier scheme="http://www.dcca.dk/cvr">89422728</identifier></entity><period><startDate>2016-01-01</startDate><endDate>2016-12-31</endDate></period><scenario><xbrldi:explicitMember dimension="e:ClassesOfEquityDimension">e:ContributedCapitalMember</xbrldi:explicitMember></scenario></context><!--Virksomhedskapital forrige EKultimo--><context id="c1286"><entity><identifier scheme="http://www.dcca.dk/cvr">89422728</identifier></entity><period><instant>2016-12-31</instant></period><scenario><xbrldi:explicitMember dimension="e:ClassesOfEquityDimension">e:ContributedCapitalMember</xbrldi:explicitMember></scenario></context><!--Overfort res forrige EKprimo--><context id="c1304"><entity><identifier scheme="http://www.dcca.dk/cvr">89422728</identifier></entity><period><instant>2016-01-01</instant></period><scenario><xbrldi:explicitMember dimension="e:ClassesOfEquityDimension">e:RetainedEarningsMember</xbrldi:explicitMember></scenario></context><!--Overfort res forrige EKi aaret--><context id="c1305"><entity><identifier scheme="http://www.dcca.dk/cvr">89422728</identifier></entity><period><startDate>2016-01-01</startDate><endDate>2016-12-31</endDate></period><scenario><xbrldi:explicitMember dimension="e:ClassesOfEquityDimension">e:RetainedEarningsMember</xbrldi:explicitMember></scenario></context><!--Overfort res forrige EKultimo--><context id="c1306"><entity><identifier scheme="http://www.dcca.dk/cvr">89422728</identifier></entity><period><instant>2016-12-31</instant></period><scenario><xbrldi:explicitMember dimension="e:ClassesOfEquityDimension">e:RetainedEarningsMember</xbrldi:explicitMember></scenario></context><!--Grunde og bygninger Leaset ud aktuel ultimo--><context id="c1348"><entity><identifier scheme="http://www.dcca.dk/cvr">89422728</identifier></entity><period><instant>2017-12-31</instant></period><scenario><xbrldi:explicitMember dimension="e:ClassesOfPropertyPlantAndEquipmentDimension">e:LandAndBuildingsMember</xbrldi:explicitMember><xbrldi:explicitMember dimension="e:ClassesOfLeasingDimension">e:AssetsLeasedOutMember</xbrldi:explicitMember></scenario></context><!--Andre anlag Leaset ud aktuel ultimo--><context id="c1351"><entity><identifier scheme="http://www.dcca.dk/cvr">89422728</identifier></entity><period><instant>2017-12-31</instant></period><scenario><xbrldi:explicitMember dimension="e:ClassesOfPropertyPlantAndEquipmentDimension">e:FixturesFittingsToolsAndEquipmentMember</xbrldi:explicitMember><xbrldi:explicitMember dimension="e:ClassesOfLeasingDimension">e:AssetsLeasedOutMember</xbrldi:explicitMember></scenario></context><!--Associeret2--><context id="c1548"><entity><identifier scheme="http://www.dcca.dk/cvr">89422728</identifier></entity><period><startDate>2017-01-01</startDate><endDate>2017-12-31</endDate></period><scenario><xbrldi:explicitMember dimension="e:TypeOfRelatedEntityDimension">e:AssociateMember</xbrldi:explicitMember><xbrldi:typedMember dimension="e:IdentificationOfRelatedEntityDimension"><e:relatedEntityIdentifier>2</e:relatedEntityIdentifier></xbrldi:typedMember></scenario></context><!--Associeret3--><context id="c1549"><entity><identifier scheme="http://www.dcca.dk/cvr">89422728</identifier></entity><period><startDate>2017-01-01</startDate><endDate>2017-12-31</endDate></period><scenario><xbrldi:explicitMember dimension="e:TypeOfRelatedEntityDimension">e:AssociateMember</xbrldi:explicitMember><xbrldi:typedMember dimension="e:IdentificationOfRelatedEntityDimension"><e:relatedEntityIdentifier>3</e:relatedEntityIdentifier></xbrldi:typedMember></scenario></context><!--Associeret4--><context id="c1550"><entity><identifier scheme="http://www.dcca.dk/cvr">89422728</identifier></entity><period><startDate>2017-01-01</startDate><endDate>2017-12-31</endDate></period><scenario><xbrldi:explicitMember dimension="e:TypeOfRelatedEntityDimension">e:AssociateMember</xbrldi:explicitMember><xbrldi:typedMember dimension="e:IdentificationOfRelatedEntityDimension"><e:relatedEntityIdentifier>4</e:relatedEntityIdentifier></xbrldi:typedMember></scenario></context><!--Associeret5--><context id="c1551"><entity><identifier scheme="http://www.dcca.dk/cvr">89422728</identifier></entity><period><startDate>2017-01-01</startDate><endDate>2017-12-31</endDate></period><scenario><xbrldi:explicitMember dimension="e:TypeOfRelatedEntityDimension">e:AssociateMember</xbrldi:explicitMember><xbrldi:typedMember dimension="e:IdentificationOfRelatedEntityDimension"><e:relatedEntityIdentifier>5</e:relatedEntityIdentifier></xbrldi:typedMember></scenario></context><!--Associeret6--><context id="c1552"><entity><identifier scheme="http://www.dcca.dk/cvr">89422728</identifier></entity><period><startDate>2017-01-01</startDate><endDate>2017-12-31</endDate></period><scenario><xbrldi:explicitMember dimension="e:TypeOfRelatedEntityDimension">e:AssociateMember</xbrldi:explicitMember><xbrldi:typedMember dimension="e:IdentificationOfRelatedEntityDimension"><e:relatedEntityIdentifier>6</e:relatedEntityIdentifier></xbrldi:typedMember></scenario></context><!--Associeret7--><context id="c1553"><entity><identifier scheme="http://www.dcca.dk/cvr">89422728</identifier></entity><period><startDate>2017-01-01</startDate><endDate>2017-12-31</endDate></period><scenario><xbrldi:explicitMember dimension="e:TypeOfRelatedEntityDimension">e:AssociateMember</xbrldi:explicitMember><xbrldi:typedMember dimension="e:IdentificationOfRelatedEntityDimension"><e:relatedEntityIdentifier>7</e:relatedEntityIdentifier></xbrldi:typedMember></scenario></context><!--Associeret8--><context id="c1554"><entity><identifier scheme="http://www.dcca.dk/cvr">89422728</identifier></entity><period><startDate>2017-01-01</startDate><endDate>2017-12-31</endDate></period><scenario><xbrldi:explicitMember dimension="e:TypeOfRelatedEntityDimension">e:AssociateMember</xbrldi:explicitMember><xbrldi:typedMember dimension="e:IdentificationOfRelatedEntityDimension"><e:relatedEntityIdentifier>8</e:relatedEntityIdentifier></xbrldi:typedMember></scenario></context><!--Associeret9--><context id="c1555"><entity><identifier scheme="http://www.dcca.dk/cvr">89422728</identifier></entity><period><startDate>2017-01-01</startDate><endDate>2017-12-31</endDate></period><scenario><xbrldi:explicitMember dimension="e:TypeOfRelatedEntityDimension">e:AssociateMember</xbrldi:explicitMember><xbrldi:typedMember dimension="e:IdentificationOfRelatedEntityDimension"><e:relatedEntityIdentifier>9</e:relatedEntityIdentifier></xbrldi:typedMember></scenario></context><!--Associeret10--><context id="c1556"><entity><identifier scheme="http://www.dcca.dk/cvr">89422728</identifier></entity><period><startDate>2017-01-01</startDate><endDate>2017-12-31</endDate></period><scenario><xbrldi:explicitMember dimension="e:TypeOfRelatedEntityDimension">e:AssociateMember</xbrldi:explicitMember><xbrldi:typedMember dimension="e:IdentificationOfRelatedEntityDimension"><e:relatedEntityIdentifier>10</e:relatedEntityIdentifier></xbrldi:typedMember></scenario></context><!--Associeret11--><context id="c1557"><entity><identifier scheme="http://www.dcca.dk/cvr">89422728</identifier></entity><period><startDate>2017-01-01</startDate><endDate>2017-12-31</endDate></period><scenario><xbrldi:explicitMember dimension="e:TypeOfRelatedEntityDimension">e:AssociateMember</xbrldi:explicitMember><xbrldi:typedMember dimension="e:IdentificationOfRelatedEntityDimension"><e:relatedEntityIdentifier>11</e:relatedEntityIdentifier></xbrldi:typedMember></scenario></context><!--Associeret12--><context id="c1558"><entity><identifier scheme="http://www.dcca.dk/cvr">89422728</identifier></entity><period><startDate>2017-01-01</startDate><endDate>2017-12-31</endDate></period><scenario><xbrldi:explicitMember dimension="e:TypeOfRelatedEntityDimension">e:AssociateMember</xbrldi:explicitMember><xbrldi:typedMember dimension="e:IdentificationOfRelatedEntityDimension"><e:relatedEntityIdentifier>12</e:relatedEntityIdentifier></xbrldi:typedMember></scenario></context><!--Associeret13--><context id="c1559"><entity><identifier scheme="http://www.dcca.dk/cvr">89422728</identifier></entity><period><startDate>2017-01-01</startDate><endDate>2017-12-31</endDate></period><scenario><xbrldi:explicitMember dimension="e:TypeOfRelatedEntityDimension">e:AssociateMember</xbrldi:explicitMember><xbrldi:typedMember dimension="e:IdentificationOfRelatedEntityDimension"><e:relatedEntityIdentifier>13</e:relatedEntityIdentifier></xbrldi:typedMember></scenario></context><!--Associeret14--><context id="c1560"><entity><identifier scheme="http://www.dcca.dk/cvr">89422728</identifier></entity><period><startDate>2017-01-01</startDate><endDate>2017-12-31</endDate></period><scenario><xbrldi:explicitMember dimension="e:TypeOfRelatedEntityDimension">e:AssociateMember</xbrldi:explicitMember><xbrldi:typedMember dimension="e:IdentificationOfRelatedEntityDimension"><e:relatedEntityIdentifier>14</e:relatedEntityIdentifier></xbrldi:typedMember></scenario></context><!--Associeret15--><context id="c1561"><entity><identifier scheme="http://www.dcca.dk/cvr">89422728</identifier></entity><period><startDate>2017-01-01</startDate><endDate>2017-12-31</endDate></period><scenario><xbrldi:explicitMember dimension="e:TypeOfRelatedEntityDimension">e:AssociateMember</xbrldi:explicitMember><xbrldi:typedMember dimension="e:IdentificationOfRelatedEntityDimension"><e:relatedEntityIdentifier>15</e:relatedEntityIdentifier></xbrldi:typedMember></scenario></context><!--Associeret16--><context id="c1562"><entity><identifier scheme="http://www.dcca.dk/cvr">89422728</identifier></entity><period><startDate>2017-01-01</startDate><endDate>2017-12-31</endDate></period><scenario><xbrldi:explicitMember dimension="e:TypeOfRelatedEntityDimension">e:AssociateMember</xbrldi:explicitMember><xbrldi:typedMember dimension="e:IdentificationOfRelatedEntityDimension"><e:relatedEntityIdentifier>16</e:relatedEntityIdentifier></xbrldi:typedMember></scenario></context><!--Associeret17--><context id="c1563"><entity><identifier scheme="http://www.dcca.dk/cvr">89422728</identifier></entity><period><startDate>2017-01-01</startDate><endDate>2017-12-31</endDate></period><scenario><xbrldi:explicitMember dimension="e:TypeOfRelatedEntityDimension">e:AssociateMember</xbrldi:explicitMember><xbrldi:typedMember dimension="e:IdentificationOfRelatedEntityDimension"><e:relatedEntityIdentifier>17</e:relatedEntityIdentifier></xbrldi:typedMember></scenario></context><!--Associeret18--><context id="c1564"><entity><identifier scheme="http://www.dcca.dk/cvr">89422728</identifier></entity><period><startDate>2017-01-01</startDate><endDate>2017-12-31</endDate></period><scenario><xbrldi:explicitMember dimension="e:TypeOfRelatedEntityDimension">e:AssociateMember</xbrldi:explicitMember><xbrldi:typedMember dimension="e:IdentificationOfRelatedEntityDimension"><e:relatedEntityIdentifier>18</e:relatedEntityIdentifier></xbrldi:typedMember></scenario></context><!--Associeret ultimo2--><context id="c1567"><entity><identifier scheme="http://www.dcca.dk/cvr">89422728</identifier></entity><period><instant>2017-12-31</instant></period><scenario><xbrldi:explicitMember dimension="e:TypeOfRelatedEntityDimension">e:AssociateMember</xbrldi:explicitMember><xbrldi:typedMember dimension="e:IdentificationOfRelatedEntityDimension"><e:relatedEntityIdentifier>2</e:relatedEntityIdentifier></xbrldi:typedMember></scenario></context><!--Associeret ultimo3--><context id="c1568"><entity><identifier scheme="http://www.dcca.dk/cvr">89422728</identifier></entity><period><instant>2017-12-31</instant></period><scenario><xbrldi:explicitMember dimension="e:TypeOfRelatedEntityDimension">e:AssociateMember</xbrldi:explicitMember><xbrldi:typedMember dimension="e:IdentificationOfRelatedEntityDimension"><e:relatedEntityIdentifier>3</e:relatedEntityIdentifier></xbrldi:typedMember></scenario></context><!--Associeret ultimo4--><context id="c1569"><entity><identifier scheme="http://www.dcca.dk/cvr">89422728</identifier></entity><period><instant>2017-12-31</instant></period><scenario><xbrldi:explicitMember dimension="e:TypeOfRelatedEntityDimension">e:AssociateMember</xbrldi:explicitMember><xbrldi:typedMember dimension="e:IdentificationOfRelatedEntityDimension"><e:relatedEntityIdentifier>4</e:relatedEntityIdentifier></xbrldi:typedMember></scenario></context><!--Associeret ultimo5--><context id="c1570"><entity><identifier scheme="http://www.dcca.dk/cvr">89422728</identifier></entity><period><instant>2017-12-31</instant></period><scenario><xbrldi:explicitMember dimension="e:TypeOfRelatedEntityDimension">e:AssociateMember</xbrldi:explicitMember><xbrldi:typedMember dimension="e:IdentificationOfRelatedEntityDimension"><e:relatedEntityIdentifier>5</e:relatedEntityIdentifier></xbrldi:typedMember></scenario></context><!--Associeret ultimo6--><context id="c1571"><entity><identifier scheme="http://www.dcca.dk/cvr">89422728</identifier></entity><period><instant>2017-12-31</instant></period><scenario><xbrldi:explicitMember dimension="e:TypeOfRelatedEntityDimension">e:AssociateMember</xbrldi:explicitMember><xbrldi:typedMember dimension="e:IdentificationOfRelatedEntityDimension"><e:relatedEntityIdentifier>6</e:relatedEntityIdentifier></xbrldi:typedMember></scenario></context><!--Associeret ultimo7--><context id="c1572"><entity><identifier scheme="http://www.dcca.dk/cvr">89422728</identifier></entity><period><instant>2017-12-31</instant></period><scenario><xbrldi:explicitMember dimension="e:TypeOfRelatedEntityDimension">e:AssociateMember</xbrldi:explicitMember><xbrldi:typedMember dimension="e:IdentificationOfRelatedEntityDimension"><e:relatedEntityIdentifier>7</e:relatedEntityIdentifier></xbrldi:typedMember></scenario></context><!--Associeret ultimo8--><context id="c1573"><entity><identifier scheme="http://www.dcca.dk/cvr">89422728</identifier></entity><period><instant>2017-12-31</instant></period><scenario><xbrldi:explicitMember dimension="e:TypeOfRelatedEntityDimension">e:AssociateMember</xbrldi:explicitMember><xbrldi:typedMember dimension="e:IdentificationOfRelatedEntityDimension"><e:relatedEntityIdentifier>8</e:relatedEntityIdentifier></xbrldi:typedMember></scenario></context><!--Associeret ultimo9--><context id="c1574"><entity><identifier scheme="http://www.dcca.dk/cvr">89422728</identifier></entity><period><instant>2017-12-31</instant></period><scenario><xbrldi:explicitMember dimension="e:TypeOfRelatedEntityDimension">e:AssociateMember</xbrldi:explicitMember><xbrldi:typedMember dimension="e:IdentificationOfRelatedEntityDimension"><e:relatedEntityIdentifier>9</e:relatedEntityIdentifier></xbrldi:typedMember></scenario></context><!--Associeret ultimo10--><context id="c1575"><entity><identifier scheme="http://www.dcca.dk/cvr">89422728</identifier></entity><period><instant>2017-12-31</instant></period><scenario><xbrldi:explicitMember dimension="e:TypeOfRelatedEntityDimension">e:AssociateMember</xbrldi:explicitMember><xbrldi:typedMember dimension="e:IdentificationOfRelatedEntityDimension"><e:relatedEntityIdentifier>10</e:relatedEntityIdentifier></xbrldi:typedMember></scenario></context><!--Associeret ultimo11--><context id="c1576"><entity><identifier scheme="http://www.dcca.dk/cvr">89422728</identifier></entity><period><instant>2017-12-31</instant></period><scenario><xbrldi:explicitMember dimension="e:TypeOfRelatedEntityDimension">e:AssociateMember</xbrldi:explicitMember><xbrldi:typedMember dimension="e:IdentificationOfRelatedEntityDimension"><e:relatedEntityIdentifier>11</e:relatedEntityIdentifier></xbrldi:typedMember></scenario></context><!--Associeret ultimo12--><context id="c1577"><entity><identifier scheme="http://www.dcca.dk/cvr">89422728</identifier></entity><period><instant>2017-12-31</instant></period><scenario><xbrldi:explicitMember dimension="e:TypeOfRelatedEntityDimension">e:AssociateMember</xbrldi:explicitMember><xbrldi:typedMember dimension="e:IdentificationOfRelatedEntityDimension"><e:relatedEntityIdentifier>12</e:relatedEntityIdentifier></xbrldi:typedMember></scenario></context><!--Associeret ultimo13--><context id="c1578"><entity><identifier scheme="http://www.dcca.dk/cvr">89422728</identifier></entity><period><instant>2017-12-31</instant></period><scenario><xbrldi:explicitMember dimension="e:TypeOfRelatedEntityDimension">e:AssociateMember</xbrldi:explicitMember><xbrldi:typedMember dimension="e:IdentificationOfRelatedEntityDimension"><e:relatedEntityIdentifier>13</e:relatedEntityIdentifier></xbrldi:typedMember></scenario></context><!--Associeret ultimo14--><context id="c1579"><entity><identifier scheme="http://www.dcca.dk/cvr">89422728</identifier></entity><period><instant>2017-12-31</instant></period><scenario><xbrldi:explicitMember dimension="e:TypeOfRelatedEntityDimension">e:AssociateMember</xbrldi:explicitMember><xbrldi:typedMember dimension="e:IdentificationOfRelatedEntityDimension"><e:relatedEntityIdentifier>14</e:relatedEntityIdentifier></xbrldi:typedMember></scenario></context><!--Associeret ultimo15--><context id="c1580"><entity><identifier scheme="http://www.dcca.dk/cvr">89422728</identifier></entity><period><instant>2017-12-31</instant></period><scenario><xbrldi:explicitMember dimension="e:TypeOfRelatedEntityDimension">e:AssociateMember</xbrldi:explicitMember><xbrldi:typedMember dimension="e:IdentificationOfRelatedEntityDimension"><e:relatedEntityIdentifier>15</e:relatedEntityIdentifier></xbrldi:typedMember></scenario></context><!--Associeret ultimo16--><context id="c1581"><entity><identifier scheme="http://www.dcca.dk/cvr">89422728</identifier></entity><period><instant>2017-12-31</instant></period><scenario><xbrldi:explicitMember dimension="e:TypeOfRelatedEntityDimension">e:AssociateMember</xbrldi:explicitMember><xbrldi:typedMember dimension="e:IdentificationOfRelatedEntityDimension"><e:relatedEntityIdentifier>16</e:relatedEntityIdentifier></xbrldi:typedMember></scenario></context><!--Associeret ultimo17--><context id="c1582"><entity><identifier scheme="http://www.dcca.dk/cvr">89422728</identifier></entity><period><instant>2017-12-31</instant></period><scenario><xbrldi:explicitMember dimension="e:TypeOfRelatedEntityDimension">e:AssociateMember</xbrldi:explicitMember><xbrldi:typedMember dimension="e:IdentificationOfRelatedEntityDimension"><e:relatedEntityIdentifier>17</e:relatedEntityIdentifier></xbrldi:typedMember></scenario></context><!--Associeret ultimo18--><context id="c1583"><entity><identifier scheme="http://www.dcca.dk/cvr">89422728</identifier></entity><period><instant>2017-12-31</instant></period><scenario><xbrldi:explicitMember dimension="e:TypeOfRelatedEntityDimension">e:AssociateMember</xbrldi:explicitMember><xbrldi:typedMember dimension="e:IdentificationOfRelatedEntityDimension"><e:relatedEntityIdentifier>18</e:relatedEntityIdentifier></xbrldi:typedMember></scenario></context><!--Aktier--><unit id="u1"><measure>xbrli:shares</measure></unit><!--DKK 1000--><unit id="u2"><measure>iso4217:DKK</measure></unit><!--Antal--><unit id="u4"><measure>xbrli:pure</measure></unit></xbrl>